<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>002067</id>
  <cache-id>GCPYXJ</cache-id>
  <type>Multi-cache</type>
  <name>Legends and Swans by Kili or bust, Multi-cache (1/1)</name>
  <size>Small</size>
  <difficulty>1</difficulty>
  <terrain>1</terrain>
  <last-found>2008-11-15</last-found>
  <placed>2005-07-31</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Kili or bust</placedby>
  <found>Geocache Found</found>
  <lat>53.354083</lat>
  <lon>-6.264567</lon>
  <last-logs>FMFFFF</last-logs>
  <owner>Kili or bust</owner>
  <description><p align="center"><a target="_blank" href=
   "http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"><img border="0"
   src=
   "http://img.geocaching.com/cache/2280ab19-c5fc-4d33-8efb-797df9c0ac8c.jpg"
     width="150" height="43" align="middle"></a></p>
<hr size="2">
<center><font color="Green">Visit The Geocaching Ireland discussion
forum <a href="http://www.mccartan.org/forums/" target=
"_blank">HERE</a></font></center>
<hr size="2"></description>
  <long-description>Please be as discreet as posslible when recovering or replacing the
cache as plenty of people frequent this place. The coordinates
above should bring you to The Hugh Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern
Art (details below). It is very close to the centre of the city and
worth a visit for anyone interested in Irish or European 19th and
20th century paintings and sculptures notably a fine collection of
French Impressionists.<br>
The Gardens are just across the road and here you will find a
number of "cross" yellow piggies "wet but shielded" in a celtic
fashion!<br>
1. multiply the total number of piggies found by 12 to give you:
N53 21.???<br>
2. multiply the total number of piggies by 48 and add 2 to give you
W006 15.???<br>
Now you have the coordinates for the cache.<br>
 <br>
 Garden of Remembrance (Dublin)<br>
 <br>
Designed by Dáithí Hanly and dedicated to the memory of all those
who gave their lives in the cause of Irish Freedom. The large
sculpture by Oisín Kelly is based on the theme of the "Children of
Lir". The garden is intended as a place of quiet remembrance and
reflection. <br>
Visitor Information<br>
<br>
 Address and Telephone No:<br>
Location: Parnell Square East, Dublin 1. + 353 1 647 2498 (Head
Office), or + 353 1 874 3074 (Garden).<br>
In the centre of Dublin (at the top of O'Connell Street). <br>
Opening Arrangements: Date Day Time<br>
<br>
 January-February Daily 11:00-16:00<br>
March-April Daily 11:00-19:00<br>
May-September Daily 09:30-20:00<br>
October Daily 11:00-19:00<br>
November-December Daily 11:00-16:00<br>
 Garden open Christmas Day. 11:00-13:00<br>
Opening times are subject to change.<br>
 Average Length of Visit: 1 hour<br>
 Admission Charges: X<br>
<br>
Free of Charge<br>
<br>
<br>
 Hugh Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern Art Charlemont House Parnell
Square North Dublin 1, Ireland<br>
Phone: +353 (0)1 874-1903 Fax: +353 (0)1 872-2182 Email: Email Hugh
Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern Art <br>
Website: http://www.hughlane.ie/ <br>
Location: Map Showing Hugh Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern Art
<br>
Open: Tuesday - Thursday 9.30 - 6.00, Friday & Saturday 9.30 -
5.00, Sunday 11.00 - 5.00, Closed Monday,<br>
<br>
BBR> THE CHILDREN OF LIR: AN IRISH LEGEND <br>
<br>
There was a time in ancient Ireland when the people believed in
magic and in druids and spells. These were the days of the Tuatha
De Danann tribe, the Goddess Danu and of Lir, the lord of the sea.
<br>
<br>
Lir's wife, Eva, had given him four beautiful children. The two
eldest, Fionnuala and Aodh, went swimming in a small lake. But
these were no ordinary swimmers! They possessed gills for breathing
and webbed feet as they were, after all, the offspring of 'the
ruler of the land beneath the waves'. <br>
<br>
They met a messenger who told them that they were wanted by their
father. They went home immediately only to find their father
disturbed.<br>
 <br>
'What is wrong father?' they enquired<br>
'Your mother has given birth to twins....' he replied<br>
'....and has gone off to rest'<br>
'What do you mean father?' they asked<br>
 <br>
Lir explained that this was what humans called 'death' but that
since they were immortal that their mother had gone to recover,
possibly for a thousand years or more. The children were to look
after the new brothers, Fiachra and Conn.<br>
 <br>
The children kissed their mother for the last time and then
left.<br>
 <br>
As the children grew Lir's spirits declined until one day he met
Aiofe, the sister of his wife. Aoife was possessed of magical
powers and soon enough it was known that she and Lir would marry.
The new family thrived under the influence of their new mother but
not for long as guilt and jealousy about the children’s real mother
took its toll on Aoife’s health. She fell into sickness for a year
but recovered only to start to become old before here time. <br>
Aoife was a changed woman now and one day suggested that she and
the children should visit their grandfather. On the journey they
stopped by a lake and she encouraged the children to go for a swim.
The four children played happily in the water, not noticing that
their stepmother was now standing at the waters edge wearing her
fathers magic cloak.<br>
 <br>
'For too long you children have stood between your father and I,
but not for much longer!' she cried <br>
'We cannot be killed by you...' Aodh replied,<br>
'...we are the Children of Lir and if you harm us our ghosts will
haunt you!'<br>
 <br>
'I’m not going to kill you.....' she shouted<br>
'......but I am going to change you!' <br>
<br>
At this she bowed her head and started an incantation. The children
looked at each other in fear as they saw a red and gold circle
envelope them on the water. They saw Aoife open up her cloak from
which the great light of a fireball emerged and hurtled towards
them, burning all in its wake. <br>
<br>
The fireball hit the water and caused masses of steam to rise about
the children and they soon lost all feeling in their legs, arms,
shoulders and head. They soon regained their sight only to see
Aoife laughing at them. Aodh tried to attack her and flailed his
arms about furiously but nothing happened except the splashing of
water. He turned to look at his brothers and sister only to see
that they had all been turned into the most beautiful swans ever
seen. <br>
<br>
Aoife scowled at them again and told them that they were to spend
nine hundred years as swans, three hundred on Lough Derravaragh,
three hundred on the Straits of Moyle and three hundred on the Isle
of Inish Glora. To end the spell they would have to hear the bell
of the new God. <br>
<br>
'I leave you with your voice however, and the most beautiful
singing ever heard' she said. <br>
Lir searched for his children that day, but Aoife told him that
they had been attacked and killed by wild boars. Fionnuala, now in
swan form, approached her father and told him what Aoife had done.
Lir was furious and banished Aoife into exile as an evil demon of
the air.<br>
 <br>
Lir faithfully visited his children and the power of his love
ensured that their time on the lake was one of bliss. He knew
though that the 300 years of the first phase had passed and that
the next phase of the spell was about to begin. The swans left for
the Straits of Moyle, never to see their father again. <br>
<br>
Their time on the Northern Straits of Moyle were not so joyous,
with frequent storms separating them, only for they to join up
again. Another 300 years passed but they had survived together.<br>
 <br>
They departed the cold straits and made their way towards Lough
Derravaragh. They flew over the land, hoping to find their father's
fort, but it was now nothing more than ruins. They wept because
they knew the time of the Tuatha De Danann was gone.<br>
 <br>
They travelled West to the waters of Inish Glora and found refuge
on a small saltwater lake where time passed slowly. One day an old
man named Mochua visited the lake and the children enquired of him
if he was a follower of the new God. The startled man asked if they
were the children of Lir and they told him that they were. <br>
'Are you a holy man?' asked Fiacra.<br>
'I am...' came the reply ' <br>
<br>
The children knew that to break the spell that they would have to
hear the bell of a new God toll in their own land. <br>
<br>
Mochua told them all about his new God and all about Saint Patrick
who had brought his faith to their country. <br>
The children became excited as they knew that this was the new god
their stepmother had told them of. They stayed with Mochua for many
years who gave them sanctuary in a small chapel which he had built.
He intended to make a bell and collected old swords, shields and
other metal to make it. The bell was now completed and was about to
be rung when another disaster occurred.<br>
 <br>
A Warrior dressed in armour entered the chapel. He had come for the
children who were famed for their wonderful singing.<br>
 <br>
'I am Liargren, King of Connaught' he shouted,<br>
'My wife desires those swans and I will have them...<br>
...give them here or I will tear this building down.' <br>
<br>
Fionnuala looked at Mochua and then said that they would agree to
go away with this King. Liargen was amazed to hear her speak but
soon composed himself and ordered his men to take the children
away. They were being loaded onto a carriage when suddenly, the
church bell tolled loudly.<br>
 <br>
Time seemed to stand still, but in another instant a great white
mist had been blown off the nearby lake and enveloped the children
as it had done 900 years before. The mist changed into all of the
colours of the rainbow before a great wind gusted it away.<br>
 The children had at last been transformed back into human form.
<br>
<br>
Liagren fled immediately, never to return. Mochua baptized the
beautiful children who had begun to age rapidly and so it was that
the children of Lir, the last of the Tuatha De Danann died soon
afterwards, their legend to live on forever.<br></long-description>
  <encoded-hints>A bronze vision.</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=83a93e65-538d-4986-83a1-ddb91b251716</url>
  <url-name>Legends and Swans</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-06-17T19:00:00Z : Found it by Crannyn <br />Found on a beautiful sunny afternoon in Dublin. Its great to get a break from the shopping! There were quite a few muggles around but was made easier wIth junior crannyn .OUT- giant paperclip IN- bobbin TFTC</li><li>2010-06-15T19:00:00Z : Owner Maintenance by Kili or bust <br />New container put in place today with new log etc. No tbs though!</li><li>2010-06-03T19:00:00Z : Found it by eve1987 <br />Wonderful location!

TFTC and kind regards from Austrian eve</li><li>2010-06-03T19:00:00Z : Found it by GudrunXY <br />Found with eve1987 on our caching tour through Ireland.
It seemed like the cache had been muggled and then put back half heartedly. The logbook was missing so we put some paper in.
TFTC GudrunXY</li><li>2009-03-06T20:00:00Z : Found it by Mancunian Pyrocacher <br />yes I know I'm a bit late in logging this [:I], but my excuse is that as the UK is a lot busier than Eire cache wise. I've put my Geocaching time in publishing caches rather than log them [:D]

Found with Mongoose, and despite what his log says. It took no persuading to do this one [:D]. Thank you for a superb cache. Really enjoyable and a must do one!

Dave</li><li>2008-11-15T20:00:00Z : Found it by Kersti.com <br />I had a feeling where this one was going to be. Stunning place, well worth a visit. Took a coin, dropped a coin and a pathtag. </li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.354083" lon="-6.264567">
    <time>2005-07-31T07:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GCPYXJ</name>
    <desc>Legends and Swans by Kili or bust, Multi-cache (1/1)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=83a93e65-538d-4986-83a1-ddb91b251716</url>
    <urlname>Legends and Swans</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache Found</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Multi-cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="273037" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Legends and Swans</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Kili or bust</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="281705">Kili or bust</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Multi-cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Small</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>1</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Dublin</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href=
   "http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"&gt;&lt;img border="0"
   src=
   "http://img.geocaching.com/cache/2280ab19-c5fc-4d33-8efb-797df9c0ac8c.jpg"
     width="150" height="43" align="middle"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr size="2"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;font color="Green"&gt;Visit The Geocaching Ireland discussion
forum &lt;a href="http://www.mccartan.org/forums/" target=
"_blank"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;hr size="2"&gt;</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">Please be as discreet as posslible when recovering or replacing the
cache as plenty of people frequent this place. The coordinates
above should bring you to The Hugh Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern
Art (details below). It is very close to the centre of the city and
worth a visit for anyone interested in Irish or European 19th and
20th century paintings and sculptures notably a fine collection of
French Impressionists.&lt;br&gt;
The Gardens are just across the road and here you will find a
number of "cross" yellow piggies "wet but shielded" in a celtic
fashion!&lt;br&gt;
1. multiply the total number of piggies found by 12 to give you:
N53 21.???&lt;br&gt;
2. multiply the total number of piggies by 48 and add 2 to give you
W006 15.???&lt;br&gt;
Now you have the coordinates for the cache.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 Garden of Remembrance (Dublin)&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Designed by Dáithí Hanly and dedicated to the memory of all those
who gave their lives in the cause of Irish Freedom. The large
sculpture by Oisín Kelly is based on the theme of the "Children of
Lir". The garden is intended as a place of quiet remembrance and
reflection. &lt;br&gt;
Visitor Information&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Address and Telephone No:&lt;br&gt;
Location: Parnell Square East, Dublin 1. + 353 1 647 2498 (Head
Office), or + 353 1 874 3074 (Garden).&lt;br&gt;
In the centre of Dublin (at the top of O'Connell Street). &lt;br&gt;
Opening Arrangements: Date Day Time&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 January-February Daily 11:00-16:00&lt;br&gt;
March-April Daily 11:00-19:00&lt;br&gt;
May-September Daily 09:30-20:00&lt;br&gt;
October Daily 11:00-19:00&lt;br&gt;
November-December Daily 11:00-16:00&lt;br&gt;
 Garden open Christmas Day. 11:00-13:00&lt;br&gt;
Opening times are subject to change.&lt;br&gt;
 Average Length of Visit: 1 hour&lt;br&gt;
 Admission Charges: X&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Free of Charge&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Hugh Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern Art Charlemont House Parnell
Square North Dublin 1, Ireland&lt;br&gt;
Phone: +353 (0)1 874-1903 Fax: +353 (0)1 872-2182 Email: Email Hugh
Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern Art &lt;br&gt;
Website: http://www.hughlane.ie/ &lt;br&gt;
Location: Map Showing Hugh Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern Art
&lt;br&gt;
Open: Tuesday - Thursday 9.30 - 6.00, Friday &amp;amp; Saturday 9.30 -
5.00, Sunday 11.00 - 5.00, Closed Monday,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
BBR&amp;gt; THE CHILDREN OF LIR: AN IRISH LEGEND &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
There was a time in ancient Ireland when the people believed in
magic and in druids and spells. These were the days of the Tuatha
De Danann tribe, the Goddess Danu and of Lir, the lord of the sea.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Lir's wife, Eva, had given him four beautiful children. The two
eldest, Fionnuala and Aodh, went swimming in a small lake. But
these were no ordinary swimmers! They possessed gills for breathing
and webbed feet as they were, after all, the offspring of 'the
ruler of the land beneath the waves'. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
They met a messenger who told them that they were wanted by their
father. They went home immediately only to find their father
disturbed.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
'What is wrong father?' they enquired&lt;br&gt;
'Your mother has given birth to twins....' he replied&lt;br&gt;
'....and has gone off to rest'&lt;br&gt;
'What do you mean father?' they asked&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Lir explained that this was what humans called 'death' but that
since they were immortal that their mother had gone to recover,
possibly for a thousand years or more. The children were to look
after the new brothers, Fiachra and Conn.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
The children kissed their mother for the last time and then
left.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
As the children grew Lir's spirits declined until one day he met
Aiofe, the sister of his wife. Aoife was possessed of magical
powers and soon enough it was known that she and Lir would marry.
The new family thrived under the influence of their new mother but
not for long as guilt and jealousy about the children’s real mother
took its toll on Aoife’s health. She fell into sickness for a year
but recovered only to start to become old before here time. &lt;br&gt;
Aoife was a changed woman now and one day suggested that she and
the children should visit their grandfather. On the journey they
stopped by a lake and she encouraged the children to go for a swim.
The four children played happily in the water, not noticing that
their stepmother was now standing at the waters edge wearing her
fathers magic cloak.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
'For too long you children have stood between your father and I,
but not for much longer!' she cried &lt;br&gt;
'We cannot be killed by you...' Aodh replied,&lt;br&gt;
'...we are the Children of Lir and if you harm us our ghosts will
haunt you!'&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
'I’m not going to kill you.....' she shouted&lt;br&gt;
'......but I am going to change you!' &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
At this she bowed her head and started an incantation. The children
looked at each other in fear as they saw a red and gold circle
envelope them on the water. They saw Aoife open up her cloak from
which the great light of a fireball emerged and hurtled towards
them, burning all in its wake. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The fireball hit the water and caused masses of steam to rise about
the children and they soon lost all feeling in their legs, arms,
shoulders and head. They soon regained their sight only to see
Aoife laughing at them. Aodh tried to attack her and flailed his
arms about furiously but nothing happened except the splashing of
water. He turned to look at his brothers and sister only to see
that they had all been turned into the most beautiful swans ever
seen. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Aoife scowled at them again and told them that they were to spend
nine hundred years as swans, three hundred on Lough Derravaragh,
three hundred on the Straits of Moyle and three hundred on the Isle
of Inish Glora. To end the spell they would have to hear the bell
of the new God. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
'I leave you with your voice however, and the most beautiful
singing ever heard' she said. &lt;br&gt;
Lir searched for his children that day, but Aoife told him that
they had been attacked and killed by wild boars. Fionnuala, now in
swan form, approached her father and told him what Aoife had done.
Lir was furious and banished Aoife into exile as an evil demon of
the air.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Lir faithfully visited his children and the power of his love
ensured that their time on the lake was one of bliss. He knew
though that the 300 years of the first phase had passed and that
the next phase of the spell was about to begin. The swans left for
the Straits of Moyle, never to see their father again. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Their time on the Northern Straits of Moyle were not so joyous,
with frequent storms separating them, only for they to join up
again. Another 300 years passed but they had survived together.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
They departed the cold straits and made their way towards Lough
Derravaragh. They flew over the land, hoping to find their father's
fort, but it was now nothing more than ruins. They wept because
they knew the time of the Tuatha De Danann was gone.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
They travelled West to the waters of Inish Glora and found refuge
on a small saltwater lake where time passed slowly. One day an old
man named Mochua visited the lake and the children enquired of him
if he was a follower of the new God. The startled man asked if they
were the children of Lir and they told him that they were. &lt;br&gt;
'Are you a holy man?' asked Fiacra.&lt;br&gt;
'I am...' came the reply ' &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The children knew that to break the spell that they would have to
hear the bell of a new God toll in their own land. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Mochua told them all about his new God and all about Saint Patrick
who had brought his faith to their country. &lt;br&gt;
The children became excited as they knew that this was the new god
their stepmother had told them of. They stayed with Mochua for many
years who gave them sanctuary in a small chapel which he had built.
He intended to make a bell and collected old swords, shields and
other metal to make it. The bell was now completed and was about to
be rung when another disaster occurred.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
A Warrior dressed in armour entered the chapel. He had come for the
children who were famed for their wonderful singing.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
'I am Liargren, King of Connaught' he shouted,&lt;br&gt;
'My wife desires those swans and I will have them...&lt;br&gt;
...give them here or I will tear this building down.' &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Fionnuala looked at Mochua and then said that they would agree to
go away with this King. Liargen was amazed to hear her speak but
soon composed himself and ordered his men to take the children
away. They were being loaded onto a carriage when suddenly, the
church bell tolled loudly.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Time seemed to stand still, but in another instant a great white
mist had been blown off the nearby lake and enveloped the children
as it had done 900 years before. The mist changed into all of the
colours of the rainbow before a great wind gusted it away.&lt;br&gt;
 The children had at last been transformed back into human form.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Liagren fled immediately, never to return. Mochua baptized the
beautiful children who had begun to age rapidly and so it was that
the children of Lir, the last of the Tuatha De Danann died soon
afterwards, their legend to live on forever.&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>A bronze vision.</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="113237295">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-17T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2557004">Crannyn</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found on a beautiful sunny afternoon in Dublin. Its great to get a break from the shopping! There were quite a few muggles around but was made easier wIth junior crannyn .OUT- giant paperclip IN- bobbin TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="113018559">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-15T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Owner Maintenance</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="281705">Kili or bust</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">New container put in place today with new log etc. No tbs though!</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="111884076">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-03T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1617792">eve1987</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Wonderful location!

TFTC and kind regards from Austrian eve</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="111440391">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-03T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2694097">GudrunXY</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found with eve1987 on our caching tour through Ireland.
It seemed like the cache had been muggled and then put back half heartedly. The logbook was missing so we put some paper in.
TFTC GudrunXY</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="112856025">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-03-06T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="77057">Mancunian Pyrocacher</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">yes I know I'm a bit late in logging this [:I], but my excuse is that as the UK is a lot busier than Eire cache wise. I've put my Geocaching time in publishing caches rather than log them [:D]

Found with Mongoose, and despite what his log says. It took no persuading to do this one [:D]. Thank you for a superb cache. Really enjoyable and a must do one!

Dave</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="57215472">
          <groundspeak:date>2008-11-15T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="320206">Kersti.com</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">I had a feeling where this one was going to be. Stunning place, well worth a visit. Took a coin, dropped a coin and a pathtag. </groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs>
        <groundspeak:travelbug id="1404977" ref="TB1YYRR">
          <groundspeak:name>Geocacher's Evolution </groundspeak:name>
        </groundspeak:travelbug>
      </groundspeak:travelbugs>
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
