<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>003000</id>
  <cache-id>GCXTN8</cache-id>
  <type>Traditional Cache</type>
  <name>Old Rathmichael by daraconn, Traditional Cache (2/2)</name>
  <size>Regular</size>
  <difficulty>2</difficulty>
  <terrain>2</terrain>
  <last-found>2009-12-31</last-found>
  <placed>2006-08-19</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>daraconn</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.232783</lat>
  <lon>-6.146383</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFFF</last-logs>
  <owner>daraconn</owner>
  <description><b>Cache Description</b><br>
<br>
The cache is a lock-and-lock lunchbox-style container. The area is
somewhat overgrown and is unfortunately inaccessible by wheelchair.
Because of tree cover the GPS signal quality may be poor in the
immediate vicinity of the cache. <i>You will not need to interfere
with any graves or ancient monuments to find the
cache.</i></description>
  <long-description><b>Access</b><br>
<br>
This cache is not easily accessed by public transport, being
approximately 2.5 km by road from the nearest bus routes (45 or 84
at Shankill church) or 3.5 km from the 44 or 63 at Kilternan.<br>
<br>
To approach the cache, you will need to turn off Rathmichael Road
at N53 14.229 W006 08.882 and head up the laneway.<br>
<br>
When you arrive at the white gates (N53 14.076 W006 08.829), you
may choose to either park your car at this point and continue on
foot, or drive on up. Please take care if your vehicle has low
clearance. Either way, please make sure you do not block access to
either gate and close the gates behind you both entering and
leaving. <br>
<br>
<b>History and notable features</b><br>
<br>
The eastern slopes of Carrickgollogan, tranquil as they may seem
today, were in more warlike times laid waste by many bloody battles
and skirmishes, thanks to their location at the much-contested
boundary between the flat plain of Dublin and the hilly lands to
the south. For three centuries the O’Byrnes and O’Tooles, exiled to
the Wicklow Mountains from their rich lands of Kildare, sustained a
campaign against the Crown forces, the southern outposts of which
were the castles at Bray and Shankill, and later at Old Court and
Shanganagh.<br>
<br>
The area today is rich in the relics of such times in the form of
castles and tower houses, as well as ancient raths and a
partially-built round tower. Other monuments of historical interest
include prehistoric wedge-tombs and early Christian crosses.<br>
<br>
At the cache location, you are standing in the middle of a very
large (100 m diameter) rath (an ancient fortification consisting of
3 concentric encircling earthen banks, surmounted by stone walls
and probably also a palisade of pointed wooden poles).<br>
<br>
Nowadays, however, you may find it hard to make out any trace of
the rath’s boundaries, the outline of which in the furze-covered
mounds will be obvious only to the trained eye (a second rath
further up the hill at N53 13.727 W006 09.144 is far easier to
appreciate). Turner points us to “a small portion of stone wall to
the SW”, while Canon Scott (writing almost 100 years ago) tells us
that “The gateway will be easily recognised, nearly due east of the
church”. (Look for two large stones hidden in the furze just
outside the modern gate of the graveyard).<br>
<br>
This rath was thought by Canon Scott to have been the stronghold of
a certain bishop (and prince) Aengus MacTáil, descendant of King
Aengus of Munster, hence the name of the locality: Ráth MhicTáil
-> Rathmichael. If this is so, the site is very early indeed,
since MacTáil died of plague in 550 AD. By around the 7th century,
possession of this strategic site was transferred to the church,
and a church and monastery were built here. The parish of
Rathmichael became an important independent ecclesiastical centre
and remained so the arrival of the Vikings.<br>
<br>
The nearby harbour of Dalkey became a Danish stronghold at the
start of the ninth century – the plunder of Glendalough occurred in
830. In the intervening time we may suppose that the monastery at
Rathmichael was attacked, its thatched roofs and wattle buildings
burned and its treasures carried off. In response to such attacks,
the monks rebuilt in more durable stone, and began, but never had
the chance to complete, a Round Tower, the stump of which now
stands beside the church.<br>
<br>
When I was growing up in the area, this feature was known as the
“Skull Hole”, because of the human remains that it contained, and
needless to say it exerted a certain morbid fascination on us as
children. Presumably the reason was that gravediggers who came upon
old graves while preparing new ones, were in the habit of tossing
the bones into the tower. It has since been cleared out and so you
need have no worry about what you may step on if you climb down
into it!<br>
<br>
A well-constructed souterrain (underground passage) was also
described “running to the NW”, but has never been explored. The
present ruined church was in use until the middle of the 17th
century, and the chancel arch is said to have collapsed around
1852. The graveyard continued in use until modern times.<br>
<br>
Today the remains consist of the south wall and the gable end, the
pointed window of which points to a Norman (14th century) style of
architecture. Attached to the south wall are mysterious stones,
carved with “cupmarks”, radiating lines and other markings. Despite
these pre-Christian forms of ornament, and the absence of cross
markings or inscriptions, they could be gravestones from the
earliest Christian times, or pre-Christian artefacts re-used as
gravestones.<br>
<br>
<b>References</b><br>
<br>
Much of the historical information in the description was taken
from the following sources:<br>
F.E. Ball; “History of Co. Dublin” (1902), of which the relevant
chapter may be found <a rel="nofollow" href=
"http://www.eiretek.org/chapters/books/ball1-6/Ball3/ball3.6.htm">here</a><br>

 Kathleen Turner; “If You Seek Monuments - a guide to the
antiquities of the Barony of Rathdown” (Rathmichael Historical
Society, 1983)<br>
Canon George Digby Scott; “The Stones of Bray” (Hodges, Figgis,
1913)<br>
<p align="center"><a target="_blank" href=
"http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"><img border="0"
     src="http://img.geocaching.com/cache/2280ab19-c5fc-4d33-8efb-797df9c0ac8c.jpg"
     width="323" height="59" align="middle"></a></p></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>REXTN8 - White Gates (please close them behind you!)<br />N 53° 14.076 W 006° 08.829<br /><br />TRXTN8 - Turn-Off<br />N 53° 14.229 W 006° 08.882<br /><br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:REXTN8|waypoints:cache-id:TRXTN8</links>
  <encoded-hints>Stumped? Yew should look behind Granny.</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=b8c11592-221d-449c-b569-4549c506bdad</url>
  <url-name>Old Rathmichael</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-06-13T19:00:00Z : Found it by EIMHK <br />Found it - never knew about this cemetery even though we had been to Rathmichael lots of times, thanks for taking us here. TFTC</li><li>2010-05-25T19:00:00Z : Found it by Serapis <br />I drove up the lane to the white gates and continued on foot from there. The dogs in the nearby house were going mental, but no people appeared. I found the cache quickly. It was a good thing the weather was dry as walking through the long grass when wet would have soaked me! As I got back in the car a 4 x 4 passed me and continued up the track, wherever he was off to? Thanks for the cache and showing me this interesting place. Serapis.</li><li>2010-05-23T13:57:01Z : Found it by thegoldentickets <br />Beautifully peaceful spot, what a history! Kids loved this one, clue was great. Had lovely picnic by the church.     </li><li>2010-02-22T20:00:00Z : Found it by Jumpin Jiminie <br />Dont think I used the correct route on this one!!! Parked the car in a lane blocked off by a big boulder and continued on foot. Had to cross some very muddy farmland and climb over the wall to get into the cemetery.

Anyway quick find after that and then it was back across the muddy field and back to the car.

TFTC

Jamie</li><li>2009-12-31T20:00:00Z : Found it by roryward <br />Beautiful, although cold, New Years Eve. Brought the whole family and parked on street, not near the white gate. Found the cemetery easily and with help from the hint, found the exact spot. Still had to poke around to find the cache. It is well camouflaged with it's surroundings ;-) Left a Liverpool FC key ring. TFTC
</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.232783" lon="-6.146383">
    <time>2006-08-19T07:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GCXTN8</name>
    <desc>Old Rathmichael by daraconn, Traditional Cache (2/2)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=b8c11592-221d-449c-b569-4549c506bdad</url>
    <urlname>Old Rathmichael</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Traditional Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="447712" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Old Rathmichael</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>daraconn</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="591662">daraconn</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Traditional Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Regular</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>2</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>2</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Dublin</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">&lt;b&gt;Cache Description&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The cache is a lock-and-lock lunchbox-style container. The area is
somewhat overgrown and is unfortunately inaccessible by wheelchair.
Because of tree cover the GPS signal quality may be poor in the
immediate vicinity of the cache. &lt;i&gt;You will not need to interfere
with any graves or ancient monuments to find the
cache.&lt;/i&gt;</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;b&gt;Access&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This cache is not easily accessed by public transport, being
approximately 2.5 km by road from the nearest bus routes (45 or 84
at Shankill church) or 3.5 km from the 44 or 63 at Kilternan.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
To approach the cache, you will need to turn off Rathmichael Road
at N53 14.229 W006 08.882 and head up the laneway.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
When you arrive at the white gates (N53 14.076 W006 08.829), you
may choose to either park your car at this point and continue on
foot, or drive on up. Please take care if your vehicle has low
clearance. Either way, please make sure you do not block access to
either gate and close the gates behind you both entering and
leaving. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;History and notable features&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The eastern slopes of Carrickgollogan, tranquil as they may seem
today, were in more warlike times laid waste by many bloody battles
and skirmishes, thanks to their location at the much-contested
boundary between the flat plain of Dublin and the hilly lands to
the south. For three centuries the O’Byrnes and O’Tooles, exiled to
the Wicklow Mountains from their rich lands of Kildare, sustained a
campaign against the Crown forces, the southern outposts of which
were the castles at Bray and Shankill, and later at Old Court and
Shanganagh.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The area today is rich in the relics of such times in the form of
castles and tower houses, as well as ancient raths and a
partially-built round tower. Other monuments of historical interest
include prehistoric wedge-tombs and early Christian crosses.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
At the cache location, you are standing in the middle of a very
large (100 m diameter) rath (an ancient fortification consisting of
3 concentric encircling earthen banks, surmounted by stone walls
and probably also a palisade of pointed wooden poles).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Nowadays, however, you may find it hard to make out any trace of
the rath’s boundaries, the outline of which in the furze-covered
mounds will be obvious only to the trained eye (a second rath
further up the hill at N53 13.727 W006 09.144 is far easier to
appreciate). Turner points us to “a small portion of stone wall to
the SW”, while Canon Scott (writing almost 100 years ago) tells us
that “The gateway will be easily recognised, nearly due east of the
church”. (Look for two large stones hidden in the furze just
outside the modern gate of the graveyard).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This rath was thought by Canon Scott to have been the stronghold of
a certain bishop (and prince) Aengus MacTáil, descendant of King
Aengus of Munster, hence the name of the locality: Ráth MhicTáil
-&amp;gt; Rathmichael. If this is so, the site is very early indeed,
since MacTáil died of plague in 550 AD. By around the 7th century,
possession of this strategic site was transferred to the church,
and a church and monastery were built here. The parish of
Rathmichael became an important independent ecclesiastical centre
and remained so the arrival of the Vikings.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The nearby harbour of Dalkey became a Danish stronghold at the
start of the ninth century – the plunder of Glendalough occurred in
830. In the intervening time we may suppose that the monastery at
Rathmichael was attacked, its thatched roofs and wattle buildings
burned and its treasures carried off. In response to such attacks,
the monks rebuilt in more durable stone, and began, but never had
the chance to complete, a Round Tower, the stump of which now
stands beside the church.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
When I was growing up in the area, this feature was known as the
“Skull Hole”, because of the human remains that it contained, and
needless to say it exerted a certain morbid fascination on us as
children. Presumably the reason was that gravediggers who came upon
old graves while preparing new ones, were in the habit of tossing
the bones into the tower. It has since been cleared out and so you
need have no worry about what you may step on if you climb down
into it!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A well-constructed souterrain (underground passage) was also
described “running to the NW”, but has never been explored. The
present ruined church was in use until the middle of the 17th
century, and the chancel arch is said to have collapsed around
1852. The graveyard continued in use until modern times.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Today the remains consist of the south wall and the gable end, the
pointed window of which points to a Norman (14th century) style of
architecture. Attached to the south wall are mysterious stones,
carved with “cupmarks”, radiating lines and other markings. Despite
these pre-Christian forms of ornament, and the absence of cross
markings or inscriptions, they could be gravestones from the
earliest Christian times, or pre-Christian artefacts re-used as
gravestones.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Much of the historical information in the description was taken
from the following sources:&lt;br&gt;
F.E. Ball; “History of Co. Dublin” (1902), of which the relevant
chapter may be found &lt;a rel="nofollow" href=
"http://www.eiretek.org/chapters/books/ball1-6/Ball3/ball3.6.htm"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;

 Kathleen Turner; “If You Seek Monuments - a guide to the
antiquities of the Barony of Rathdown” (Rathmichael Historical
Society, 1983)&lt;br&gt;
Canon George Digby Scott; “The Stones of Bray” (Hodges, Figgis,
1913)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href=
"http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"&gt;&lt;img border="0"
     src="http://img.geocaching.com/cache/2280ab19-c5fc-4d33-8efb-797df9c0ac8c.jpg"
     width="323" height="59" align="middle"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;REXTN8 - White Gates (please close them behind you!)&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 14.076 W 006° 08.829&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TRXTN8 - Turn-Off&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 14.229 W 006° 08.882&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>Stumped? Yew should look behind Granny.</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="112677484">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-13T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2557273">EIMHK</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found it - never knew about this cemetery even though we had been to Rathmichael lots of times, thanks for taking us here. TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="110525636">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-25T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1019524">Serapis</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">I drove up the lane to the white gates and continued on foot from there. The dogs in the nearby house were going mental, but no people appeared. I found the cache quickly. It was a good thing the weather was dry as walking through the long grass when wet would have soaked me! As I got back in the car a 4 x 4 passed me and continued up the track, wherever he was off to? Thanks for the cache and showing me this interesting place. Serapis.</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="109632272">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-23T13:57:01Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="3314071">thegoldentickets</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Beautifully peaceful spot, what a history! Kids loved this one, clue was great. Had lovely picnic by the church.     </groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="97980687">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-02-22T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2553511">Jumpin Jiminie</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Dont think I used the correct route on this one!!! Parked the car in a lane blocked off by a big boulder and continued on foot. Had to cross some very muddy farmland and climb over the wall to get into the cemetery.

Anyway quick find after that and then it was back across the muddy field and back to the car.

TFTC

Jamie</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="94095945">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-12-31T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2044674">roryward</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Beautiful, although cold, New Years Eve. Brought the whole family and parked on street, not near the white gate. Found the cemetery easily and with help from the hint, found the exact spot. Still had to poke around to find the cache. It is well camouflaged with it's surroundings ;-) Left a Liverpool FC key ring. TFTC
</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
