<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>004540</id>
  <cache-id>GC1PF3H</cache-id>
  <type>Unknown Cache</type>
  <name>2 A Walk in the Garden-Kilbride Circuit by Kili or Bust, Unknown Cache (3.5/3.5)</name>
  <size>Small</size>
  <difficulty>3.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>3.5</terrain>
  <last-found>2009-08-29</last-found>
  <placed>2009-04-10</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Kili or Bust</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.20005</lat>
  <lon>-6.40815</lon>
  <last-logs>FFWFF</last-logs>
  <owner>Kili or bust</owner>
  <description>
      </description>
  <long-description><b><i>The mountain<br />
sat upon the plain<br />
In his eternal<br />
chair,<br />
His observation<br />
omnifold,<br />
His inquest everywhere.<br />
<br />
The seasons<br />
prayed<br />
around his knees,<br />
Like children round a sire:<br />
Grandfather of the days<br />
is he,<br />
Of dawn the ancestor.<br />
(Emily Dickinson)</i></b><br />
<br />
This is a walk on 4 low level mountains in the &ldquo;Garden
County&rdquo; Wicklow but right next to the border with Co. Dublin.
The walk takes you on a circular route around the Army firing range
at Kilbride (ring 01 4582428 for firing days. Red flags or lights
will be evident on those days). The walk stays at the perimeter and
well away from any problems! This is an excellent, easy half day
10K walk only a short distance from the city so do try to pick a
nice day. Total ascent is just 553m. There are Megallithic Tombs on
two of the mountains which are well worth a look! The coordinates
above just provide the parking area near the entrance to Kilbride
Army Camp and most of the info required is below but you will need
to solve the puzzle here to find the start point (Stage 1) where
you will be given more crucial information (Stage 2). Don't forget
a pen and some paper! A camera would be good. The scenery speaks
for itself.<br />
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/fb6e7b96-9190-4c23-8e31-7aae63479451.jpg" /></center>
<br />
The blue line in the above image is roughly the course you must
take. From the first mountain to the second, stay close to a fence
till close to the rising ground of the second mountain where the
fence veers off to the right but you can follow any of several well
trodden mountain paths more directly to the summit and the next
Stage.<br />
After that there is a good walk to the 3rd mountain and in the
saddle between the ground can become quite boggy and soft. Good
footwear is usually advisable here in any conditions. The rest of
the walk is pretty simple and the last one is really only a hill.
Some more sticky and sloppy ground along by the stream getting
close to the road again.<br />
<br />
From Mountain Views:<br />
Seefin Mountain Waterford County<br />
Su&iacute; Finn A name in Irish<br />
(Ir. Mullach Su&iacute; Finn [LL] , 'summit of Fionn&rsquo;s
seat')<br />
Height: 726 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 75 for top Grid Ref: S27416
06822 Latitude: 52.212974 Longitude: -7.599651 ITM: 627359
606876<br />
Seefin is the 90th highest summit in Ireland.<br />
<br />
Seahan Mountain Dublin County<br />
Su&iacute;och&aacute;n A name in Irish (Ir. Su&iacute;och&aacute;n
[PWJ*], 'seat' )<br />
Height: 648 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top Grid Ref: O08121
19700 Latitude: 53.216980 Longitude: -6.382190 ITM: 708046
719729<br />
Seahan has two megalithic cairns on its summit. Liam Price noted
that Seahan appears on the Down Survey maps as "Seavick na bantree"
and rightly interpreted this as Ir. Suidhe Mhic na Baintrighe,
'seat of the widow's son'. However, he believed that the story
behind the name would never be understood: "This curious name must
have some reference to old traditions about the ancient burial
cairns which crown the top of this mountain. All such traditions
about this place have long ago disappeared ("The Antiquities and
Place Names of South County Dublin", Dublin Historical Record, vol.
ii, no. 4, 121-33)." While the precise story may never be
recovered, it should be noted that Mac na Baintr&iacute;, the
widow's son, is a common figure in Irish folktales whose
characteristics are eternal persistence and ingenuity in the face
of adversity. Seahan is the 200th highest summit in Ireland. Seahan
is the third highest point in county Dublin. <font color=
"red"><font size="4"><b>Do not start the trek without all the
proper mountain rain gear, waterproof boots and the guidance
material, compass, map, GPSr with mapping etc. Please note that all
parts of this cache are hiked at your own risk. The cache owner
takes no responsibility of any sort for any reason including
accidents or mishaps. The red broken line on the OSI map (if you
have one) is the Military Firing Range so please try to remain
outside that line. Ring the military at 01 4582428 to check the
firing days.<br /></b></font></font><br />
<i><b>On<br />
Emerald<br />
Glistening hills, naught but<br />
Tinkling streams and soft bog with purple frills, and<br />
Sparkling<br />
Granite, rich<br />
With eons of earth<br />
Life, washed and heaven fed,<br />
Where doe, grouse and silent fox gentle lay their<br />
Cubbing bed, and young men lie dead.<br />
(Anon, WW1)<br /></b></i><br />
This cache would not be advisable during periods of snow!<br />
<br />
At Stage 3 take 4 letters away from the last word (the metal sign,
not the newer wooden one). How many are left. This = C. Complete
the following for Stage 4: N53 12. AB(B+C) W006 22.CCA<br />
<br />
At Stage 4 find 3 vertical numbers = DEF (total 18). Complete the
following with new numbers etc to find coords for Stage 5 at N53
13.(C-1)CA W006 22 (A+1)B(A+1)<br />
<br />
At Stage 5 find 3 more digits (even trigits!) these = GHi (total
16). Complete the following to find the final cache coordinates:
N53 12.A(E-5)D W006 23.(F-2)(H-4)(G+i-9) Keep forest (mostly cut
down) on right and follow stream toward the cache and then back
down to the road N53 12.498 W006 24.194. Go left and walk for
approx 1K back to the car park.<br />
<br />
Seefingan Mountain Dublin/ Wicklow County<br />
Su&iacute; Fingain A name in Irish (Ir. Su&iacute; Fingain [OSNB*],
'Fingan's seat') Height: 724 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top
Grid Ref: O08671 16935 Latitude: 53.192034 Longitude: -6.374900
ITM: 708596 716964<br />
Seefingan, like Seefin and Seahan, has a large megalithic cairn on
its summit. Seefingan is the 92nd highest summit in Ireland.
Seefingan is the second highest point in county Dublin.<br />
<br />
Corrig Mountain Mountain Dublin/ Wicklow County An Charraig A name
in Irish (Ir. An Charraig [OSI], 'rock') Height: 618 metres OS
1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top Grid Ref: O09050 19364 Latitude:
53.213772 Longitude: -6.368404 ITM: 708975 719393<br />
Nowadays there are actually no rocks on this boggy top. The name
was reported as Corriganoura by Price's informant (PNCW). Corrig
Mountain is the 248th highest summit in Ireland. <font color=
"red"><font size="4">Please be aware that cars parked in areas
close to walking trails are vulnerable and they can be vandalised
or stolen. Unfortunately this is an ongoing problem which is
extremely difficult to solve. so there is a risk involved.<br />
<br />
Please observe the country code to the best of your ability. Local
landowners often generously allow access to upland areas across or
through parts of their private property. Please, please be
conscious of this and return the courtesy by keeping all gates
closed, immediately and not on your way back!. Please use the gates
where appropriate but if you have to climb over them then use the
hinged side ONLY.<br />
Please do not cause any damage of any sort to fences or barriers
along the way.<br /></font></font><br />
<b><i>INMATE of a mountain-dwelling,<br />
Thou hast clomb aloft,<br />
And gazed<br />
From the watch-towers of Helvellyn;<br />
Awed, delighted,<br />
And amazed!<br />
(William Wordsworth)</i></b><br />
<br />
Check Start Coords: <a href=
"http://www.geochecker.com/index.php?code=3921da2cf735111a9a9b718e7c21d1ab&action=check&wp=47433150463348&name=3220412057616c6b20696e207468652047617264656e">
Geochecker.com</a>.<br />
<br />
<p><br />
Check Final Coords: <a href=
"http://www.geochecker.com/index.php?code=189b8f079b35fbec28a9359de90e4f0d&action=check&wp=47433150463348&name=3220412057616c6b20696e207468652047617264656e2046696e616c">
Geochecker.com</a>.</p></long-description>
  <encoded-hints>Final: Near fence</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=13ec5ce9-bfe8-44a6-bb4f-189e2dafd064</url>
  <url-name>2 A Walk in the Garden-Kilbride Circuit</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-02-20T20:00:00Z : Found it by Fjon <br />Did this one with Donnacha on a nice cold & windless day. 
If you're not of a certain age you're going to need an internet phone for stage 1! And stage 4, well you need a magnifying glass and some very good eye sight to pick out the weathered numbers there. 
Apart from these two small problems we had, it was a really enjoyable walk. Snow for the most part, which I imagine is much more pleasant than the bog and heather that was underneath. 
My only regret is I didn't get to see any of the tombs on any of the summits. </li><li>2010-02-20T20:00:00Z : Found it by Donnacha <br />Found with Fjon on a perfect day for this walk. As I approached the parking area who did I meet but Hezekiah, starting the walk in the opposite direction. We then met again about half way around the circuit. I didn't think I'd be walking in snow again this year, but with snow still remaining from the last fall and the small bit that fell last night, we found ourselves walking through some drifts, it was pretty cool with some amazing views of the snow covered landscape. This is why I started Geocaching all those years ago.

Lucky for us we both had internet enabled devices to help solve stage 1 so with that out of the way we started our trek up the mountain stopping along the way to take in the views. After having a coffee at stage 2 we headed off for stage 3. There seem to be a new second sign post but it was obvious as to which one we had to use. Off to stage 4 then and after an unsuccessful quick look around it was lunch time. After a bit of grub we resumed the search for the numbers. We found the numbers quite difficult to find and I wouldn't be surprised if they get weathered off by the summer. Numbers found quickly at stage 5, then it was off to find the cache which we found quickly.

An excellent walk which I enjoyed very much, and made even better finding a Geocache. Thanks Sean.</li><li>2009-10-05T19:00:00Z : Write note by Hezekiah <br />"WD"is for "War Department" - the stones mark the perimeter of the range!</li><li>2009-10-04T19:00:00Z : Found it by daraconn <br />A very enjoyable walk in a part of the mountains that I hadn't visited for nearly 20 years. I remembered the excitement of squeezing into the narrow entrance of the Seefin passage grave, so I brought my head-torch. Imagine my surprise, when I squeezed in this time, to find that the roof had collapsed over the centre of the passage, exposing the passage and half-burying two of the five burial chambers. I couldn't believe it - it's stood here for 5000 years, and during my lifetime it fell down. Anyway, it's an extraordinary and very special monument, and well-worth the walk to visit it.

I was unable to decipher the information at Stage 1; I knew the "code" but had no way of translating it. But even without resolving the co-ordinates I had no difficulty finding the sign at Stage 2. I had a little more difficulty at Stage 4 - we were unable to find the 3 vertical numbers, and eventually gave up. However, using the information we had already gathered, and the information in the description, I was able to find the cache. This is my second in the "A Walk in the Garden" series, and I am very impressed.

I was interested in the "bench-mark" stones of which we came across at least 3 along the route. Each was inscribed with "WD" (and a bench-mark symbol between the two letters), and a number, and two of them said "Centre of Stream". "WD" = "water department"? "Wicklow district"?

I took the TB Jagged Metal Token, which links into my plans for next week. Thanks for a great cache.</li><li>2009-08-29T19:00:00Z : Found it by toczygroszek <br />It was great challenge! My 7th of "Walk in the Garden" series and favourite. "Cup of tea" to owner ;)

Start point was only 23 km from my home, so decided go there by bicycle. Got puncture when just arriving, but fixed id after. I was very confused reading informatons from stage 1, fut finaly solved it "about" [:o)] Stage 4 took me few minutes - not that easy [8D]
Nice walk, very windy and some showers, but generally not bad. Great view of Dublin, Howth, Lambay Island. Only ravens, sheep and... motor biker [:)]

Really nice walk, amazing only one find before. TFTC</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.20005" lon="-6.40815">
    <time>2009-04-10T07:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GC1PF3H</name>
    <desc>2 A Walk in the Garden-Kilbride Circuit by Kili or Bust, Unknown Cache (3.5/3.5)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=13ec5ce9-bfe8-44a6-bb4f-189e2dafd064</url>
    <urlname>2 A Walk in the Garden-Kilbride Circuit</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Unknown Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="1182328" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>2 A Walk in the Garden-Kilbride Circuit</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Kili or Bust</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="281705">Kili or bust</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Unknown Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Small</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>3.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>3.5</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Leinster</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">
      </groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The mountain&lt;br /&gt;
sat upon the plain&lt;br /&gt;
In his eternal&lt;br /&gt;
chair,&lt;br /&gt;
His observation&lt;br /&gt;
omnifold,&lt;br /&gt;
His inquest everywhere.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The seasons&lt;br /&gt;
prayed&lt;br /&gt;
around his knees,&lt;br /&gt;
Like children round a sire:&lt;br /&gt;
Grandfather of the days&lt;br /&gt;
is he,&lt;br /&gt;
Of dawn the ancestor.&lt;br /&gt;
(Emily Dickinson)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is a walk on 4 low level mountains in the &amp;ldquo;Garden
County&amp;rdquo; Wicklow but right next to the border with Co. Dublin.
The walk takes you on a circular route around the Army firing range
at Kilbride (ring 01 4582428 for firing days. Red flags or lights
will be evident on those days). The walk stays at the perimeter and
well away from any problems! This is an excellent, easy half day
10K walk only a short distance from the city so do try to pick a
nice day. Total ascent is just 553m. There are Megallithic Tombs on
two of the mountains which are well worth a look! The coordinates
above just provide the parking area near the entrance to Kilbride
Army Camp and most of the info required is below but you will need
to solve the puzzle here to find the start point (Stage 1) where
you will be given more crucial information (Stage 2). Don't forget
a pen and some paper! A camera would be good. The scenery speaks
for itself.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/fb6e7b96-9190-4c23-8e31-7aae63479451.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The blue line in the above image is roughly the course you must
take. From the first mountain to the second, stay close to a fence
till close to the rising ground of the second mountain where the
fence veers off to the right but you can follow any of several well
trodden mountain paths more directly to the summit and the next
Stage.&lt;br /&gt;
After that there is a good walk to the 3rd mountain and in the
saddle between the ground can become quite boggy and soft. Good
footwear is usually advisable here in any conditions. The rest of
the walk is pretty simple and the last one is really only a hill.
Some more sticky and sloppy ground along by the stream getting
close to the road again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From Mountain Views:&lt;br /&gt;
Seefin Mountain Waterford County&lt;br /&gt;
Su&amp;iacute; Finn A name in Irish&lt;br /&gt;
(Ir. Mullach Su&amp;iacute; Finn [LL] , 'summit of Fionn&amp;rsquo;s
seat')&lt;br /&gt;
Height: 726 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 75 for top Grid Ref: S27416
06822 Latitude: 52.212974 Longitude: -7.599651 ITM: 627359
606876&lt;br /&gt;
Seefin is the 90th highest summit in Ireland.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Seahan Mountain Dublin County&lt;br /&gt;
Su&amp;iacute;och&amp;aacute;n A name in Irish (Ir. Su&amp;iacute;och&amp;aacute;n
[PWJ*], 'seat' )&lt;br /&gt;
Height: 648 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top Grid Ref: O08121
19700 Latitude: 53.216980 Longitude: -6.382190 ITM: 708046
719729&lt;br /&gt;
Seahan has two megalithic cairns on its summit. Liam Price noted
that Seahan appears on the Down Survey maps as "Seavick na bantree"
and rightly interpreted this as Ir. Suidhe Mhic na Baintrighe,
'seat of the widow's son'. However, he believed that the story
behind the name would never be understood: "This curious name must
have some reference to old traditions about the ancient burial
cairns which crown the top of this mountain. All such traditions
about this place have long ago disappeared ("The Antiquities and
Place Names of South County Dublin", Dublin Historical Record, vol.
ii, no. 4, 121-33)." While the precise story may never be
recovered, it should be noted that Mac na Baintr&amp;iacute;, the
widow's son, is a common figure in Irish folktales whose
characteristics are eternal persistence and ingenuity in the face
of adversity. Seahan is the 200th highest summit in Ireland. Seahan
is the third highest point in county Dublin. &lt;font color=
"red"&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do not start the trek without all the
proper mountain rain gear, waterproof boots and the guidance
material, compass, map, GPSr with mapping etc. Please note that all
parts of this cache are hiked at your own risk. The cache owner
takes no responsibility of any sort for any reason including
accidents or mishaps. The red broken line on the OSI map (if you
have one) is the Military Firing Range so please try to remain
outside that line. Ring the military at 01 4582428 to check the
firing days.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;On&lt;br /&gt;
Emerald&lt;br /&gt;
Glistening hills, naught but&lt;br /&gt;
Tinkling streams and soft bog with purple frills, and&lt;br /&gt;
Sparkling&lt;br /&gt;
Granite, rich&lt;br /&gt;
With eons of earth&lt;br /&gt;
Life, washed and heaven fed,&lt;br /&gt;
Where doe, grouse and silent fox gentle lay their&lt;br /&gt;
Cubbing bed, and young men lie dead.&lt;br /&gt;
(Anon, WW1)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This cache would not be advisable during periods of snow!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At Stage 3 take 4 letters away from the last word (the metal sign,
not the newer wooden one). How many are left. This = C. Complete
the following for Stage 4: N53 12. AB(B+C) W006 22.CCA&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At Stage 4 find 3 vertical numbers = DEF (total 18). Complete the
following with new numbers etc to find coords for Stage 5 at N53
13.(C-1)CA W006 22 (A+1)B(A+1)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At Stage 5 find 3 more digits (even trigits!) these = GHi (total
16). Complete the following to find the final cache coordinates:
N53 12.A(E-5)D W006 23.(F-2)(H-4)(G+i-9) Keep forest (mostly cut
down) on right and follow stream toward the cache and then back
down to the road N53 12.498 W006 24.194. Go left and walk for
approx 1K back to the car park.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Seefingan Mountain Dublin/ Wicklow County&lt;br /&gt;
Su&amp;iacute; Fingain A name in Irish (Ir. Su&amp;iacute; Fingain [OSNB*],
'Fingan's seat') Height: 724 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top
Grid Ref: O08671 16935 Latitude: 53.192034 Longitude: -6.374900
ITM: 708596 716964&lt;br /&gt;
Seefingan, like Seefin and Seahan, has a large megalithic cairn on
its summit. Seefingan is the 92nd highest summit in Ireland.
Seefingan is the second highest point in county Dublin.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Corrig Mountain Mountain Dublin/ Wicklow County An Charraig A name
in Irish (Ir. An Charraig [OSI], 'rock') Height: 618 metres OS
1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top Grid Ref: O09050 19364 Latitude:
53.213772 Longitude: -6.368404 ITM: 708975 719393&lt;br /&gt;
Nowadays there are actually no rocks on this boggy top. The name
was reported as Corriganoura by Price's informant (PNCW). Corrig
Mountain is the 248th highest summit in Ireland. &lt;font color=
"red"&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Please be aware that cars parked in areas
close to walking trails are vulnerable and they can be vandalised
or stolen. Unfortunately this is an ongoing problem which is
extremely difficult to solve. so there is a risk involved.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Please observe the country code to the best of your ability. Local
landowners often generously allow access to upland areas across or
through parts of their private property. Please, please be
conscious of this and return the courtesy by keeping all gates
closed, immediately and not on your way back!. Please use the gates
where appropriate but if you have to climb over them then use the
hinged side ONLY.&lt;br /&gt;
Please do not cause any damage of any sort to fences or barriers
along the way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;INMATE of a mountain-dwelling,&lt;br /&gt;
Thou hast clomb aloft,&lt;br /&gt;
And gazed&lt;br /&gt;
From the watch-towers of Helvellyn;&lt;br /&gt;
Awed, delighted,&lt;br /&gt;
And amazed!&lt;br /&gt;
(William Wordsworth)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Check Start Coords: &lt;a href=
"http://www.geochecker.com/index.php?code=3921da2cf735111a9a9b718e7c21d1ab&amp;amp;action=check&amp;amp;wp=47433150463348&amp;amp;name=3220412057616c6b20696e207468652047617264656e"&gt;
Geochecker.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Check Final Coords: &lt;a href=
"http://www.geochecker.com/index.php?code=189b8f079b35fbec28a9359de90e4f0d&amp;amp;action=check&amp;amp;wp=47433150463348&amp;amp;name=3220412057616c6b20696e207468652047617264656e2046696e616c"&gt;
Geochecker.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>Final: Near fence</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="97725362">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-02-20T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="243261">Fjon</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Did this one with Donnacha on a nice cold &amp; windless day. 
If you're not of a certain age you're going to need an internet phone for stage 1! And stage 4, well you need a magnifying glass and some very good eye sight to pick out the weathered numbers there. 
Apart from these two small problems we had, it was a really enjoyable walk. Snow for the most part, which I imagine is much more pleasant than the bog and heather that was underneath. 
My only regret is I didn't get to see any of the tombs on any of the summits. </groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="97722197">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-02-20T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="61401">Donnacha</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found with Fjon on a perfect day for this walk. As I approached the parking area who did I meet but Hezekiah, starting the walk in the opposite direction. We then met again about half way around the circuit. I didn't think I'd be walking in snow again this year, but with snow still remaining from the last fall and the small bit that fell last night, we found ourselves walking through some drifts, it was pretty cool with some amazing views of the snow covered landscape. This is why I started Geocaching all those years ago.

Lucky for us we both had internet enabled devices to help solve stage 1 so with that out of the way we started our trek up the mountain stopping along the way to take in the views. After having a coffee at stage 2 we headed off for stage 3. There seem to be a new second sign post but it was obvious as to which one we had to use. Off to stage 4 then and after an unsuccessful quick look around it was lunch time. After a bit of grub we resumed the search for the numbers. We found the numbers quite difficult to find and I wouldn't be surprised if they get weathered off by the summer. Numbers found quickly at stage 5, then it was off to find the cache which we found quickly.

An excellent walk which I enjoyed very much, and made even better finding a Geocache. Thanks Sean.</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="86585089">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-10-05T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Write note</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="274644">Hezekiah</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">"WD"is for "War Department" - the stones mark the perimeter of the range!</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="86426929">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-10-04T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="591662">daraconn</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">A very enjoyable walk in a part of the mountains that I hadn't visited for nearly 20 years. I remembered the excitement of squeezing into the narrow entrance of the Seefin passage grave, so I brought my head-torch. Imagine my surprise, when I squeezed in this time, to find that the roof had collapsed over the centre of the passage, exposing the passage and half-burying two of the five burial chambers. I couldn't believe it - it's stood here for 5000 years, and during my lifetime it fell down. Anyway, it's an extraordinary and very special monument, and well-worth the walk to visit it.

I was unable to decipher the information at Stage 1; I knew the "code" but had no way of translating it. But even without resolving the co-ordinates I had no difficulty finding the sign at Stage 2. I had a little more difficulty at Stage 4 - we were unable to find the 3 vertical numbers, and eventually gave up. However, using the information we had already gathered, and the information in the description, I was able to find the cache. This is my second in the "A Walk in the Garden" series, and I am very impressed.

I was interested in the "bench-mark" stones of which we came across at least 3 along the route. Each was inscribed with "WD" (and a bench-mark symbol between the two letters), and a number, and two of them said "Centre of Stream". "WD" = "water department"? "Wicklow district"?

I took the TB Jagged Metal Token, which links into my plans for next week. Thanks for a great cache.</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="82443428">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-08-29T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1429023">toczygroszek</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">It was great challenge! My 7th of "Walk in the Garden" series and favourite. "Cup of tea" to owner ;)

Start point was only 23 km from my home, so decided go there by bicycle. Got puncture when just arriving, but fixed id after. I was very confused reading informatons from stage 1, fut finaly solved it "about" [:o)] Stage 4 took me few minutes - not that easy [8D]
Nice walk, very windy and some showers, but generally not bad. Great view of Dublin, Howth, Lambay Island. Only ravens, sheep and... motor biker [:)]

Really nice walk, amazing only one find before. TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
