<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>004818</id>
  <cache-id>GC1N065</cache-id>
  <type>Unknown Cache</type>
  <name>Where Bats Dare by toczygroszek, Unknown Cache (1.5/4)</name>
  <size>Small</size>
  <difficulty>1.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>4</terrain>
  <last-found>2010-03-12</last-found>
  <placed>2009-02-27</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>toczygroszek</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.3627</lat>
  <lon>-6.071433</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFFF</last-logs>
  <owner>toczygroszek</owner>
  <description>This cache is the real caving adventure. It's a dangerous challenge
so read carefully whole description below.</description>
  <long-description><center>
<img src="http://img.geocaching.com/cache/56a32bff-f262-4313-aead-1d5088075944.jpg" />
</center>
<br />
<p align="justify">Coordinates are not exactly at the cache
location. The cache is hidden in a cave in a cliff at sea level
where there is no GPS signal, so coordinates take you are only to
the entrance to the cave. Cache is accessible only during low tide,
at high tide the cave is full of water. You can check tides
<b><a href="http://easytide.ukho.gov.uk/EasyTide/EasyTide/SelectPrediction.aspx?PortID=0618"
   target="_blank">HERE</a></b>. You don't have to be exactly at
   the time of the lowest level of water, 2 hours before and after
   is enough. But <font color="red"><b>NEVER try to get into the
   cave at high tide, its extremely dangerous!</b></font><br />
Unfortunately, even at low tide there is still a small lake/puddle
at the entrance to the cave so you have to bring
<font color="blue"><b>wellingtons</b></font> with you. You can
climb above water, but only if you have good experience in rock
climbing, otherwise you will fall into the water
<img src='http://www.geocaching.com/images/icons/icon_smile_wink.gif'
     border="0" align="middle" />. You have to bring a
     <font color="blue"><b>torch</b></font> with you because the
     cache is placed in complete darkness.<br />
<br />
Cave is always a dangerous spot, even if it's small, and especially
where periodically flooded by water. There is no cellphone signal
inside and nobody will see and hear you when you are in the cave.
Cave is a very special ecosystem worth protecting, with its special
climate, fauna and flora. Regarding all those things
remember:<br />
<br />
<font color="green"><b>- Don't go to the cave alone, if you happen
to have even a small accident, you will in big trouble. Always
leave a note with your family or friend saying where the cave is
and when you plan to get out of the cave and give them a ring when
you come back onto a safe ground.<br />
<br />
- Always carry an extra torch in case you lose or break down your
only one light.<br />
<br />
- Take some warm cloths because it is cold and humid inside the
cave.<br />
<br />
- Don't use open fire as smoke will blacken the walls and may kill
some creatures (including you
<img src='http://www.geocaching.com/images/icons/icon_smile_wink.gif'
     border="0" align="middle" />).<br />
<br />
- Don't disturb any creatures inside.<br />
<br />
- Don't left any rubbish behind you or inscription on the
walls.</b><br />
<br /></font> There are two paths from the top of the cliff to the
beach below. It's your decision which one will you use. One is at N
53° 21.741 W 006° 04.478 and second at N 53° 21.903 W 006° 03.971.
Both paths are very steep and the way to the cave is rocky and
slippery so proper walking boots are strongly recommended.<br />
<br />
 <b>Cache location:</b><br />
<br />
Go straight into the cave through approx. 10 m long lake/puddle,
and then turn right into a dark passage, and go about 15 m to the
end, where you will find the cache. The cache is a small tupperware
container with a logbook, pencil and some goodies.<br />
<br />
Have a look at the attached pictures to see details of the
terrain.<br />
<br />
 Please replace the cache and its cover exactly as you found it.
And please report any problems with the cache and its location.</p>
<br />
<br />
<a href="http://flagcounter.com/more/DF7"><img src="http://flagcounter.com/count/DF7/bg=FFFFFF/txt=000000/border=CCCCCC/columns=6/maxflags=248/viewers=0/labels=1/"
     alt="free counters" border="0" /></a> <br />
<br />
<!--start of handicaching link-->
<p><a href="http://www.handicaching.com/show.php?waypoint=GC1N065"
target="_blank"><img src="http://www.handicaching.com/images/seal_rater2.gif"
     border="0" alt="View the ratings for GC1N065" /></a></p>
<!--end of handicaching link--></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>P11N065 - Path1<br />N 53° 21.741 W 006° 04.478<br /><br />P21N065 - Path2<br />N 53° 21.903 W 006° 03.971<br /><br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:P11N065|waypoints:cache-id:P21N065</links>
  <encoded-hints>left side, chest height, dark stone</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=fca5ddba-4b28-4c7d-a982-d8dbd2bc60b7</url>
  <url-name>Where Bats Dare</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-04-18T19:00:00Z : Found it by premg <br />What an adventure with crannyn and hollmanr. After a lot of scrambing over rocks and a few minor injuries we finally got to front of cave. Great excitement and great stories to tell afterwards! Finished off with fish & chips in Howth. SL TFTC</li><li>2010-04-18T19:00:00Z : Found it by Crannyn <br />We celebrated our 100th find with this one! After carefull navigation over rocks and a few bumps and bruises we eventually found it.Great excitement with the kids! Thank goodness we remembered the torches.TB - IN. TFTC</li><li>2010-04-18T19:00:00Z : Found it by hollmanr <br />Our team has been split up with my better half stuck in US due to all the volcanic ash .. so geocaching simultaneously in 2 countries. We visited this cache site last week but alas forgot the torch so back again with crannyn this week. We did a lot of walking before hand as we were too close to full tide and actually went down path 1 then path 2 and then as we still couldn't access it path 1 again with a lot of kids who were brilliant and stuck the pace well. Rocks were very slippy and we had a few minor injuries amongst the younger members of  the group on route. It was a lovely day and we were prepared for the rock pool at the entrance but not for the rather hilarious entrances by some of the kids .... although they weren't all laughing .... and the water was sooo cold. (We had spotted a mother and son having a quick dip in Drumleck Point a short while before that .. pure madness!).
I ventured into the cave passage leaving kids at entrance to passage shining their torches .. it was very wet and slippy and dark inside so didn't want to risk any more injuries. Found the cache no problem but rock mentioned in the hint was jammed tight into the cache site and couldn't budge it to retrieve cache. crannyn came in and we tried for ages .. about to give up when crannyn got it unwedged and we managed to retrieve it and brought it back to the kids to sign. Great excitement!
Great cache; SL TNLN TFTC
</li><li>2010-03-28T19:00:00Z : Found it by Spark_ie <br />Wayhay !!  Finally, on my second attempt !  I'm not proud of having the only DNF on this one, especially seen as I got right to the cache location last time round, but didn't use my head to find the cache !!! This time round, both my schedule, the weather, and the tide all suited, and I had to go for it !!   Got to the entrance of the cave no problems, and after some acrobatics, I managed to make it into the cave with dry feet ! [:)] Got to the cache location no problems, and found the cache instantly... Just don't know how I missed it last time !!!  Swopped Geocoins and made my way back.  Halfway back out, I could hear a load of waves crashing on the rocks outside, the sound of this echoing around the cave wasn't all the settling, but it turned out they were waves from a passing Irish Ferries Ship !!! Thanks for a great Cache!!    Spark_ie           (Rated 5 stars with [url=http://www.gcvote.com]GCVote[/url])</li><li>2010-03-12T20:00:00Z : Found it by Moonshiner Extraordinaire <br />As the tide was right, I asked Anna if I could try for this cache on our way home (Marijanna was asleep in the back of the car). She said “OK” but that she’d stay in the car (a wise choice – staying in the car, I mean). We parked right down at the end of Ceanchor Road. At the path, I had to choose ‘right’ or ‘left’. I chose right (path1) and when I reached those co-ords, I knew I had been down on that beach before (for a cache). The co-ords were at the Jameson (whiskey people) family’s private under-public-path entry to their private beach (look for their sea swimming pool). Anyway, I made my way down to the beach and across the rocks to the cave entrance (my GPS ‘0’ exactly) – a bit cumbersome, because I was wearing my wellies. The tide was ‘miles’ out. Once inside, I forgot about the instructions on the cache page (and my field notes) – and proceeded to search in the wrong place (for ages). With the light from my little torch getting weak, I gave up and headed for the entrance. Just inside the entrance pool, I read my field notes – and cursed vigorously when I realised my error! Because my torch batteries were almost gone, I kept the torch off until I really needed it (feeling my way, although it’s amazing what you can see with so little light – my FCÁ training came in handy). Close to the cache, I switched my torch on (miserable light) and quickly found the cache (at 17:03). While signing the log, I became aware of loud wave noises – causing me to speed up and replace the cache (as well as lament that I was alone). With it safely replaced, I wasted no time making my way to the entrance and out. The tide hadn’t quite reached the cave but it was pretty close (and already appeared to be somewhat higher than the pool level – so that when it did start to flow into the cave, the level would rapidly rise a foot or a foot and a half). I was pleased to have found the cache and be back out in daylight. I was going to wait and watch the water flowing in, but was distracted by the sound of a dog barking nearby. Looking towards it, I saw it was a large seal ‘barking’ at me and throwing its head around. Alarmed (thinking it might attack), I turned to ‘run’ for the beach. Immediately, I saw that the incoming tide had almost cut me off… Only the tops of rocks were above the water – so I ran over them, using them as stepping stones. When I was safely back on the beach, I heard the seal again – it had apparently kept pace with me while I made my way back. In my mind, I now believed that the seal had been warning me of the danger – and had kept an eye on me afterwards! I shouted thanks to it and waved to it until I started climbing the steps. When I reached the top (the path), the seal had gone. What a day – and what a cache! Go raibh maith agat faoi’n taisce iontach seo.

Moonshiner X (cache #1,240)</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.3627" lon="-6.071433">
    <time>2009-02-27T08:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GC1N065</name>
    <desc>Where Bats Dare by toczygroszek, Unknown Cache (1.5/4)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=fca5ddba-4b28-4c7d-a982-d8dbd2bc60b7</url>
    <urlname>Where Bats Dare</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Unknown Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="1138203" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Where Bats Dare</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>toczygroszek</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="1429023">toczygroszek</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Unknown Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Small</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>1.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>4</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Dublin</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">This cache is the real caving adventure. It's a dangerous challenge
so read carefully whole description below.</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src="http://img.geocaching.com/cache/56a32bff-f262-4313-aead-1d5088075944.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p align="justify"&gt;Coordinates are not exactly at the cache
location. The cache is hidden in a cave in a cliff at sea level
where there is no GPS signal, so coordinates take you are only to
the entrance to the cave. Cache is accessible only during low tide,
at high tide the cave is full of water. You can check tides
&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://easytide.ukho.gov.uk/EasyTide/EasyTide/SelectPrediction.aspx?PortID=0618"
   target="_blank"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;. You don't have to be exactly at
   the time of the lowest level of water, 2 hours before and after
   is enough. But &lt;font color="red"&gt;&lt;b&gt;NEVER try to get into the
   cave at high tide, its extremely dangerous!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Unfortunately, even at low tide there is still a small lake/puddle
at the entrance to the cave so you have to bring
&lt;font color="blue"&gt;&lt;b&gt;wellingtons&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt; with you. You can
climb above water, but only if you have good experience in rock
climbing, otherwise you will fall into the water
&lt;img src='http://www.geocaching.com/images/icons/icon_smile_wink.gif'
     border="0" align="middle" /&gt;. You have to bring a
     &lt;font color="blue"&gt;&lt;b&gt;torch&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt; with you because the
     cache is placed in complete darkness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cave is always a dangerous spot, even if it's small, and especially
where periodically flooded by water. There is no cellphone signal
inside and nobody will see and hear you when you are in the cave.
Cave is a very special ecosystem worth protecting, with its special
climate, fauna and flora. Regarding all those things
remember:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;font color="green"&gt;&lt;b&gt;- Don't go to the cave alone, if you happen
to have even a small accident, you will in big trouble. Always
leave a note with your family or friend saying where the cave is
and when you plan to get out of the cave and give them a ring when
you come back onto a safe ground.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
- Always carry an extra torch in case you lose or break down your
only one light.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
- Take some warm cloths because it is cold and humid inside the
cave.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
- Don't use open fire as smoke will blacken the walls and may kill
some creatures (including you
&lt;img src='http://www.geocaching.com/images/icons/icon_smile_wink.gif'
     border="0" align="middle" /&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
- Don't disturb any creatures inside.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
- Don't left any rubbish behind you or inscription on the
walls.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt; There are two paths from the top of the cliff to the
beach below. It's your decision which one will you use. One is at N
53° 21.741 W 006° 04.478 and second at N 53° 21.903 W 006° 03.971.
Both paths are very steep and the way to the cave is rocky and
slippery so proper walking boots are strongly recommended.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;Cache location:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Go straight into the cave through approx. 10 m long lake/puddle,
and then turn right into a dark passage, and go about 15 m to the
end, where you will find the cache. The cache is a small tupperware
container with a logbook, pencil and some goodies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Have a look at the attached pictures to see details of the
terrain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
 Please replace the cache and its cover exactly as you found it.
And please report any problems with the cache and its location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://flagcounter.com/more/DF7"&gt;&lt;img src="http://flagcounter.com/count/DF7/bg=FFFFFF/txt=000000/border=CCCCCC/columns=6/maxflags=248/viewers=0/labels=1/"
     alt="free counters" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--start of handicaching link--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.handicaching.com/show.php?waypoint=GC1N065"
target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.handicaching.com/images/seal_rater2.gif"
     border="0" alt="View the ratings for GC1N065" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--end of handicaching link--&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;P11N065 - Path1&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 21.741 W 006° 04.478&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;P21N065 - Path2&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 21.903 W 006° 03.971&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>left side, chest height, dark stone</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="105296895">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-18T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="3199198">premg</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">What an adventure with crannyn and hollmanr. After a lot of scrambing over rocks and a few minor injuries we finally got to front of cave. Great excitement and great stories to tell afterwards! Finished off with fish &amp; chips in Howth. SL TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="104897466">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-18T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2557004">Crannyn</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">We celebrated our 100th find with this one! After carefull navigation over rocks and a few bumps and bruises we eventually found it.Great excitement with the kids! Thank goodness we remembered the torches.TB - IN. TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="104888801">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-18T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2511647">hollmanr</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Our team has been split up with my better half stuck in US due to all the volcanic ash .. so geocaching simultaneously in 2 countries. We visited this cache site last week but alas forgot the torch so back again with crannyn this week. We did a lot of walking before hand as we were too close to full tide and actually went down path 1 then path 2 and then as we still couldn't access it path 1 again with a lot of kids who were brilliant and stuck the pace well. Rocks were very slippy and we had a few minor injuries amongst the younger members of  the group on route. It was a lovely day and we were prepared for the rock pool at the entrance but not for the rather hilarious entrances by some of the kids .... although they weren't all laughing .... and the water was sooo cold. (We had spotted a mother and son having a quick dip in Drumleck Point a short while before that .. pure madness!).
I ventured into the cave passage leaving kids at entrance to passage shining their torches .. it was very wet and slippy and dark inside so didn't want to risk any more injuries. Found the cache no problem but rock mentioned in the hint was jammed tight into the cache site and couldn't budge it to retrieve cache. crannyn came in and we tried for ages .. about to give up when crannyn got it unwedged and we managed to retrieve it and brought it back to the kids to sign. Great excitement!
Great cache; SL TNLN TFTC
</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="101621669">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-28T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="950104">Spark_ie</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Wayhay !!  Finally, on my second attempt !  I'm not proud of having the only DNF on this one, especially seen as I got right to the cache location last time round, but didn't use my head to find the cache !!! This time round, both my schedule, the weather, and the tide all suited, and I had to go for it !!   Got to the entrance of the cave no problems, and after some acrobatics, I managed to make it into the cave with dry feet ! [:)] Got to the cache location no problems, and found the cache instantly... Just don't know how I missed it last time !!!  Swopped Geocoins and made my way back.  Halfway back out, I could hear a load of waves crashing on the rocks outside, the sound of this echoing around the cave wasn't all the settling, but it turned out they were waves from a passing Irish Ferries Ship !!! Thanks for a great Cache!!    Spark_ie           (Rated 5 stars with [url=http://www.gcvote.com]GCVote[/url])</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="105357535">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-12T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="154025">Moonshiner Extraordinaire</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">As the tide was right, I asked Anna if I could try for this cache on our way home (Marijanna was asleep in the back of the car). She said “OK” but that she’d stay in the car (a wise choice – staying in the car, I mean). We parked right down at the end of Ceanchor Road. At the path, I had to choose ‘right’ or ‘left’. I chose right (path1) and when I reached those co-ords, I knew I had been down on that beach before (for a cache). The co-ords were at the Jameson (whiskey people) family’s private under-public-path entry to their private beach (look for their sea swimming pool). Anyway, I made my way down to the beach and across the rocks to the cave entrance (my GPS ‘0’ exactly) – a bit cumbersome, because I was wearing my wellies. The tide was ‘miles’ out. Once inside, I forgot about the instructions on the cache page (and my field notes) – and proceeded to search in the wrong place (for ages). With the light from my little torch getting weak, I gave up and headed for the entrance. Just inside the entrance pool, I read my field notes – and cursed vigorously when I realised my error! Because my torch batteries were almost gone, I kept the torch off until I really needed it (feeling my way, although it’s amazing what you can see with so little light – my FCÁ training came in handy). Close to the cache, I switched my torch on (miserable light) and quickly found the cache (at 17:03). While signing the log, I became aware of loud wave noises – causing me to speed up and replace the cache (as well as lament that I was alone). With it safely replaced, I wasted no time making my way to the entrance and out. The tide hadn’t quite reached the cave but it was pretty close (and already appeared to be somewhat higher than the pool level – so that when it did start to flow into the cave, the level would rapidly rise a foot or a foot and a half). I was pleased to have found the cache and be back out in daylight. I was going to wait and watch the water flowing in, but was distracted by the sound of a dog barking nearby. Looking towards it, I saw it was a large seal ‘barking’ at me and throwing its head around. Alarmed (thinking it might attack), I turned to ‘run’ for the beach. Immediately, I saw that the incoming tide had almost cut me off… Only the tops of rocks were above the water – so I ran over them, using them as stepping stones. When I was safely back on the beach, I heard the seal again – it had apparently kept pace with me while I made my way back. In my mind, I now believed that the seal had been warning me of the danger – and had kept an eye on me afterwards! I shouted thanks to it and waved to it until I started climbing the steps. When I reached the top (the path), the seal had gone. What a day – and what a cache! Go raibh maith agat faoi’n taisce iontach seo.

Moonshiner X (cache #1,240)</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs>
        <groundspeak:travelbug id="2006120" ref="TB2K4AF">
          <groundspeak:name>Brave Lion</groundspeak:name>
        </groundspeak:travelbug>
      </groundspeak:travelbugs>
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
