<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>005263</id>
  <cache-id>GCM7R6</cache-id>
  <type>Virtual Cache</type>
  <name>Northside Pub Crawl by Bootle, Virtual Cache (2.5/1.5)</name>
  <size>Virtual</size>
  <difficulty>2.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>1.5</terrain>
  <last-found>2009-11-19</last-found>
  <placed>2004-12-07</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Bootle</placedby>
  <found>Geocache Found</found>
  <lat>53.349883</lat>
  <lon>-6.24935</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFFFF</last-logs>
  <owner>Bootle</owner>
  <description>This Virtual Cache should take you to many of Dublin City Centre’s
finer Public Houses on the North Side of the River
Liffey!</description>
  <long-description><p align="center"><a href="http://www.geocachingireland.com"
target="_blank"><img height="53" border="0" align="middle"
width="328" src="http://geocachingireland.com/logo4.jpg" /></a></p>
<br />
 <br />
 This is a virtual cache with roughly 20 stages! However, all the
stages are close together, so the whole cache should only take you
about 60-120 minutes (or possibly much, much longer if you decide
to sample the quality of Guinness at each stage!). The terrain is
flat and you will be walking along concrete for the entire cache,
so no specialist clothing is needed. However it might be wise to
bring a calculator to figure out the answers at the end. You can
visit the pubs in any order, but the order I list them is probably
the quickest route to take. The starting point of the cache is
quite close to the Connolly train station. This cache can really
only be done on foot - leave the car in one of the city's many car
parks and head off for a stroll!<br />
<br />
Dublin has over 700 pubs, so choosing the best is always going to
be a difficult task. This particular group was chosen based on the
basis of many factors, such as history, significance, atmosphere,
etc. The idea, and much of the text in this cache page, came from
Pat Liddy's book, "Secret Dublin" (New Holland Press), which is a
must for anyone spending a significant amount of time in the city.
The route more or less follows that described in the book, but some
of the pubs are different. I'm sure I've left out many great pubs,
but there are also many great ones included. Along the route there
are several questions to be answered, all of which will help you
reach the final pub (Number 18!) on the walk. Email me the name of
that pub to complete the cache. All clues are on the buildings'
exteriors, so you will not need to go into any of them to get the
answers (although most are well worth a visit!)<br />
<br />
Satellite coverage may come and go in the city centre, but can
usually be picked up from open locations, such as along the River
Liffey and at street intersections. I've left out the names of the
pubs to encourage people to use their GPS to find them, but if
satellite coverage can't be gained, the encrypted hints will tell
you which pub to look out for. The coordinates listed above for the
cache are those for the first pub.<br />
<br />
Thanks to fellow cacher Tolmaion for a few updates on the state of
the pubs in 2009. It seems several of my original pub choices have
become victims of the recession and have closed or changed hands.
I've changed the route a little to reflect this.<br />
<br />
1) The pub-crawl starts in Dublin's recently developed financial
district, the International Financial Services Centre (IFSC). The
first pub is at N53 20.993 W 006 14.961 and was, in the 19th
century, the dockmasters office. On the shelves within you will
find many of the office trappings and samples of the examined
cargoes.&nbsp; How many clocks are on the tower on the pub?<br />
ANSWER A =<br />
<br />
2) From here, take a stroll to Connolly Station and admire the new
LUAS terminus. The LUAS is Dublin's light rail system, completed in
2004, and is a welcome addition to the capital's transport system.
From here, walk past the central bus station, Busaras, to a pub at
N53 20.998 W006 15.157. This pub is currently being renovated, but
when in operation provides a live music and night club venue, as
well as being a nice place for an after work pint. How many letter
"a"s are there in the name of this pub?<br />
ANSWER B= <br />
<br />
3) From here it's only a short distance to N53 21.053 W6 15.257.
This pub and its hotel are popular spots with the guests of the
many hostels and B&Bs along Gardiner Street. How many
sculpyures / plaques showing violins / fiddles on them are at the
entrance to the hotel.<br />
ANSWER C= <br />
<br />
4) From here, move on N53 20.930 W006 15.464. The name of the pub
suggests that, at one stage in its history, the River Liffey might
have swept by its door. On the building beside the pub you will
find two dates written in Roman numerals. Find the date the
building was erected. Bearing in mind that M=1000, D=500, C=100,
X=10 and I=1, in what year was the building erected?<br />
ANSWER D=<br />
<br />
5) Furthed down the street, at N53 20.918 W006 15.525, you will
find a fine traditional pub. What is the street number of this
pub?<br />
ANSWER E=<br />
<br />
6) Across the road at N53 20.915 W006 15.514 you will find a hotel
with a quiet pub. The hotel is popular with tourists and worth a
stop if you need a drink at this early stage in the pub-crawl!
There are two street numbers listed for this hotel. What number do
you get if you add them together?<br />
ANSWER F= <br />
<br />
7) At N53 20.911 W006 15.529 you will find a large new pub that
used to be home to the O'Connell Street branch of Bank Of Ireland.
Today the building houses a comfortable pub which serves delicious
lunches. At the front entrance to the building, count the number of
harps on the insignia above the doorway to get answer G. <br />
ANSWER G= <br />
<br />
8) Make your way northwards up O'Connell Street until you reach a
small side street on your right. Pop into the pub at N53 20 940
W006 15.530 for a relaxing Guinness and enjoy the sights and sounds
of the many Dublin characters that will probably be propping up the
bar. What is the street number for this pub? <br />
ANSWER H=<br />
<br />
9) At N53 20.837 W006 15.656 you will find the kind of pub that I
dislike the most. This modern pub will probably be recommended as a
great spot for tourists in many of the guidebooks to Dublin, but
will most likely have all sorts of terrible entertainment going on.
The last time I was there (several years ago, so it might have
improved!), there were a couple of awful balladeers reminiscing
about some distant past events, a DJ who spoke over the records
more often than not, and some ridiculous Riverdance - lite / Irish
dancing thing was being performed in a corner. Enter at your own
risk! What is the even street number of this pub? <br />
ANSWER I=<br />
<br />
10) At N53 20.814 W006 15.808 there is a much more enjoyable pub.
It is themed in a Russian Revolution style, has pleasant décor and
usually has good music. Stop here for a quick shot of vodka. How
many letters are in the name of this pub?<br />
ANSWER J=<br />
<br />
11) At N53 20.779 W006 15.949 you will find a fashionable hot-spot
located in a modern hotel. If you are trendy enough to get in you
might spot some up and coming figures from the entertainment
industry here. How many lamp-posts are in front (i.e. on the
river-side) of this hotel? <br />
ANSWER K=<br />
<br />
12) Stroll along the quays to Capel Street, a grand old street now
home to many army surplus, D-I-Y and bargain shops. At N53 20.794
W006 16.077 you will find a pub with an, eh, "interesting" name,
and some "interesting" decor inside. I was not brave enough to go
inside! Count the number of times the name of the pub appears on
the pub's windows. Add 1 to your answer and divide this number by 6
and you will have answer L. <br />
ANSWER L=<br />
<br />
13) At N53 20.767 W006 16.137 the James Joyce fans amongst you
might like to visit the Hotel where the Sirens chapter of Ulysses
is set. Unfortunately this pub is currently being slowly renovated.
Look for a blue sticker that claims this pub was once a Dublin
Tourism Member. What year is printed on this sticker? ANSWER M=
<br />
<br />
14) At N53 20.754 W006 16.168 you will find a pleasant modern pub.
How many letters in the two words that make up the name of this
pub?<br />
ANSWER N=<br />
<br />
15) The name of the pub at N53 20.748 W006 16.342 reflects the fact
that you are now in the heart of the Irish judicial quarter, with
the impressive Four Courts building a stones throw away. The
building is one of several beautiful buildings in Dublin designed
by James Gandon in the latter eighteenth century. Drop into this
pub and eavesdrop on the days events in court. At what time does
the pub open for business (just the hour is needed here - the
minutes are unimportant)? <br />
ANSWER O=<br />
<br />
16) At N53 20.758 W006 16.545 you will find another pub popular
with the employees of the courts. Find the number of the postal
district that these pubs are in. For those unfamiliar with Dublin's
postal system, this is listed on a blue and white street sign
nearby.<br />
ANSWER P= <br />
<br />
17) All you have to do now is use your answers to find the
coordinates of the final pub! This can be done by adding,
subtracting, multiplying and dividing the answers you found along
the way. In the following problems, <br />
<br />
+ means to add the values<br />
- means subtract the values<br />
x means multiply the values<br />
/ means divide the first value by the second value<br />
<br />
For the problems with brackets, figure out the answers in brackets
first before completing the rest of the problem -<br />
<br />
ANSWER 1 = (E+K)xN<br />
ANSWER 2 = (D/B) + [{(AxP) - G} x N]<br />
ANSWER 3 = H<br />
ANSWER 4 = {(M+I-G)/<(F-C)/I>} + (O/J) + L<br />
<br />
Insert your answers into the following coordinates to get the
coordinates of the last pub.<br />
<br />
(N53 ANSWER 1 . ANSWER 2) (W006 ANSWER 3 . ANSWER 4)<br />
<br />
Once you've figured this out, head to the pub and note its name
before stopping off for a well earned few
pints!&nbsp;<a href="http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=84282177-54b1-4489-9d2a-b4e98432a813"
   rel="nofollow"></a></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>02M7R6 - Stage 02<br />N 53° 20.998 W 006° 15.157<br /><br />03M7R6 - Stage 03<br />N 53° 21.053 W 006° 15.257<br /><br />04M7R6 - Stage 04<br />N 53° 20.930 W 006° 15.464<br /><br />05M7R6 - Stage 05<br />N 53° 20.918 W 006° 15.525<br /><br />06M7R6 - Stage 06<br />N 53° 20.915 W 006° 15.514<br /><br />07M7R6 - Stage 07<br />N 53° 20.911 W 006° 15.529<br /><br />08M7R6 - Stage 08<br />N 53° 20.940 W 006° 15.530<br /><br />09M7R6 - Stage 09<br />N 53° 20.837 W 006° 15.656<br /><br />10M7R6 - Stage 10<br />N 53° 20.814 W 006° 15.808<br /><br />11M7R6 - Stage 11<br />N 53° 20.779 W 006° 15.949<br /><br />12M7R6 - Stage 12<br />N 53° 20.794 W 006° 16.077<br /><br />13M7R6 - Stage 13<br />N 53° 20.767 W 006° 16.137<br /><br />14M7R6 - Stage 14<br />N 53° 20.754 W 006° 16.168<br /><br />15M7R6 - Stage 15<br />N 53° 20.748 W 006° 16.342<br /><br />16M7R6 - Stage 16<br />N 53° 20.758 W 006° 16.545<br /><br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:02M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:03M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:04M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:05M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:06M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:07M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:08M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:09M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:10M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:11M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:12M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:13M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:14M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:15M7R6|waypoints:cache-id:16M7R6</links>
  <encoded-hints>1) The Harbourmaster, IFSC; 2) The Isaac Butt, Store Street; 3) O Shea's Gardiner Street; 4) The Flowing Tide, Abbey Street; 5) Madigan’s, Abbey Street; 6) Wynn’s Hotel, Abbey Street; 7) Grand Central, O’Connell Street; 8) The Sackville Lounge, Sackville Place; 9) Knightsbridge, Bachelor’s Walk; 10) Pravda, Liffey Street; 11) The Morrison Hotel, Ormond Quay; 12) Pantibar, Capel Street; 13) The Ormond Hotel, Ormond Quay; 14) Sin E, Ormond Quay; 15) The Legal Eagle, Chancery Place; 16) The Quill, Church Street;</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=50fc843c-0190-4328-b79b-2821dfe37414</url>
  <url-name>Northside Pub Crawl</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-05-22T19:00:00Z : Found it by Bus&Betty <br />This is our second pub crawl cache and we enjoyed it as much as the first.

We finished finding the numbers and then went to a pub to have a beverage and do the math.  We plugged the coordinates into both our handheld GPS and our Nuvi, and much to our surprize, it was the pub that we had spent Thursday evening at.  

For clue 12, one needs to add 3 to the number of signs painted on the windows to get the correct answer.  

</li><li>2010-05-08T19:00:00Z : Found it by Horge der Seher <br />This one was a really great multi-virtual. However, I needed three days to tackle it. Three days, allthough I tried out only approx. 6 or 7 of the pubs. Unfortunately, I finished it at the final during midday, so the final pub was still closed. What a pitty, because not only bootle recommended it, but even my guide of Dublin. Well, I hope i will come back and visit this pub, as well. Thanks for the very nice trip through the northside!</li><li>2010-04-03T19:00:00Z : Found it by ruettenscheider <br />21:35
This one we found quickly during our Easter-holiday tour in Dublin.
Thank you for the quick logpermission.

TFTC

Sandra and Detlef from Essen, Germany</li><li>2010-03-16T19:00:00Z : Found it by Blue Jay 59 <br />Nice one. enjoyed picking up the different stages, we picked them up over a few different visits to town.
Only one we had a small problem with was #12 - we think there's one of the names missing, we didn't go in either, though we did get a lot of funny looks from the clientele and the bouncers as we were counting & checking  [:D]
Email sent to owner with name of final pub.
TFTC
Blue Jay 59
#250
</li><li>2010-03-16T19:00:00Z : Found it by Toffee Man <br />Had found various stages of this one over several different nights.
Got the last few & worked out the final destination tonight with Blue Jay 59. This was our 250th cache.
E-mailed owner with answer.
TFTC
Toffee man
#250</li><li>2009-11-19T20:00:00Z : Found it by Kersti.com <br />Cold, windy night in Dublin with JME1979 - what shall we do? Go visiting pubs with a purpose of course. The final location was an obvious choice and one I know quite well, as opposed to the others which I mainly know through reputation... honest! Glad I wasn't doing this one in high heels!</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.349883" lon="-6.24935">
    <time>2004-12-07T08:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GCM7R6</name>
    <desc>Northside Pub Crawl by Bootle, Virtual Cache (2.5/1.5)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=50fc843c-0190-4328-b79b-2821dfe37414</url>
    <urlname>Northside Pub Crawl</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache Found</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Virtual Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="192177" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Northside Pub Crawl</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Bootle</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="96113">Bootle</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Virtual Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Virtual</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>2.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1.5</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Dublin</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">This Virtual Cache should take you to many of Dublin City Centre’s
finer Public Houses on the North Side of the River
Liffey!</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.geocachingireland.com"
target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img height="53" border="0" align="middle"
width="328" src="http://geocachingireland.com/logo4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
 This is a virtual cache with roughly 20 stages! However, all the
stages are close together, so the whole cache should only take you
about 60-120 minutes (or possibly much, much longer if you decide
to sample the quality of Guinness at each stage!). The terrain is
flat and you will be walking along concrete for the entire cache,
so no specialist clothing is needed. However it might be wise to
bring a calculator to figure out the answers at the end. You can
visit the pubs in any order, but the order I list them is probably
the quickest route to take. The starting point of the cache is
quite close to the Connolly train station. This cache can really
only be done on foot - leave the car in one of the city's many car
parks and head off for a stroll!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dublin has over 700 pubs, so choosing the best is always going to
be a difficult task. This particular group was chosen based on the
basis of many factors, such as history, significance, atmosphere,
etc. The idea, and much of the text in this cache page, came from
Pat Liddy's book, "Secret Dublin" (New Holland Press), which is a
must for anyone spending a significant amount of time in the city.
The route more or less follows that described in the book, but some
of the pubs are different. I'm sure I've left out many great pubs,
but there are also many great ones included. Along the route there
are several questions to be answered, all of which will help you
reach the final pub (Number 18!) on the walk. Email me the name of
that pub to complete the cache. All clues are on the buildings'
exteriors, so you will not need to go into any of them to get the
answers (although most are well worth a visit!)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Satellite coverage may come and go in the city centre, but can
usually be picked up from open locations, such as along the River
Liffey and at street intersections. I've left out the names of the
pubs to encourage people to use their GPS to find them, but if
satellite coverage can't be gained, the encrypted hints will tell
you which pub to look out for. The coordinates listed above for the
cache are those for the first pub.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to fellow cacher Tolmaion for a few updates on the state of
the pubs in 2009. It seems several of my original pub choices have
become victims of the recession and have closed or changed hands.
I've changed the route a little to reflect this.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
1) The pub-crawl starts in Dublin's recently developed financial
district, the International Financial Services Centre (IFSC). The
first pub is at N53 20.993 W 006 14.961 and was, in the 19th
century, the dockmasters office. On the shelves within you will
find many of the office trappings and samples of the examined
cargoes.&amp;nbsp; How many clocks are on the tower on the pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER A =&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
2) From here, take a stroll to Connolly Station and admire the new
LUAS terminus. The LUAS is Dublin's light rail system, completed in
2004, and is a welcome addition to the capital's transport system.
From here, walk past the central bus station, Busaras, to a pub at
N53 20.998 W006 15.157. This pub is currently being renovated, but
when in operation provides a live music and night club venue, as
well as being a nice place for an after work pint. How many letter
"a"s are there in the name of this pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER B= &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
3) From here it's only a short distance to N53 21.053 W6 15.257.
This pub and its hotel are popular spots with the guests of the
many hostels and B&amp;amp;Bs along Gardiner Street. How many
sculpyures / plaques showing violins / fiddles on them are at the
entrance to the hotel.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER C= &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
4) From here, move on N53 20.930 W006 15.464. The name of the pub
suggests that, at one stage in its history, the River Liffey might
have swept by its door. On the building beside the pub you will
find two dates written in Roman numerals. Find the date the
building was erected. Bearing in mind that M=1000, D=500, C=100,
X=10 and I=1, in what year was the building erected?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER D=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
5) Furthed down the street, at N53 20.918 W006 15.525, you will
find a fine traditional pub. What is the street number of this
pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER E=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
6) Across the road at N53 20.915 W006 15.514 you will find a hotel
with a quiet pub. The hotel is popular with tourists and worth a
stop if you need a drink at this early stage in the pub-crawl!
There are two street numbers listed for this hotel. What number do
you get if you add them together?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER F= &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
7) At N53 20.911 W006 15.529 you will find a large new pub that
used to be home to the O'Connell Street branch of Bank Of Ireland.
Today the building houses a comfortable pub which serves delicious
lunches. At the front entrance to the building, count the number of
harps on the insignia above the doorway to get answer G. &lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER G= &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
8) Make your way northwards up O'Connell Street until you reach a
small side street on your right. Pop into the pub at N53 20 940
W006 15.530 for a relaxing Guinness and enjoy the sights and sounds
of the many Dublin characters that will probably be propping up the
bar. What is the street number for this pub? &lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER H=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
9) At N53 20.837 W006 15.656 you will find the kind of pub that I
dislike the most. This modern pub will probably be recommended as a
great spot for tourists in many of the guidebooks to Dublin, but
will most likely have all sorts of terrible entertainment going on.
The last time I was there (several years ago, so it might have
improved!), there were a couple of awful balladeers reminiscing
about some distant past events, a DJ who spoke over the records
more often than not, and some ridiculous Riverdance - lite / Irish
dancing thing was being performed in a corner. Enter at your own
risk! What is the even street number of this pub? &lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER I=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
10) At N53 20.814 W006 15.808 there is a much more enjoyable pub.
It is themed in a Russian Revolution style, has pleasant décor and
usually has good music. Stop here for a quick shot of vodka. How
many letters are in the name of this pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER J=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
11) At N53 20.779 W006 15.949 you will find a fashionable hot-spot
located in a modern hotel. If you are trendy enough to get in you
might spot some up and coming figures from the entertainment
industry here. How many lamp-posts are in front (i.e. on the
river-side) of this hotel? &lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER K=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
12) Stroll along the quays to Capel Street, a grand old street now
home to many army surplus, D-I-Y and bargain shops. At N53 20.794
W006 16.077 you will find a pub with an, eh, "interesting" name,
and some "interesting" decor inside. I was not brave enough to go
inside! Count the number of times the name of the pub appears on
the pub's windows. Add 1 to your answer and divide this number by 6
and you will have answer L. &lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER L=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
13) At N53 20.767 W006 16.137 the James Joyce fans amongst you
might like to visit the Hotel where the Sirens chapter of Ulysses
is set. Unfortunately this pub is currently being slowly renovated.
Look for a blue sticker that claims this pub was once a Dublin
Tourism Member. What year is printed on this sticker? ANSWER M=
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
14) At N53 20.754 W006 16.168 you will find a pleasant modern pub.
How many letters in the two words that make up the name of this
pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER N=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
15) The name of the pub at N53 20.748 W006 16.342 reflects the fact
that you are now in the heart of the Irish judicial quarter, with
the impressive Four Courts building a stones throw away. The
building is one of several beautiful buildings in Dublin designed
by James Gandon in the latter eighteenth century. Drop into this
pub and eavesdrop on the days events in court. At what time does
the pub open for business (just the hour is needed here - the
minutes are unimportant)? &lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER O=&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
16) At N53 20.758 W006 16.545 you will find another pub popular
with the employees of the courts. Find the number of the postal
district that these pubs are in. For those unfamiliar with Dublin's
postal system, this is listed on a blue and white street sign
nearby.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER P= &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
17) All you have to do now is use your answers to find the
coordinates of the final pub! This can be done by adding,
subtracting, multiplying and dividing the answers you found along
the way. In the following problems, &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
+ means to add the values&lt;br /&gt;
- means subtract the values&lt;br /&gt;
x means multiply the values&lt;br /&gt;
/ means divide the first value by the second value&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For the problems with brackets, figure out the answers in brackets
first before completing the rest of the problem -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 1 = (E+K)xN&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 2 = (D/B) + [{(AxP) - G} x N]&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 3 = H&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 4 = {(M+I-G)/&amp;lt;(F-C)/I&amp;gt;} + (O/J) + L&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Insert your answers into the following coordinates to get the
coordinates of the last pub.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(N53 ANSWER 1 . ANSWER 2) (W006 ANSWER 3 . ANSWER 4)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once you've figured this out, head to the pub and note its name
before stopping off for a well earned few
pints!&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=84282177-54b1-4489-9d2a-b4e98432a813"
   rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;02M7R6 - Stage 02&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.998 W 006° 15.157&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;03M7R6 - Stage 03&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 21.053 W 006° 15.257&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;04M7R6 - Stage 04&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.930 W 006° 15.464&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;05M7R6 - Stage 05&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.918 W 006° 15.525&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;06M7R6 - Stage 06&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.915 W 006° 15.514&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;07M7R6 - Stage 07&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.911 W 006° 15.529&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;08M7R6 - Stage 08&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.940 W 006° 15.530&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;09M7R6 - Stage 09&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.837 W 006° 15.656&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;10M7R6 - Stage 10&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.814 W 006° 15.808&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;11M7R6 - Stage 11&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.779 W 006° 15.949&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;12M7R6 - Stage 12&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.794 W 006° 16.077&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;13M7R6 - Stage 13&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.767 W 006° 16.137&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;14M7R6 - Stage 14&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.754 W 006° 16.168&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;15M7R6 - Stage 15&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.748 W 006° 16.342&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;16M7R6 - Stage 16&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.758 W 006° 16.545&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>1) The Harbourmaster, IFSC; 2) The Isaac Butt, Store Street; 3) O Shea's Gardiner Street; 4) The Flowing Tide, Abbey Street; 5) Madigan’s, Abbey Street; 6) Wynn’s Hotel, Abbey Street; 7) Grand Central, O’Connell Street; 8) The Sackville Lounge, Sackville Place; 9) Knightsbridge, Bachelor’s Walk; 10) Pravda, Liffey Street; 11) The Morrison Hotel, Ormond Quay; 12) Pantibar, Capel Street; 13) The Ormond Hotel, Ormond Quay; 14) Sin E, Ormond Quay; 15) The Legal Eagle, Chancery Place; 16) The Quill, Church Street;</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="109607154">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-22T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1225625">Bus&amp;Betty</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">This is our second pub crawl cache and we enjoyed it as much as the first.

We finished finding the numbers and then went to a pub to have a beverage and do the math.  We plugged the coordinates into both our handheld GPS and our Nuvi, and much to our surprize, it was the pub that we had spent Thursday evening at.  

For clue 12, one needs to add 3 to the number of signs painted on the windows to get the correct answer.  

</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="108346925">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-08T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1536412">Horge der Seher</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">This one was a really great multi-virtual. However, I needed three days to tackle it. Three days, allthough I tried out only approx. 6 or 7 of the pubs. Unfortunately, I finished it at the final during midday, so the final pub was still closed. What a pitty, because not only bootle recommended it, but even my guide of Dublin. Well, I hope i will come back and visit this pub, as well. Thanks for the very nice trip through the northside!</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="102781605">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-03T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="281703">ruettenscheider</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">21:35
This one we found quickly during our Easter-holiday tour in Dublin.
Thank you for the quick logpermission.

TFTC

Sandra and Detlef from Essen, Germany</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="100078800">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-16T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2709154">Blue Jay 59</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Nice one. enjoyed picking up the different stages, we picked them up over a few different visits to town.
Only one we had a small problem with was #12 - we think there's one of the names missing, we didn't go in either, though we did get a lot of funny looks from the clientele and the bouncers as we were counting &amp; checking  [:D]
Email sent to owner with name of final pub.
TFTC
Blue Jay 59
#250
</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="100072052">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-16T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2826452">Toffee Man</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Had found various stages of this one over several different nights.
Got the last few &amp; worked out the final destination tonight with Blue Jay 59. This was our 250th cache.
E-mailed owner with answer.
TFTC
Toffee man
#250</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="90833436">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-11-19T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="320206">Kersti.com</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Cold, windy night in Dublin with JME1979 - what shall we do? Go visiting pubs with a purpose of course. The final location was an obvious choice and one I know quite well, as opposed to the others which I mainly know through reputation... honest! Glad I wasn't doing this one in high heels!</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
