<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>005529</id>
  <cache-id>GCJJVZ</cache-id>
  <type>Virtual Cache</type>
  <name>Southside Pub Crawl by Bootle, Virtual Cache (3.5/1)</name>
  <size>Virtual</size>
  <difficulty>3.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>1</terrain>
  <last-found>2008-09-27</last-found>
  <placed>2004-05-29</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Bootle</placedby>
  <found>Geocache Found</found>
  <lat>53.346917</lat>
  <lon>-6.25535</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFFXF</last-logs>
  <owner>Bootle</owner>
  <description>This Multi-Stage Virtual Cache should take you to many of Dublin
City Centre’s finer Public Houses on the South Side of the River
Liffey.</description>
  <long-description><p align="center"><a target="_blank"
href="http://www.geocachingireland.com"><img height="53" border="0"
align="middle" width="328"
src="http://geocachingireland.com/logo4.jpg" /></a></p>
This is a virtual cache with roughly 20 stages! However, all the
stages are close together, so the whole cache should only take you
about 60-120 minutes. (or possibly much, much longer if you decide
to sample the quality of Guinness at each stage!). The terrain is
flat and you will be walking along concrete for the entire cache,
so no specialist clothing is needed. However it might be wise to
bring a calculator to figure out the answers at the end. You can
visit the pubs in any order, but the order I list them is probably
the quickest route to take. The starting point of the cache is not
far from most bus routes that go in to the city centre. It’s also
very close to the Tara Street DART station. This cache can really
only be done on foot – leave the car in one of the city’s many car
parks and head off for a stroll!<br />
 <br />
Dublin has over 700 pubs, so choosing the best is always going to
be a difficult task. This particular group was chosen on the basis
of many factors, such as history, significance, atmosphere, etc.
The idea, and much of the text in this cache page, came from Pat
Liddy’s book, “Secret Dublin” (New Holland Press), which is a must
for anyone spending a significant amount of time in the city. The
route more or less follows that described in the book, but some of
the pubs are different. I’m sure I’ve left out many great pubs, but
there are also many great ones included. Along the route there are
several questions to be answered, all of which will help you reach
the final pub (Number 23!) on the walk. Email me the name of that
pub to complete the cache. All clues are on the buildings’
exteriors, so you will not need to go into any of them to get the
answers (although most are well worth a visit!)<br />
 <br />
Satellite coverage may come and go in the city centre, but can
usually be picked up from open locations, such as along the River
Liffey, in Trinity College, Dublin Castle courtyard, St. Stephen’s
Green and at street intersections. I’ve left out the names of the
pubs to encourage people to use their GPS to find them, but if
satellite coverage can’t be gained, the encrypted hints will tell
you which pub to look out for. Print out the map so you will know
where the streets mentioned in the clues lie. The coordinates
listed above for the cache are those for the first pub.<br />
 <br />
A big thanks to fellow geocacher Shakes for testing this route and
clearing up a few confusing issues with some of my original clues!
Thanks also to Tolmaion for a few updates on the state of the pubs
in 2009. It seems several of my original pub choices have become
victims of the recession and have closed or changed hands. I've
changed the route a little to reflect this.<br />
 <br />
1) The first pub is at N53 20.815 W6 15.321. This pub is a small
unpretentious establishment with low wooden beam ceilings, and an
original old world interior. At this pub, what is the third number
on the year in the sign relating to Bloomsday?<br />
ANSWER A =<br />
 <br />
2) From here, walk to N53 20.771 W6 15.420. Here you will find
another pleasant pub that makes a nice location for watching the
comings and goings across the road at the various bus-stops. You
may well encounter a driver having an after work pint or two. The
upstairs room in the pub was a popular meeting spot for the Polish
community in Ireland over the last few years and is generally quite
fun and noisy when the Polish football team happened to be on TV!
Here you must count the number of entrances to the pub and multiply
that number by 4.<br />
ANSWER B=<br />
 <br />
3) From here head over to N53 20.752 W6 15.582. This pub is well
worth popping into – as it’s a shrine to authentic Victorianism,
with old-fashioned carved mahogany shelf units, counter screens and
counters, which are complemented by a collection of brass vessels,
bric a brac and framed pictures. This pub is the first of eight
stops on the tour in the area known as Temple Bar. This
pedestrianised zone can be either a pleasant cultural experience
with left-field record and clothes shops, an art-house cinema and a
huge selection of restaurants, or a depressing collection of
streets full of loud stag and hen parties with many pubs providing
manufactured “authentic” Irish atmosphere. It’s best to visit the
area on a sunny Saturday afternoon when the place comes alive, with
a book market in Temple Bar Square and an excellent food market in
Meeting House Square… Outside the pub, look at the lamp which
states the pub’s name. How many glass sides are in this lamp?<br />
ANSWER C=<br />
 <br />
4) From here, move on to the junction of N53 20.742 W6 15.711,
where the next two pubs are located. One pub is famous for its live
traditional Irish Music (as the outer side wall proclaims in huge
letters!) and is named after a poet/musician/senator friend of
James Joyce. Both pubs are worth a visit for some authentic Dublin
pub atmosphere. Stand between the two pubs and look at the street
numbers of both pubs (both street numbers I'm looking for here are
odd numbers), and subtract the lower number from the higher number.
Add 2 to this figure to get Answer D<br />
ANSWER D=<br />
 <br />
5) At N53 20.725 W6 15.775 you will find a New York style pub and
restaurant, which is an important live music venue. Look at the top
of the building and count the number of letters in the surname
mentioned on the black sign “A ????????????? & Sons”<br />
ANSWER E=<br />
 <br />
6) Move on to N53 20.762 W6 15.803 to find a small traditional pub
which hosts famous music and comedy evenings. Here you are looking
for the first number in the telephone number of the company who
supplied the pub’s alarm.<br />
ANSWER F=<br />
 <br />
7) At N53 20.740 W6 15.844 you will find a pub which used to be a
nice quiet place but has now fallen victim to tourism and is a
shadow of its former self. It looks nice from the outside, though…
Here, find the second last number of the company that painted the
pub’s signs. Note there are 2 companies who have painted signs on
the pub. The one you are looking for is called Sign Design.<br />
ANSWER G=<br />
 <br />
8) At N53 20.734 W6 15.880 you will find a pub which is popular
with tourists due to the traditional Irish music and dancing which
take place there regularly. I find the atmosphere there a bit
manufactured, though. Outside, look for the name of the nightclub
attached to the pub. Take away 3 from the answer to get H.<br />
ANSWER H=<br />
 <br />
9) At N53 20.706 W6 16.008 you will find the Hotel, Nightclub and
pub owned by the rock group, U2. Look to the left of the building
and find the year that Dollard’s, next to the Hotel, was founded.
What’s the fourth number of the year?<br />
ANSWER I=<br />
 <br />
10) At N53 20.712 W6 16.021 you will find a pub which brews its own
beers and stouts. It is well worth a visit and you’ll probably find
some form of live music going on there. Find the number of wooden
bird-houses on the outside of the building.<br />
ANSWER J=<br />
 <br />
11) At N53 20.698 W6 16.074 you will find two pubs, both of which
are quite unappealing. The one to the north is slightly better as
it is often a last resort on a particularly late night out, when
every other pub seems to shut down. Find the number of the postal
district that these pubs are in. For those unfamiliar with Dublin’s
postal system, this is listed on a blue and white street sign
nearby.<br />
ANSWER K=<br />
 <br />
12) At N53 20.673 W6 16.041 you will find a much more attractive
pub, with welcoming atmosphere and a fine collection of comfortable
inviting couches that envelope anyone who sits in them. Stop here
for a rest -you’re halfway through the pubcrawl! At this stage
you’re probably tired from the walking, or too drunk to care,
depending on how fully you’ve experienced each pub! Outside the pub
look across the street towards an ancient sign for a hotel that
once existed. How many letters in the middle word of the Hotel
name?<br />
ANSWER L=<br />
 <br />
13) At N53 20.656 W6 15.984 you will find another traditional pub
with much wood decorating the exterior and interior of the pub.
It’s a nice place for a quiet pint. What is the street number of
the pub?<br />
ANSWER M=<br />
 <br />
14) At N53 20.630 W6 15.872 you will find a pub where the bright
exteriors are reflected by some of the more flamboyant characters
you might encounter inside. Across the road, in Dame Lane, you will
find an ancient neon sign advertising hair care. How many yellow
letters make up the last two words of the question beneath the neon
face?<br />
ANSWER N=<br />
 <br />
15) At N53 20.626 W6 15.821 lies my favourite pub in all Dublin.
It’s a traditional pub which looks like it has not been updated in
many, many years. Stop off here for a Guinness and a toasted
sandwich. Outside, find a sign for Pay and Display Parking. In the
sign, what number is represented by the two Xs “07:00 –
XX:00”<br />
ANSWER O=<br />
 <br />
16) At N53 20.585 W6 15.830 you will find a hotel which has a
hidden treasure of a bar upstairs. It’s a relaxing, unknown room
with many ancient looking books and comfortable chairs. Outside,
look for a sign telling you the year the Egon Ronay’s Guide gave
the pub an award. What’s the fourth number of the year?<br />
ANSWER P=<br />
 <br />
17) Next up is a pub which hosts various well renowned music and
comedy nights in its upstairs room. At N53 20.586 W6 15.716, this
pub is quite small, but retains a nice traditional feel. What is
the street number (an odd number) of the pub?<br />
ANSWER Q=<br />
 <br />
18) At N53 20.536 W6 15.753 you will find another traditional pub
that I like very much. It’s quite compact, so don’t try to visit it
on a weekend evening. Instead, drop in earlier in the day and
you’ll probably get a seat. Outside you’ll probably hear a busker
covering a Van Morrison song. I think the Irish Tourist Board
employs them to cover Mr. Morrison 24 hours a day. What street
number is this pub?<br />
ANSWER R=<br />
 <br />
19) At N53 20.444 W6 15.667 you will find a pub which is quiet and
comfortable (there’s a room upstairs if downstairs is full). It is
often frequented by actors from the various theatres around town,
so if you’re a theatre buff you might spot someone you recognize.
Look at the outside front wall. How many decorative grey vents
(shaped a little like a flower) are there along the bottom of the
front of the pub?<br />
ANSWER S=<br />
 <br />
20) At N53 20.465 W6 15.568 you will find a pub which was converted
from a house and internally still maintains the layout and many of
the features of a house. What are the first two numbers of the year
that this pub was established?<br />
ANSWER T=<br />
 <br />
21) N53 20.512 W6 15.559 is the site of a pub immortalized in James
Joyce’s “Ulysses”. In the book, Leopold Bloom stops in for lunch at
the ‘Moral Pub” as he calls it. To get the answer for this pub, add
1 to the street number of the pub<br />
ANSWER U=<br />
 <br />
22) This is the penultimate pub! It’s at N53 20.427 W6 15.513, and
was converted in 1994 from some dull insurance offices into a large
café-style bar with excellent interiors and expensive posh coffees.
Have a quick look inside, but move on to the final destination for
a well earned Pint of Plain! How many times is the number 41
painted on the front of the sign of the bookseller to the right of
the pub?<br />
ANSWER V=<br />
 <br />
23) All you have to do now is use your answers to find the
coordinates of the final pub! This can be done by adding,
subtracting, multiplying and dividing the answers you found along
the way. In the following problems,<br />
+ means to add the values<br />
- means subtract the values<br />
x means multiply the values<br />
/ means divide the first value by the second value<br />
 <br />
For the problems with brackets, figure out the answers in brackets
first before completing the rest of the problem -<br />
 <br />
ANSWER 1 = B+C+E+G<br />
ANSWER 2 = {([K*K*K]+H)xD} - (Q+U)<br />
ANSWER 3 = M/(S+J) + A<br />
ANSWER 4 = (FxIxLxV) - (N+O+P+R+T)<br />
 <br />
Insert your answers into the following coordinates to get the
coordinates of the last pub.<br />
 <br />
(N53 ANSWER 1 . ANSWER 2) (W006 ANSWER 3 . ANSWER 4)<br />
 <br />
Once you’ve figured this out, head to this pub and note its name
before stopping off for a well earned few pints, providing you can
find a seat! NOTE: - you are definitely looking for a pub here, not
a cafe.<br /></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>02JJVZ - Pub # 02<br />N 53° 20.771 W 006° 15.420<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 02<br />03JJVZ - Pub # 03<br />N 53° 20.752 W 006° 15.582<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 03<br />04JJVZ - Pub # 04<br />N 53° 20.742 W 006° 15.711<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 04<br />05JJVZ - Pub # 05<br />N 53° 20.725 W 006° 15.775<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 05<br />06JJVZ - Pub # 06<br />N 53° 20.762 W 006° 15.803<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 06<br />07JJVZ - Pub # 07<br />N 53° 20.740 W 006° 15.844<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 07<br />08JJVZ - Pub # 08<br />N 53° 20.734 W 006° 15.880<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 08<br />09JJVZ - Pub # 09<br />N 53° 20.706 W 006° 16.008<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 09<br />10JJVZ - Pub # 10<br />N 53° 20.712 W 006° 16.021<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 10<br />11JJVZ - Pub # 11<br />N 53° 20.698 W 006° 16.074<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 11<br />12JJVZ - Pub # 12<br />N 53° 20.673 W 006° 16.041<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 12<br />13JJVZ - Pub # 13<br />N 53° 20.656 W 006° 15.984<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 13<br />14JJVZ - Pub # 14<br />N 53° 20.630 W 006° 15.872<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 14<br />15JJVZ - Pub # 15<br />N 53° 20.626 W 006° 15.821<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 15<br />16JJVZ - Pub # 16<br />N 53° 20.585 W 006° 15.830<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 16<br />17JJVZ - Pub  # 17<br />N 53° 20.586 W 006° 15.716<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 17<br />18JJVZ - Pub # 18<br />N 53° 20.536 W 006° 15.753<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 18<br />19JJVZ - Pub # 19<br />N 53° 20.444 W 006° 15.667<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 19<br />20JJVZ - Pub # 20<br />N 53° 20.465 W 006° 15.568<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 20<br />21JJVZ - Pub # 21<br />N 53° 20.512 W 006° 15.559<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 21<br />22JJVZ - Pub # 22<br />N 53° 20.427 W 006° 15.513<br />Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 22<br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:02JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:03JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:04JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:05JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:06JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:07JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:08JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:09JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:10JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:11JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:12JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:13JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:14JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:15JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:16JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:17JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:18JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:19JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:20JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:21JJVZ|waypoints:cache-id:22JJVZ</links>
  <encoded-hints>1) Mulligan’s, Poolbeg Street; 2) Chaplins, Hawkins Street; 3) The Palace Bar, Fleet Street; 4) Oliver St. John Gogarty; The Auld Dubliner, Anglesea Street; 5) Eamon Doran’s, Crown Alley; 6) Ha’Penny Bridge Inn, Wellington Quay; 7) The Temple Bar, Temple Bar; 8) Fitzsimon’s, Essex Street East; 9) The Clarence, Essex Street East; 10) The Porterhouse, Essex Street East; 11) The Czech Inn, Essex Gate; 12) The Front Lounge, Parliament Street; 13) Brogan’s, Dame Street; 14) The George, George’s Street; 15) The Stag’s Head, Dame Lane; 16) The Central Hotel, Exchequer Street; 17) The International, Exchequer Street; 18) Grogan’s, William Street South; 19) Neary’s. Chatham Street; 20) Kehoe’s, South Anne Street; 21) Davy Byrne’s, Duke Street; 22) Café En Seine, Dawson Street;</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=84282177-54b1-4489-9d2a-b4e98432a813</url>
  <url-name>Southside Pub Crawl</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-06-05T19:00:00Z : Found it by eve1987 <br />it was a very hard work and we needed 2 evenings... but it was great and we had a lot of fun!!

A very good ideal for a virtual cache! 

Kind regards from Austria, eve</li><li>2010-06-04T19:00:00Z : Found it by GudrunXY <br />It took us three days and two nights to finish all of it.
TFTC, GudrunXY</li><li>2010-05-19T19:00:00Z : Found it by Bus&Betty <br />Great way to get some good exercise after long flights from Minneapolis.  

As it was early in the day, we only stopped for two pints, but they were very good.

One of our favorite caches ever.  Next one...Northside Pub Crawl.

TFTC
B&B</li><li>2010-05-15T19:00:00Z : Found it by Alastair74 <br />Found with Wildfowler while spending the day in Dublin for the WWFM. TFTC</li><li>2010-05-13T19:00:00Z : Didn't find it by lamm4 <br />It was a nice trip through a nice city. After more then 30 years a lot of things has changed.We didn't find the final [:(] but it was a very good guide for us. TFTC</li><li>2008-09-27T19:00:00Z : Found it by Kersti.com <br />I've started this one a few times but tonight was out with jme1979 and the mission was to complete it! Now to go back and drink at them all...</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.346917" lon="-6.25535">
    <time>2004-05-29T07:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GCJJVZ</name>
    <desc>Southside Pub Crawl by Bootle, Virtual Cache (3.5/1)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=84282177-54b1-4489-9d2a-b4e98432a813</url>
    <urlname>Southside Pub Crawl</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache Found</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Virtual Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="143252" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Southside Pub Crawl</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Bootle</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="96113">Bootle</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Virtual Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Virtual</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>3.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Leinster</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">This Multi-Stage Virtual Cache should take you to many of Dublin
City Centre’s finer Public Houses on the South Side of the River
Liffey.</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank"
href="http://www.geocachingireland.com"&gt;&lt;img height="53" border="0"
align="middle" width="328"
src="http://geocachingireland.com/logo4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
This is a virtual cache with roughly 20 stages! However, all the
stages are close together, so the whole cache should only take you
about 60-120 minutes. (or possibly much, much longer if you decide
to sample the quality of Guinness at each stage!). The terrain is
flat and you will be walking along concrete for the entire cache,
so no specialist clothing is needed. However it might be wise to
bring a calculator to figure out the answers at the end. You can
visit the pubs in any order, but the order I list them is probably
the quickest route to take. The starting point of the cache is not
far from most bus routes that go in to the city centre. It’s also
very close to the Tara Street DART station. This cache can really
only be done on foot – leave the car in one of the city’s many car
parks and head off for a stroll!&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Dublin has over 700 pubs, so choosing the best is always going to
be a difficult task. This particular group was chosen on the basis
of many factors, such as history, significance, atmosphere, etc.
The idea, and much of the text in this cache page, came from Pat
Liddy’s book, “Secret Dublin” (New Holland Press), which is a must
for anyone spending a significant amount of time in the city. The
route more or less follows that described in the book, but some of
the pubs are different. I’m sure I’ve left out many great pubs, but
there are also many great ones included. Along the route there are
several questions to be answered, all of which will help you reach
the final pub (Number 23!) on the walk. Email me the name of that
pub to complete the cache. All clues are on the buildings’
exteriors, so you will not need to go into any of them to get the
answers (although most are well worth a visit!)&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Satellite coverage may come and go in the city centre, but can
usually be picked up from open locations, such as along the River
Liffey, in Trinity College, Dublin Castle courtyard, St. Stephen’s
Green and at street intersections. I’ve left out the names of the
pubs to encourage people to use their GPS to find them, but if
satellite coverage can’t be gained, the encrypted hints will tell
you which pub to look out for. Print out the map so you will know
where the streets mentioned in the clues lie. The coordinates
listed above for the cache are those for the first pub.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
A big thanks to fellow geocacher Shakes for testing this route and
clearing up a few confusing issues with some of my original clues!
Thanks also to Tolmaion for a few updates on the state of the pubs
in 2009. It seems several of my original pub choices have become
victims of the recession and have closed or changed hands. I've
changed the route a little to reflect this.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
1) The first pub is at N53 20.815 W6 15.321. This pub is a small
unpretentious establishment with low wooden beam ceilings, and an
original old world interior. At this pub, what is the third number
on the year in the sign relating to Bloomsday?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER A =&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
2) From here, walk to N53 20.771 W6 15.420. Here you will find
another pleasant pub that makes a nice location for watching the
comings and goings across the road at the various bus-stops. You
may well encounter a driver having an after work pint or two. The
upstairs room in the pub was a popular meeting spot for the Polish
community in Ireland over the last few years and is generally quite
fun and noisy when the Polish football team happened to be on TV!
Here you must count the number of entrances to the pub and multiply
that number by 4.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER B=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
3) From here head over to N53 20.752 W6 15.582. This pub is well
worth popping into – as it’s a shrine to authentic Victorianism,
with old-fashioned carved mahogany shelf units, counter screens and
counters, which are complemented by a collection of brass vessels,
bric a brac and framed pictures. This pub is the first of eight
stops on the tour in the area known as Temple Bar. This
pedestrianised zone can be either a pleasant cultural experience
with left-field record and clothes shops, an art-house cinema and a
huge selection of restaurants, or a depressing collection of
streets full of loud stag and hen parties with many pubs providing
manufactured “authentic” Irish atmosphere. It’s best to visit the
area on a sunny Saturday afternoon when the place comes alive, with
a book market in Temple Bar Square and an excellent food market in
Meeting House Square… Outside the pub, look at the lamp which
states the pub’s name. How many glass sides are in this lamp?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER C=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
4) From here, move on to the junction of N53 20.742 W6 15.711,
where the next two pubs are located. One pub is famous for its live
traditional Irish Music (as the outer side wall proclaims in huge
letters!) and is named after a poet/musician/senator friend of
James Joyce. Both pubs are worth a visit for some authentic Dublin
pub atmosphere. Stand between the two pubs and look at the street
numbers of both pubs (both street numbers I'm looking for here are
odd numbers), and subtract the lower number from the higher number.
Add 2 to this figure to get Answer D&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER D=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
5) At N53 20.725 W6 15.775 you will find a New York style pub and
restaurant, which is an important live music venue. Look at the top
of the building and count the number of letters in the surname
mentioned on the black sign “A ????????????? &amp;amp; Sons”&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER E=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
6) Move on to N53 20.762 W6 15.803 to find a small traditional pub
which hosts famous music and comedy evenings. Here you are looking
for the first number in the telephone number of the company who
supplied the pub’s alarm.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER F=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
7) At N53 20.740 W6 15.844 you will find a pub which used to be a
nice quiet place but has now fallen victim to tourism and is a
shadow of its former self. It looks nice from the outside, though…
Here, find the second last number of the company that painted the
pub’s signs. Note there are 2 companies who have painted signs on
the pub. The one you are looking for is called Sign Design.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER G=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
8) At N53 20.734 W6 15.880 you will find a pub which is popular
with tourists due to the traditional Irish music and dancing which
take place there regularly. I find the atmosphere there a bit
manufactured, though. Outside, look for the name of the nightclub
attached to the pub. Take away 3 from the answer to get H.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER H=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
9) At N53 20.706 W6 16.008 you will find the Hotel, Nightclub and
pub owned by the rock group, U2. Look to the left of the building
and find the year that Dollard’s, next to the Hotel, was founded.
What’s the fourth number of the year?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER I=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
10) At N53 20.712 W6 16.021 you will find a pub which brews its own
beers and stouts. It is well worth a visit and you’ll probably find
some form of live music going on there. Find the number of wooden
bird-houses on the outside of the building.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER J=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
11) At N53 20.698 W6 16.074 you will find two pubs, both of which
are quite unappealing. The one to the north is slightly better as
it is often a last resort on a particularly late night out, when
every other pub seems to shut down. Find the number of the postal
district that these pubs are in. For those unfamiliar with Dublin’s
postal system, this is listed on a blue and white street sign
nearby.&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER K=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
12) At N53 20.673 W6 16.041 you will find a much more attractive
pub, with welcoming atmosphere and a fine collection of comfortable
inviting couches that envelope anyone who sits in them. Stop here
for a rest -you’re halfway through the pubcrawl! At this stage
you’re probably tired from the walking, or too drunk to care,
depending on how fully you’ve experienced each pub! Outside the pub
look across the street towards an ancient sign for a hotel that
once existed. How many letters in the middle word of the Hotel
name?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER L=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
13) At N53 20.656 W6 15.984 you will find another traditional pub
with much wood decorating the exterior and interior of the pub.
It’s a nice place for a quiet pint. What is the street number of
the pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER M=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
14) At N53 20.630 W6 15.872 you will find a pub where the bright
exteriors are reflected by some of the more flamboyant characters
you might encounter inside. Across the road, in Dame Lane, you will
find an ancient neon sign advertising hair care. How many yellow
letters make up the last two words of the question beneath the neon
face?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER N=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
15) At N53 20.626 W6 15.821 lies my favourite pub in all Dublin.
It’s a traditional pub which looks like it has not been updated in
many, many years. Stop off here for a Guinness and a toasted
sandwich. Outside, find a sign for Pay and Display Parking. In the
sign, what number is represented by the two Xs “07:00 –
XX:00”&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER O=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
16) At N53 20.585 W6 15.830 you will find a hotel which has a
hidden treasure of a bar upstairs. It’s a relaxing, unknown room
with many ancient looking books and comfortable chairs. Outside,
look for a sign telling you the year the Egon Ronay’s Guide gave
the pub an award. What’s the fourth number of the year?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER P=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
17) Next up is a pub which hosts various well renowned music and
comedy nights in its upstairs room. At N53 20.586 W6 15.716, this
pub is quite small, but retains a nice traditional feel. What is
the street number (an odd number) of the pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER Q=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
18) At N53 20.536 W6 15.753 you will find another traditional pub
that I like very much. It’s quite compact, so don’t try to visit it
on a weekend evening. Instead, drop in earlier in the day and
you’ll probably get a seat. Outside you’ll probably hear a busker
covering a Van Morrison song. I think the Irish Tourist Board
employs them to cover Mr. Morrison 24 hours a day. What street
number is this pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER R=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
19) At N53 20.444 W6 15.667 you will find a pub which is quiet and
comfortable (there’s a room upstairs if downstairs is full). It is
often frequented by actors from the various theatres around town,
so if you’re a theatre buff you might spot someone you recognize.
Look at the outside front wall. How many decorative grey vents
(shaped a little like a flower) are there along the bottom of the
front of the pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER S=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
20) At N53 20.465 W6 15.568 you will find a pub which was converted
from a house and internally still maintains the layout and many of
the features of a house. What are the first two numbers of the year
that this pub was established?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER T=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
21) N53 20.512 W6 15.559 is the site of a pub immortalized in James
Joyce’s “Ulysses”. In the book, Leopold Bloom stops in for lunch at
the ‘Moral Pub” as he calls it. To get the answer for this pub, add
1 to the street number of the pub&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER U=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
22) This is the penultimate pub! It’s at N53 20.427 W6 15.513, and
was converted in 1994 from some dull insurance offices into a large
café-style bar with excellent interiors and expensive posh coffees.
Have a quick look inside, but move on to the final destination for
a well earned Pint of Plain! How many times is the number 41
painted on the front of the sign of the bookseller to the right of
the pub?&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER V=&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
23) All you have to do now is use your answers to find the
coordinates of the final pub! This can be done by adding,
subtracting, multiplying and dividing the answers you found along
the way. In the following problems,&lt;br /&gt;
+ means to add the values&lt;br /&gt;
- means subtract the values&lt;br /&gt;
x means multiply the values&lt;br /&gt;
/ means divide the first value by the second value&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
For the problems with brackets, figure out the answers in brackets
first before completing the rest of the problem -&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 1 = B+C+E+G&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 2 = {([K*K*K]+H)xD} - (Q+U)&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 3 = M/(S+J) + A&lt;br /&gt;
ANSWER 4 = (FxIxLxV) - (N+O+P+R+T)&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Insert your answers into the following coordinates to get the
coordinates of the last pub.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
(N53 ANSWER 1 . ANSWER 2) (W006 ANSWER 3 . ANSWER 4)&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Once you’ve figured this out, head to this pub and note its name
before stopping off for a well earned few pints, providing you can
find a seat! NOTE: - you are definitely looking for a pub here, not
a cafe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;02JJVZ - Pub # 02&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.771 W 006° 15.420&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 02&lt;br /&gt;03JJVZ - Pub # 03&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.752 W 006° 15.582&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 03&lt;br /&gt;04JJVZ - Pub # 04&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.742 W 006° 15.711&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 04&lt;br /&gt;05JJVZ - Pub # 05&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.725 W 006° 15.775&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 05&lt;br /&gt;06JJVZ - Pub # 06&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.762 W 006° 15.803&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 06&lt;br /&gt;07JJVZ - Pub # 07&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.740 W 006° 15.844&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 07&lt;br /&gt;08JJVZ - Pub # 08&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.734 W 006° 15.880&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 08&lt;br /&gt;09JJVZ - Pub # 09&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.706 W 006° 16.008&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 09&lt;br /&gt;10JJVZ - Pub # 10&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.712 W 006° 16.021&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 10&lt;br /&gt;11JJVZ - Pub # 11&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.698 W 006° 16.074&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 11&lt;br /&gt;12JJVZ - Pub # 12&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.673 W 006° 16.041&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 12&lt;br /&gt;13JJVZ - Pub # 13&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.656 W 006° 15.984&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 13&lt;br /&gt;14JJVZ - Pub # 14&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.630 W 006° 15.872&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 14&lt;br /&gt;15JJVZ - Pub # 15&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.626 W 006° 15.821&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 15&lt;br /&gt;16JJVZ - Pub # 16&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.585 W 006° 15.830&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 16&lt;br /&gt;17JJVZ - Pub  # 17&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.586 W 006° 15.716&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 17&lt;br /&gt;18JJVZ - Pub # 18&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.536 W 006° 15.753&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 18&lt;br /&gt;19JJVZ - Pub # 19&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.444 W 006° 15.667&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 19&lt;br /&gt;20JJVZ - Pub # 20&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.465 W 006° 15.568&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 20&lt;br /&gt;21JJVZ - Pub # 21&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.512 W 006° 15.559&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 21&lt;br /&gt;22JJVZ - Pub # 22&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.427 W 006° 15.513&lt;br /&gt;Southside Pub Crawl Pub # 22&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>1) Mulligan’s, Poolbeg Street; 2) Chaplins, Hawkins Street; 3) The Palace Bar, Fleet Street; 4) Oliver St. John Gogarty; The Auld Dubliner, Anglesea Street; 5) Eamon Doran’s, Crown Alley; 6) Ha’Penny Bridge Inn, Wellington Quay; 7) The Temple Bar, Temple Bar; 8) Fitzsimon’s, Essex Street East; 9) The Clarence, Essex Street East; 10) The Porterhouse, Essex Street East; 11) The Czech Inn, Essex Gate; 12) The Front Lounge, Parliament Street; 13) Brogan’s, Dame Street; 14) The George, George’s Street; 15) The Stag’s Head, Dame Lane; 16) The Central Hotel, Exchequer Street; 17) The International, Exchequer Street; 18) Grogan’s, William Street South; 19) Neary’s. Chatham Street; 20) Kehoe’s, South Anne Street; 21) Davy Byrne’s, Duke Street; 22) Café En Seine, Dawson Street;</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="112541824">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-05T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1617792">eve1987</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">it was a very hard work and we needed 2 evenings... but it was great and we had a lot of fun!!

A very good ideal for a virtual cache! 

Kind regards from Austria, eve</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="111863530">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-04T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2694097">GudrunXY</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">It took us three days and two nights to finish all of it.
TFTC, GudrunXY</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="109178754">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-19T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1225625">Bus&amp;Betty</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Great way to get some good exercise after long flights from Minneapolis.  

As it was early in the day, we only stopped for two pints, but they were very good.

One of our favorite caches ever.  Next one...Northside Pub Crawl.

TFTC
B&amp;B</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="109084232">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-15T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2453409">Alastair74</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found with Wildfowler while spending the day in Dublin for the WWFM. TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="109514608">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-13T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Didn't find it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1932037">lamm4</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">It was a nice trip through a nice city. After more then 30 years a lot of things has changed.We didn't find the final [:(] but it was a very good guide for us. TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="53973713">
          <groundspeak:date>2008-09-27T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="320206">Kersti.com</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">I've started this one a few times but tonight was out with jme1979 and the mission was to complete it! Now to go back and drink at them all...</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
