<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>006274</id>
  <cache-id>GC1J3MC</cache-id>
  <type>Earthcache</type>
  <name>North Bull Island by AbbeyAckbar, Earthcache (1.5/1.5)</name>
  <size>Not chosen</size>
  <difficulty>1.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>1.5</terrain>
  <last-found>2010-05-15</last-found>
  <placed>2010-02-07</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>AbbeyAckbar</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.3725</lat>
  <lon>-6.156667</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFFF</last-logs>
  <owner>AbbeyAckbar</owner>
  <description><center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/4f8d51a6-f70a-494c-a1c2-d5dab2dbed11.jpg" /></center>
<p><b>Introduction</b></p>
<p>The North Bull Island developed from a sandbank and is a
relatively recent depositional feature to the Dublin coastline. The
island is less than 200 years old. The name is derived from the
locality, Clontarf, which in Gaelic is Cluain Tairbh meaning the
Bull's Meadow.</p></description>
  <long-description><p>What is fascinating about the island is how it came to exist,
and how it has developed into the island you see today. It is a
site of both national and international scientific interest.</p>
<p>A sandspit is a form of coastal deposition that occurs as a
result of sediment being deposited that may have come from rivers,
and/or cliff erosion. Human impact may increase the supply of
material available which is what happened with North Bull Island.
It formed due to sedimentation accumulation resulting from the
construction of a harbour wall for Dublin port.</p>
<p><b>The Construction of the Harbour Walls & beginning of
North Bull Island</b></p>
<p>Dublin Bay had a problem with silting for a long time at the
mouth of the River Liffey. After years of dredging to keep a clear
channel, attempts began in 1715 to build a wall which was to later
become the Great South Wall, completed in 1830. The first barrier
that was built was destroyed by a storm, so in 1761 work began on a
stone pier starting from the Poolbeg Lighthouse. In 1768, back at
shore, the construction of a massive granite wall began and was
completed in 1795.</p>
<p>During this time, the building of a North Bull Wall was proposed
as the south wall hadn&rsquo;t solved the silting problem. Captain
William Bligh, of &lsquo;Mutiny on the Bounty&rsquo; fame, surveyed
Dublin Bay for the Ballast Board in 1801, highlighting the
potential of the North Bull sandbank, a small dry part of the North
Bull which was directly adjacent to the large 18th century mansion
known as Baymount (Now known as Manresa House). A wooden bridge was
erected in 1819 to enable the construction of a stone wall. The
Bull Wall (which is 1km long) was completed in 1821.</p>
<p>The section of the Bull Wall from the statue &lsquo;Realt na
Mara&rsquo; (Our Lady, Queen of the Sea), to the lighthouse is
known as the half tide wall. This is covered at high tide. The
purpose of the half tide wall and the wooden bridge section of the
bull wall was to act as safety valves to prevent damage to the wall
from the pressure of the full tide. Gradually, the channel into the
River Liffey deepened. The water level increased from 6ft to 16ft
at low tide. Wave and current action deposited and reworked the
sediments on the seabed. The sand that was dislodged got carried
out into the bay, picked up by currents and then deposited on the
North Bull Bank behind the north wall. This was the beginning of
North Bull Island.</p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/03cb9980-793d-4522-821e-67b871ce54ea.jpg" /></center>
<p><b>The development of the island</b></p>
<p>The image below is a rough map of the area resulting from
sediment deposition.</p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c92f7b5a-f522-4bc6-be3c-40cfc8ff8c67.jpg" /></center>
<p>The island reached its current length in 1902. It is approx.
5km. long and 1km wide at its widest point. The area above high
tide is 300 hectares approx. and the Island continues to grow
seaward.</p>
<p>A sandspit is a type of shoal. Shoals are typically long and
narrow and develop where a stream or ocean current promotes
deposition of granular material.</p>
<p>The end of a spit attached to land is called the proximal end,
and the end jutting out into water is called the distal end. One
end is more protected than the other, and mud flats/salt marshes
may develop in sheltered areas behind them as is the case with
North Bull Island. Spits develop hooked ends due to wave refraction
which occurs at the end of the spit which carries some material
into more sheltered areas.</p>
<p>Three basic landscapes types have developed over the past 150yrs
on the island :</p>
<p><b>1.</b> The elevated dune area<br />
<b>2.</b> The salt marsh<br />
<b>3.</b> The mud/sand flats of the lagoon.</p>
<p><b>1.1 The Sand Dunes</b><br />
A well-developed and dynamic dune system stretches along the
seaward side of the island. Various types of dunes occur, from
fixed dune grassland to pioneer communities on foredunes. The dune
system and beach is composed of sea/tide borne and wind blown sand
particles. Sand is a naturally occurring granular material composed
of finely divided rock and mineral particles. As the term is used
by geologists, sand particles range in diameter from 0.0625 to 2mm.
An individual particle in this range size is termed a sand grain.
In dune formation, marram grass plays a vital role in binding the
sand together with its roots and underground stems which can grow
upto 5 meters long. They send out horizontal root stems called
&lsquo;rhizomes&rsquo; under the surface to push up new growth
short distances away.These roots stabilize the dune and above
ground plant structures intercept and trap more sand. Dunes can
form without plants but they will be smaller than the potential
size they could reach if plants were able to establish and grow.
The dune closest to the ocean is the primary dune, or foredune,
followed by what are called secondary dunes or back dunes.</p>
<p><b>2.1 The Salt & Freshwater Marshes</b><br />
The salt marsh is in the inter-tidal zone. It is located between
the island and the mainland. It is a large linear saltmarsh complex
backed by mudflats all of which are covered at high tide. The edge
of the marsh is marked by an eroding edge which varies from 20 cm
to 60 cm high. The substrate (sediment that rests at the bottom) of
the salt marsh and intertidal mudflats is composed mainly of very
fine silt particles, probably originating from materials discharged
into Dublin Bay by the rivers Liffey, Tolka and Dodder. There are
coarse gravels and stones in the Kilbarrack/Sutton area, which are
probably remnants of glacial till. (Glacial till is a type of
glacial deposit : material directly deposited from glacial ice.
Till includes a mixture of undifferentiated material ranging from
clay size to boulders.)</p>
<p>Each landscape type has its own distinctive vegetation. An
interesting mini eco-system is located in a large dune slack known
as the Alder Marsh (because of the presence of Alder trees) at the
north end of the island enclosed within the dunes at water level,
and features its own distinctive plant and insect life.</p>
<p><b>3.1 The Mudflats</b><br />
The mudflats are in the inter-tidal zone beside the salt marsh.
Mudflats may be viewed geologically as exposed layers of bay mud,
resulting from deposition of estuarine silts, clays and marine
animal detritus. Most of the sediment within a mudflat is within
the intertidal zone, and so the flat is submerged and exposed 2
times a day approx.<br />
The island shelters two intertidal lagoons which are divided by a
solid causeway. The sediments of the lagoons are mainly sands with
a small and varying mixture of silt and clay.</p>
<p>
___________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>The seabed at the mouth of Dublin Bay infront of North Bull
Island shows the dynamic sedimentary processes operating in the
Irish Sea. The large sandbank located in the centre of the bay
(known as Burford Bank) is a notable seabed feature. From a
geological perspective, the sand waves at the northern and southern
ends of the bank illustrate the strong tidal currents moving in the
area which created and maintain this stunning seabed feature. It
has been suggested that there is a possibility that within the next
50yrs, continued deposition on bull island may lead to it merging
with the mainland at Red Rock in Sutton, forming a lagoon and
changing the make-up of the area. However, the risk of this is
considered very small due to the strength of currents and depth of
water in Sutton Channel.</p>
<p>Several of the city's small rivers and streams enter the bay
here, notably the Naniken River, the River Tolka, the Santry River,
Fox Stream, Blackbanks Stream and Daunagh Water.</p>
<p>The island is currently connected to the mainland by means of
the old wooden bridge and a causeway which was built in 1964 to
facilitate the volume of people visiting the island. The growing
number of visitors was also helped by the introduction of the horse
tram services to Clontarf in 1873, and further by the tram line to
Howth, which opened in 1900, and stopped in the Clontarf /
Dollymount area.</p>
<p>The island lies roughly parallel to the shore off Clontarf
(including Dollymount), Raheny & Kilbarrack, and faces Sutton.
Between the causeway access point to the island and half way up to
the North Wall lies St.Anne's park (Dublin's 2nd largest park)
North Bull Island is run from the depot in this park. Dublin City
Council care and maintain the island through the parks and
landscape services division. The proximity of the park to the
island means that there is a very large area of the city suburb for
an abundance of plantlife and wildlife to thrive in and enjoy.</p>
<p><b>Flora and Fauna of the island</b></p>
<p>As a result of this landscape formation from the sea, an
abundance of wildlife and plantlife now exists and thrives on the
island. The island was declared a bird sanctuary in 1931 and is
protected under the Irish Wildlife Act. The island was declared a
Biosphere reserve by UNESCO (United Nations Educational Scientific
and cultural organization) in 1981. Biosphere reserves are sites
which demonstrate approaches to conservation and sustainable
development. The island was designated a National Nature Reserve in
1988 and a wetland of international importance under the Ramsar
Convention.</p>
<p>(<b>Note :February 2nd every year is &lsquo;World Wetlands
Day.</b> It marks the date of the signing of the Convention on
Wetlands on 2 February 1971, in the Iranian city of Ramsar on the
shores of the Caspian Sea. It aims to raise public awareness of
wetland values and benefits)</p>
<br />
<center><b><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/b0ab8faa-112c-4cfa-a8fa-88415bd965e1.jpg" /></b></center>
<p><b>Interpretive Centre</b></p>
<p>There is an interpretive centre located at the end of the
causeway (see additional waypoint co-ords) which assists in the
understanding of the unique flora and fauna and specialised
habitats of the island. It was constructed in 1986 through Dublin
City Council Parks and Landscape Services who also run the
facility. The centre serves to inform and educate the thousands of
schoolchildren and members of the public who visit every year. The
centre has a lecture theatre, a natural history museum, and an
aquarium. You can view the exhibits and use the telescope to watch
the birds outside. And it's all <b>for FREE!</b></p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c6ebaacc-bd42-4606-9620-910627116294.jpg" /></center>
<br />
<p><b>Getting to North Bull Island</b></p>
<p>From the city centre, you can get the number 130 bus from Lower
Abbey Street to the Bull Wall.</p>
<p><b>Parking</b></p>
<p>Parking is available anywere on either side of the causeway
(waypoint provided). All the information you need to get for
questions 1 to 3 are within walking distance of the parking area.
For questions 4 and 5, It is advisable to drive/cycle to another
parking location provided near the north bull wall (waypoint
provided)</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>To log your visit</b></p>
<p style="color:darkgreen">To geocaching@thyme-it.ie please email
us the answers to at least <b>3</b> of the following questions
:</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>1.</b>Go to N53 22.344, W006
09.471.<br />
Depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Based on your direct observation, name and describe
<b>TWO</b> landscapes that lie before you at this location.</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>2.</b>Go to N53 22.169, W06
08.613.<br />
Do you see primary dunes, secondary dunes, or both? Note the water
roughness and wave action you can see at this location for question
4.</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>3.</b>At N53 22.448, W006
09.840.<br />
Name the three plants listed as growing in the alder marsh section
of the island as stated on the information board about North Bull
Island located at the causeway access point to the island.</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>4.</b>Go to N53 21.624, W006
10.919<br />
Depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Describe the difference in the water roughness and wave
action of the water between this location and the location of the
dunes in question 2.</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>5.</b>At the same co-ords as above,
depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Tell me is the tide coming in or going out, and how did you
arrive at that conclusion? note: If the tide is far out when you
visit this location, describe what you see before you.</p>
<p>The following is optional and <b>NOT</b> a requirement to log
your visit - photos from your visit are very welcome with your log.
Feel free to upload any wildlife/plant life/landscape photos you
take during your visit to the earthcache site.</p>
<center>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/95dce3d8-8691-4752-801c-0f42d3a45770.jpg" />
<font size="4"><b>HAPPY EARTHCACHING!</b></font> <img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/95dce3d8-8691-4752-801c-0f42d3a45770.jpg" />
</p>
</center>
<br />
<br />
<center>
<table>
<tr>
<td align='center'>I am a proud</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align='center'><a href='http://www.earthcache.org'><img src=
'http://img.geocaching.com/user/e01b4330-2470-4531-a05d-2662bb4def80.jpg'
border='0' /></a></td>
</tr>
</table>
<br />
<a href="http://s06.flagcounter.com/more/HQ8E"><img src=
"http://s06.flagcounter.com/count/HQ8E/bg=FBFF8F/txt=246624/border=2F6935/columns=6/maxflags=60/viewers=3/labels=0/"
alt="free counters" /></a></center></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>A11J3MC - Location for answer 1<br />N 53° 22.344 W 006° 09.471<br />Depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Based on your direct observation, name and describe TWO landscpes that lie before you at this location.<br />A21J3MC - Location for answer 2<br />N 53° 22.169 W 006° 08.613<br />Do you see primary dunes, secondary dunes, or both?<br />A31J3MC - Location for answer 3<br />N 53° 22.448 W 006° 09.840<br />Name the three plants listed as growing in the alder marsh section of the island as stated on the information board.<br />A41J3MC - Location for answer 4 and 5<br />N 53° 21.624 W 006° 10.919<br />Describe the difference in the water roughness and wave action of
the water between this location and the location of the dunes in
question 2.

AND

Tell me is the tide coming in or going out, and how did you arrive
at that conclusion?<br />CP1J3MC - North Bull Wall parking location<br />N 53° 21.293 W 006° 10.197<br />Parking area for cars at the North Bull Wall<br />IC1J3MC - The Interpretive Centre<br />N 53° 22.120 W 006° 08.955<br />The location of the interpretive centre.<br />PK1J3MC - Causeway Parking<br />N 53° 22.210 W 006° 08.955<br />You can park your car along either side and at any point of the causeway road.<br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:A11J3MC|waypoints:cache-id:A21J3MC|waypoints:cache-id:A31J3MC|waypoints:cache-id:A41J3MC|waypoints:cache-id:CP1J3MC|waypoints:cache-id:IC1J3MC|waypoints:cache-id:PK1J3MC</links>
  <encoded-hints>
      </encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=60c90510-2459-4a7f-96c3-3c647aa1ded6</url>
  <url-name>North Bull Island</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-06-05T19:00:00Z : Found it by eve1987 <br />An very interesting walk and i learned a lot! 

TFTC, eve</li><li>2010-05-25T19:00:00Z : Found it by tmob <br />#2405

We looked for this cache during our holidays in Ireland.
Six fantastic days, 1800kms driven, and a bunch of caches found.
Definitely a great way to get to know this beautiful island!

When we did our homework about Dublin's caches, this one kept our attention.
Good decision to came here today, we learn something, and found beautiful place.

Thanks for this one...
Greetings from Portugal</li><li>2010-05-21T19:00:00Z : Found it by GudrunXY <br />It was a nice and interesting walk around the island. Learned lots of new stuff and even more new vocabularies. [8D]
Of course I had to get sunburned, it seems every time I visit Dublin I get sunburned - it's like a tradition.
TFTC, GudrunXY</li><li>2010-05-15T19:00:00Z : Found it by Alastair74 <br />Found with Wildfowler while spending the day in Dublin for the WWFM. TFTC</li><li>2010-05-15T19:00:00Z : Found it by wildfowler <br />Found on a caching weekend around Dublin with Alastair74! Thanks for a good earthcache in a very nice spot so close to a big city! I've sailed past it many times on the ferry from Wales. Nice to actually visit it for a change! Email sent! TFTEC</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.3725" lon="-6.156667">
    <time>2010-02-07T08:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GC1J3MC</name>
    <desc>North Bull Island by AbbeyAckbar, Earthcache (1.5/1.5)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=60c90510-2459-4a7f-96c3-3c647aa1ded6</url>
    <urlname>North Bull Island</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Earthcache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="1052154" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>North Bull Island</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>AbbeyAckbar</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="1265839">AbbeyAckbar</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Earthcache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Not chosen</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>1.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1.5</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Dublin</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/4f8d51a6-f70a-494c-a1c2-d5dab2dbed11.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Introduction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The North Bull Island developed from a sandbank and is a
relatively recent depositional feature to the Dublin coastline. The
island is less than 200 years old. The name is derived from the
locality, Clontarf, which in Gaelic is Cluain Tairbh meaning the
Bull's Meadow.&lt;/p&gt;</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;p&gt;What is fascinating about the island is how it came to exist,
and how it has developed into the island you see today. It is a
site of both national and international scientific interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sandspit is a form of coastal deposition that occurs as a
result of sediment being deposited that may have come from rivers,
and/or cliff erosion. Human impact may increase the supply of
material available which is what happened with North Bull Island.
It formed due to sedimentation accumulation resulting from the
construction of a harbour wall for Dublin port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Construction of the Harbour Walls &amp;amp; beginning of
North Bull Island&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Bay had a problem with silting for a long time at the
mouth of the River Liffey. After years of dredging to keep a clear
channel, attempts began in 1715 to build a wall which was to later
become the Great South Wall, completed in 1830. The first barrier
that was built was destroyed by a storm, so in 1761 work began on a
stone pier starting from the Poolbeg Lighthouse. In 1768, back at
shore, the construction of a massive granite wall began and was
completed in 1795.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, the building of a North Bull Wall was proposed
as the south wall hadn&amp;rsquo;t solved the silting problem. Captain
William Bligh, of &amp;lsquo;Mutiny on the Bounty&amp;rsquo; fame, surveyed
Dublin Bay for the Ballast Board in 1801, highlighting the
potential of the North Bull sandbank, a small dry part of the North
Bull which was directly adjacent to the large 18th century mansion
known as Baymount (Now known as Manresa House). A wooden bridge was
erected in 1819 to enable the construction of a stone wall. The
Bull Wall (which is 1km long) was completed in 1821.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section of the Bull Wall from the statue &amp;lsquo;Realt na
Mara&amp;rsquo; (Our Lady, Queen of the Sea), to the lighthouse is
known as the half tide wall. This is covered at high tide. The
purpose of the half tide wall and the wooden bridge section of the
bull wall was to act as safety valves to prevent damage to the wall
from the pressure of the full tide. Gradually, the channel into the
River Liffey deepened. The water level increased from 6ft to 16ft
at low tide. Wave and current action deposited and reworked the
sediments on the seabed. The sand that was dislodged got carried
out into the bay, picked up by currents and then deposited on the
North Bull Bank behind the north wall. This was the beginning of
North Bull Island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/03cb9980-793d-4522-821e-67b871ce54ea.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The development of the island&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image below is a rough map of the area resulting from
sediment deposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c92f7b5a-f522-4bc6-be3c-40cfc8ff8c67.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The island reached its current length in 1902. It is approx.
5km. long and 1km wide at its widest point. The area above high
tide is 300 hectares approx. and the Island continues to grow
seaward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sandspit is a type of shoal. Shoals are typically long and
narrow and develop where a stream or ocean current promotes
deposition of granular material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end of a spit attached to land is called the proximal end,
and the end jutting out into water is called the distal end. One
end is more protected than the other, and mud flats/salt marshes
may develop in sheltered areas behind them as is the case with
North Bull Island. Spits develop hooked ends due to wave refraction
which occurs at the end of the spit which carries some material
into more sheltered areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three basic landscapes types have developed over the past 150yrs
on the island :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.&lt;/b&gt; The elevated dune area&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;2.&lt;/b&gt; The salt marsh&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;3.&lt;/b&gt; The mud/sand flats of the lagoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.1 The Sand Dunes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A well-developed and dynamic dune system stretches along the
seaward side of the island. Various types of dunes occur, from
fixed dune grassland to pioneer communities on foredunes. The dune
system and beach is composed of sea/tide borne and wind blown sand
particles. Sand is a naturally occurring granular material composed
of finely divided rock and mineral particles. As the term is used
by geologists, sand particles range in diameter from 0.0625 to 2mm.
An individual particle in this range size is termed a sand grain.
In dune formation, marram grass plays a vital role in binding the
sand together with its roots and underground stems which can grow
upto 5 meters long. They send out horizontal root stems called
&amp;lsquo;rhizomes&amp;rsquo; under the surface to push up new growth
short distances away.These roots stabilize the dune and above
ground plant structures intercept and trap more sand. Dunes can
form without plants but they will be smaller than the potential
size they could reach if plants were able to establish and grow.
The dune closest to the ocean is the primary dune, or foredune,
followed by what are called secondary dunes or back dunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2.1 The Salt &amp;amp; Freshwater Marshes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The salt marsh is in the inter-tidal zone. It is located between
the island and the mainland. It is a large linear saltmarsh complex
backed by mudflats all of which are covered at high tide. The edge
of the marsh is marked by an eroding edge which varies from 20 cm
to 60 cm high. The substrate (sediment that rests at the bottom) of
the salt marsh and intertidal mudflats is composed mainly of very
fine silt particles, probably originating from materials discharged
into Dublin Bay by the rivers Liffey, Tolka and Dodder. There are
coarse gravels and stones in the Kilbarrack/Sutton area, which are
probably remnants of glacial till. (Glacial till is a type of
glacial deposit : material directly deposited from glacial ice.
Till includes a mixture of undifferentiated material ranging from
clay size to boulders.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each landscape type has its own distinctive vegetation. An
interesting mini eco-system is located in a large dune slack known
as the Alder Marsh (because of the presence of Alder trees) at the
north end of the island enclosed within the dunes at water level,
and features its own distinctive plant and insect life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3.1 The Mudflats&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The mudflats are in the inter-tidal zone beside the salt marsh.
Mudflats may be viewed geologically as exposed layers of bay mud,
resulting from deposition of estuarine silts, clays and marine
animal detritus. Most of the sediment within a mudflat is within
the intertidal zone, and so the flat is submerged and exposed 2
times a day approx.&lt;br /&gt;
The island shelters two intertidal lagoons which are divided by a
solid causeway. The sediments of the lagoons are mainly sands with
a small and varying mixture of silt and clay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
___________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seabed at the mouth of Dublin Bay infront of North Bull
Island shows the dynamic sedimentary processes operating in the
Irish Sea. The large sandbank located in the centre of the bay
(known as Burford Bank) is a notable seabed feature. From a
geological perspective, the sand waves at the northern and southern
ends of the bank illustrate the strong tidal currents moving in the
area which created and maintain this stunning seabed feature. It
has been suggested that there is a possibility that within the next
50yrs, continued deposition on bull island may lead to it merging
with the mainland at Red Rock in Sutton, forming a lagoon and
changing the make-up of the area. However, the risk of this is
considered very small due to the strength of currents and depth of
water in Sutton Channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several of the city's small rivers and streams enter the bay
here, notably the Naniken River, the River Tolka, the Santry River,
Fox Stream, Blackbanks Stream and Daunagh Water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The island is currently connected to the mainland by means of
the old wooden bridge and a causeway which was built in 1964 to
facilitate the volume of people visiting the island. The growing
number of visitors was also helped by the introduction of the horse
tram services to Clontarf in 1873, and further by the tram line to
Howth, which opened in 1900, and stopped in the Clontarf /
Dollymount area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The island lies roughly parallel to the shore off Clontarf
(including Dollymount), Raheny &amp;amp; Kilbarrack, and faces Sutton.
Between the causeway access point to the island and half way up to
the North Wall lies St.Anne's park (Dublin's 2nd largest park)
North Bull Island is run from the depot in this park. Dublin City
Council care and maintain the island through the parks and
landscape services division. The proximity of the park to the
island means that there is a very large area of the city suburb for
an abundance of plantlife and wildlife to thrive in and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Flora and Fauna of the island&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this landscape formation from the sea, an
abundance of wildlife and plantlife now exists and thrives on the
island. The island was declared a bird sanctuary in 1931 and is
protected under the Irish Wildlife Act. The island was declared a
Biosphere reserve by UNESCO (United Nations Educational Scientific
and cultural organization) in 1981. Biosphere reserves are sites
which demonstrate approaches to conservation and sustainable
development. The island was designated a National Nature Reserve in
1988 and a wetland of international importance under the Ramsar
Convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;b&gt;Note :February 2nd every year is &amp;lsquo;World Wetlands
Day.&lt;/b&gt; It marks the date of the signing of the Convention on
Wetlands on 2 February 1971, in the Iranian city of Ramsar on the
shores of the Caspian Sea. It aims to raise public awareness of
wetland values and benefits)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/b0ab8faa-112c-4cfa-a8fa-88415bd965e1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Interpretive Centre&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an interpretive centre located at the end of the
causeway (see additional waypoint co-ords) which assists in the
understanding of the unique flora and fauna and specialised
habitats of the island. It was constructed in 1986 through Dublin
City Council Parks and Landscape Services who also run the
facility. The centre serves to inform and educate the thousands of
schoolchildren and members of the public who visit every year. The
centre has a lecture theatre, a natural history museum, and an
aquarium. You can view the exhibits and use the telescope to watch
the birds outside. And it's all &lt;b&gt;for FREE!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c6ebaacc-bd42-4606-9620-910627116294.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Getting to North Bull Island&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the city centre, you can get the number 130 bus from Lower
Abbey Street to the Bull Wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Parking&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking is available anywere on either side of the causeway
(waypoint provided). All the information you need to get for
questions 1 to 3 are within walking distance of the parking area.
For questions 4 and 5, It is advisable to drive/cycle to another
parking location provided near the north bull wall (waypoint
provided)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;To log your visit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;To geocaching@thyme-it.ie please email
us the answers to at least &lt;b&gt;3&lt;/b&gt; of the following questions
:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.&lt;/b&gt;Go to N53 22.344, W006
09.471.&lt;br /&gt;
Depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Based on your direct observation, name and describe
&lt;b&gt;TWO&lt;/b&gt; landscapes that lie before you at this location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;2.&lt;/b&gt;Go to N53 22.169, W06
08.613.&lt;br /&gt;
Do you see primary dunes, secondary dunes, or both? Note the water
roughness and wave action you can see at this location for question
4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;3.&lt;/b&gt;At N53 22.448, W006
09.840.&lt;br /&gt;
Name the three plants listed as growing in the alder marsh section
of the island as stated on the information board about North Bull
Island located at the causeway access point to the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.&lt;/b&gt;Go to N53 21.624, W006
10.919&lt;br /&gt;
Depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Describe the difference in the water roughness and wave
action of the water between this location and the location of the
dunes in question 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;5.&lt;/b&gt;At the same co-ords as above,
depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Tell me is the tide coming in or going out, and how did you
arrive at that conclusion? note: If the tide is far out when you
visit this location, describe what you see before you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is optional and &lt;b&gt;NOT&lt;/b&gt; a requirement to log
your visit - photos from your visit are very welcome with your log.
Feel free to upload any wildlife/plant life/landscape photos you
take during your visit to the earthcache site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/95dce3d8-8691-4752-801c-0f42d3a45770.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;HAPPY EARTHCACHING!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/95dce3d8-8691-4752-801c-0f42d3a45770.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;I am a proud&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.earthcache.org'&gt;&lt;img src=
'http://img.geocaching.com/user/e01b4330-2470-4531-a05d-2662bb4def80.jpg'
border='0' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://s06.flagcounter.com/more/HQ8E"&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://s06.flagcounter.com/count/HQ8E/bg=FBFF8F/txt=246624/border=2F6935/columns=6/maxflags=60/viewers=3/labels=0/"
alt="free counters" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;A11J3MC - Location for answer 1&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 22.344 W 006° 09.471&lt;br /&gt;Depending on when you visit this cache, your observations will
vary. Based on your direct observation, name and describe TWO landscpes that lie before you at this location.&lt;br /&gt;A21J3MC - Location for answer 2&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 22.169 W 006° 08.613&lt;br /&gt;Do you see primary dunes, secondary dunes, or both?&lt;br /&gt;A31J3MC - Location for answer 3&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 22.448 W 006° 09.840&lt;br /&gt;Name the three plants listed as growing in the alder marsh section of the island as stated on the information board.&lt;br /&gt;A41J3MC - Location for answer 4 and 5&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 21.624 W 006° 10.919&lt;br /&gt;Describe the difference in the water roughness and wave action of
the water between this location and the location of the dunes in
question 2.

AND

Tell me is the tide coming in or going out, and how did you arrive
at that conclusion?&lt;br /&gt;CP1J3MC - North Bull Wall parking location&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 21.293 W 006° 10.197&lt;br /&gt;Parking area for cars at the North Bull Wall&lt;br /&gt;IC1J3MC - The Interpretive Centre&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 22.120 W 006° 08.955&lt;br /&gt;The location of the interpretive centre.&lt;br /&gt;PK1J3MC - Causeway Parking&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 22.210 W 006° 08.955&lt;br /&gt;You can park your car along either side and at any point of the causeway road.&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      </groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="112541435">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-05T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1617792">eve1987</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">An very interesting walk and i learned a lot! 

TFTC, eve</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="111497732">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-25T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="868022">tmob</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">#2405

We looked for this cache during our holidays in Ireland.
Six fantastic days, 1800kms driven, and a bunch of caches found.
Definitely a great way to get to know this beautiful island!

When we did our homework about Dublin's caches, this one kept our attention.
Good decision to came here today, we learn something, and found beautiful place.

Thanks for this one...
Greetings from Portugal</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="109474129">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-21T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2694097">GudrunXY</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">It was a nice and interesting walk around the island. Learned lots of new stuff and even more new vocabularies. [8D]
Of course I had to get sunburned, it seems every time I visit Dublin I get sunburned - it's like a tradition.
TFTC, GudrunXY</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="109083647">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-15T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2453409">Alastair74</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found with Wildfowler while spending the day in Dublin for the WWFM. TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="108916620">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-15T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="182407">wildfowler</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found on a caching weekend around Dublin with Alastair74! Thanks for a good earthcache in a very nice spot so close to a big city! I've sailed past it many times on the ferry from Wales. Nice to actually visit it for a change! Email sent! TFTEC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
