<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>006335</id>
  <cache-id>GCVYXV</cache-id>
  <type>Unknown Cache</type>
  <name>Tayleur by Windsockers, Unknown Cache (4.5/1.5)</name>
  <size>Not chosen</size>
  <difficulty>4.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>1.5</terrain>
  <last-found>2008-10-25</last-found>
  <placed>2006-05-09</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Windsockers</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.493567</lat>
  <lon>-6.108917</lon>
  <last-logs>XXFMF</last-logs>
  <owner>Windsockers</owner>
  <description><center>The John Tayleur<br />
<br />
<center>
<img src="http://www.eraoftheclipperships.com/images/tayleur6.jpg" />
</center></center>
<br />
New Tombstones bound for Austrailia<br />
<br />
<img src="http://www.northbeach.ie/gallery/albums/userpics/10001/john_tayleur.jpg" /></description>
  <long-description><p><b>From "The Illustrated London News", 28th January,
1854.</b></p>
<p>The Tayleur was designed expressly for the Australian passenger
Trade, to form one of Messrs. Pilkington and Wilsons celebrated
White Star Line. She was 2500 tons new measurement, and was capable
Of carrying 4000 tons of cargo. No expense had been spared in her
Construction and fitting up, and the general opinion was that she
Would prove a fast and safe sailer. Had justice been done to so
Fine a vessel, these expectations would, probably, have been
Realized but, if the prevailing statements are correct, the ship
Was undermanned when she left Liverpool, and to that fatal error
The sad catastrophe we have this week to relate, must be mainly
attributed.</p>
<p>The Tayleur sailed from Liverpool for Melbourne, at five minutes
To twelve, on Thursday, January 26th, with 652 persons on board,
Including the crew, and about eight p.m. was off Holyhead. After
Nightfall it began to blow strongly and during all next day the
Ship struggled with an adverse wind. By that time the more
Intelligent of the passengers became alarmed on account of the
Evident incompetence of the crew to manage the vessel. A number of
The men were Chinese and Lascars, who hardly knew the English
Language, and were consequently unable to understand the orders
Given by the captain. Throughout the whole of Friday the weather
Was thick and hazy also, so that no observations could be taken.
Early on Saturday morning the ship was under full sail, for which
The captain was blamed by some of the passengers, who remarked that
The crew could not take in so much sail on an emergency. As the day
Wore on the weather became boisterous, and about ten a.m. land was
In sight. In order to avoid any possible danger the ships course
Was altered about half-past eleven, and she was hauled up two
Points to windward. It was whilst on this course, and in about half
An hour after, that the man in the bows on the lookout cried out,
Breakers on the starboard bow! It was then blowing heavily, and a
High sea running. The helm was put hard to starboard, the sheets of
The headsails let go, and every means taken to bring the ship round
On a course free from the threatened danger. It was then impossible
To see a cable's length from the vessel, and in about twenty
Minutes more she struck with great violence on a reef of rocks
Running out from a creek right to the eastward bluff of Lambay
Island. The shock was tremendous, shaking the vessel from stem to
Stern. She rose on the next wave, and drove in rather broadside on;
And when she struck again still heaving, the sea made a clean
Breach over her amidships, setting everything on deck afloat. After
Two or three more shocks, the ship began to sink by the stern, and
The scene of confusion and dismay that ensued baffles all
Description; the passengers rushing up the hatchway, husbands
Carrying their children, and women lying prostrate on the deck with
Their infants, screaming and imploring help. The ship's quarter
Drifted on towards one side of the creek; and one of the cook's
Assistants (a black man), two Lascars, and three seamen, contrived
To jump across on shore, and thus saved their lives. A rope and a
Spar were afterwards got across, and by this means a number of
Lives were rescued, chiefly through the activity and devoted
Gallantry of two or three young men, passengers, whose exertions in
Saving the lives of their fellow-sufferers deserve the highest
Praise. Those who attempted to escape by the bows of the vessel
All, or nearly, met a miserable fate: the moment they fell into the
Water, the waves caught them, and dashed them violently against the
rocks; and the survivors on shore could perceive the unfortunate
Creatures, with their heads bruised and cut open, struggling amidst
The waves and one by one sinking under them. A first-cabin
Passenger, who managed to get on shore, gives the following account
Of the sad scenes which followed :</p>
<p>among some of the earliest of the females who attempted to get
On shore were some young Irishwomen. Most of them lost their hold
Of the rope, and fell into the sea. The doctor of the ship, a most
Noble fellow, struggled hard to save his wife and child, he had
Succeeded in getting about half-way to the shore on a rope holding
His child by its clothes in his teeth, but just then the ship
Lurched outwards, by which the rope was dragged from the hands of
Those who held it on the lower rocks, and was held only by those
Above, thus running him high in the air, so that the brave fellow
Could not drop on the rock. Word was now given to lower the rope
Gently; but those who held it above let it go by the run, and the
Poor fellow, with his child, was buried in the waves; but in a
Short time he again appeared above the water, manfully battling
With the waves and the portions of the wreck that now floated about
Him. He at length swam to a ladder hanging by a rope alongside the
Ship, and got upon it. After he had been there a minute or two his
Wife floated close to him; he immediately took bold of her, and
Dragged her on the ladder, tenderly parted the hair from her face,
And appeared to be encouraging her; but in another minute she was
Washed from his hold, and sank almost immediately. He then got up
Again into the ship and tried to get his wife on shore, but they
Both perished. He deserved a better fate. The scene was now most
Truly awful. The most desperate struggles for life were made by the
Wretched passengers, great numbers of women jumped overboard, in
The vain hope of reaching land; and the ropes were crowded by
Hundreds who, in their eagerness, terror, and confusion, frustrated
Each others efforts for self-preservation. Many of the females
Would get half way, and then become unable to proceed further; and,
After clinging to the rope for a short time, would be forced from
Their hold by those who came after them. Three women only, out of
200 were saved. One of those had got part of the way across when
Her legs fell, and she hung for some time by her two hands over the
Foaming waves; her husband then came on the rope, and managed to
Assist her to the shore. Two men came on shore with children tied
To their backs but of the whole who fell into the water not above
Five were saved. I saw one fine girl, who, after falling from the
Rope managed to get hold of another one, which was hanging from the
Side of the ship, and which she held on to for more than a quarter
Of an hour, the sea every moment dashing her against the side of
The ship: but it was impossible for us to lend her any assistance.
Someone got a spar out, by which several got on shore; but it soon
Broke; and now might be seen hundreds hanging on to the bulwarks of
The ship, each struggling to get on shore. I saw one young woman
Hanging on the middle of the rope for some time by her two hands,
But those pushing to get on shore soon sent her to her doom. The
Ships stern now began to sink; the ship made a lurch, and all the
Ropes were snapped asunder. The scene now was most harrowing. Every
Wave washed off scores at a time. We could see them struggle for a
Moment, then, tossing their arms, sink to rise no more. At length
The whole of the ship sunk under water. There was a fearful
Struggle for a moment, and all, except two who were in the rigging,
Were gone. The coastguard, who had been appraised of the wreck, now
Came up; but all they could do was to attempt to save the two who
were in the rigging. They managed to get a line to one of them, by
Fastening two lines, at the end of each of which was a piece of
Wood, to a single line, and guiding it from the rock to the spot
Where the poor fellow was, so that he could reach it. They then
Dragged him ashore. There was one fine young man left on the top,
But they could not reach him, and when he saw them going away his
Cries were heartrending. About two o'clock the next morning the
Coastguard managed to reach him, after he had been in the top
Fourteen hours: you may fancy the poor fellow's joy at his
Deliverance. We found we were on Lambay Island, three miles from
Rush, and about thirteen miles from Dublin.</p>
<p>Out of the entire number of persons on board only 282
Individuals were saved, so that 370 lives must have been lost
Altogether. News of the wreck having been taken to Dublin, the
Steam-packet Prince was sent to Lambay Island on Sunday afternoon;
And next morning the whole of the passengers and crew who had been
Rescued were taken to Dublin, where comfortable accommodation was
Provided for them.</p>
<p>Later accounts state that nearly 50 bodies have been found, and
That an inquest is to be held.</p>
<p>The Liverpool Mercury adds the following statement: We learn
That a letter has been received from Captain Noble, but it conveys
Nothing like an accurate account of the cause of the disaster. It
Appears that he had two sails blown away in the gale of Friday and
Saturday morning. His rudder, a patent one, is complained of as
Difficult to work, and his compasses were wrong. This is the sum of
His statement. It appears that there were a little over 100 females
On board, only three of whom are said to have been saved. The
Vessel still holds together and, as there is a large quantity of
Timber on board, she may continue to do so.</p>
<p>A subscription list has been opened in Liverpool in aid of the
Unfortunate sufferers by this deplorable wreck. It is headed by Mr.
Charles Moore, one of the owners, with £ 150, followed by the names
Of Messrs. Pilkington and Wilson (the Liverpool agents), £ 100; Mr.
James Baines (of the Black Ball line of Australian packets), £ 100,
Mr WS & Co £3o5</p>
<p><b>The Cache</b></p>
<p>In order to claim this cache you will need to do the following
:</p>
<p>1. Visit 2 locations to get the coordinates for the final
location</p>
<p>2. At the 1st location obtain the information that will give you
the location of the second part of the cache and half of the final
coordinates for the cache itself.</p>
<p>3. At the 2nd location obtain the other half of the coordinates
for the final cache.</p>
<br />
<center>
<img src="http://www.northbeach.ie/gallery/albums/userpics/10001/windsock-anim-small.gif" />
<br />
<b>The Windsockers</b></center></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>CLVYXV - Cache location<br />N/S  __ ° __ . ___ W/E ___ ° __ . ___ <br /><br />SLVYXV - Second location<br />N/S  __ ° __ . ___ W/E ___ ° __ . ___ <br /><br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:CLVYXV|waypoints:cache-id:SLVYXV</links>
  <encoded-hints>MISS YE SHIRT</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=23c667de-c67c-4af8-afba-6489b300ae92</url>
  <url-name>Tayleur</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-04-08T19:00:00Z : Didn't find it by steokelly <br />[Think we were at secound stage but after looking high and low could not find anything.] Reread some other peoples experiance and maybe need to get outside the box. will revisit to check this idea .....</li><li>2010-02-14T20:00:00Z : Didn't find it by theswerve <br />After finding stage 1 over a year ago...finally worked where stage 2 was...looked today,but found nothing!!!...at least i have half the final location...will be back...</li><li>2009-08-31T19:00:00Z : Found it by snoopyandmickey <br />Nice cache to finish the summer.  Tricky cache and it took more than one day.  Thankfully one half of the team is useful with numbers!  TFTC!  </li><li>2008-12-05T20:00:00Z : Owner Maintenance by Windsockers <br />Cache checked all in order</li><li>2008-10-25T19:00:00Z : Found it by toczygroszek <br />1st stage found with daraconn and theswerve one month ago. Short brainstorming, some ideas, but no success. One day Dara told he dissloved puzzle with one of ideas what we talking after finding 1st stage. Fortunately theswerwe was remember what the idea was, and after that it took me not too much thinking. After finding with Dara 2nd stage, we went to final location. We spotted dead animal - this time crab - it is always good sign if you looking for difficult Windsockers cache (1st time it was dead cormorant, 2nd dead rabbit). After about 20 min searching we found it - it was more than 20 m off.
Tahnks for this cache, I'm waiting for next puzzle caches!</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.493567" lon="-6.108917">
    <time>2006-05-09T07:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GCVYXV</name>
    <desc>Tayleur by Windsockers, Unknown Cache (4.5/1.5)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=23c667de-c67c-4af8-afba-6489b300ae92</url>
    <urlname>Tayleur</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Unknown Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="392209" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Tayleur</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Windsockers</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="271623">Windsockers</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Unknown Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Not chosen</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>4.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1.5</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Leinster</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">&lt;center&gt;The John Tayleur&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.eraoftheclipperships.com/images/tayleur6.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
New Tombstones bound for Austrailia&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.northbeach.ie/gallery/albums/userpics/10001/john_tayleur.jpg" /&gt;</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;From "The Illustrated London News", 28th January,
1854.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tayleur was designed expressly for the Australian passenger
Trade, to form one of Messrs. Pilkington and Wilsons celebrated
White Star Line. She was 2500 tons new measurement, and was capable
Of carrying 4000 tons of cargo. No expense had been spared in her
Construction and fitting up, and the general opinion was that she
Would prove a fast and safe sailer. Had justice been done to so
Fine a vessel, these expectations would, probably, have been
Realized but, if the prevailing statements are correct, the ship
Was undermanned when she left Liverpool, and to that fatal error
The sad catastrophe we have this week to relate, must be mainly
attributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tayleur sailed from Liverpool for Melbourne, at five minutes
To twelve, on Thursday, January 26th, with 652 persons on board,
Including the crew, and about eight p.m. was off Holyhead. After
Nightfall it began to blow strongly and during all next day the
Ship struggled with an adverse wind. By that time the more
Intelligent of the passengers became alarmed on account of the
Evident incompetence of the crew to manage the vessel. A number of
The men were Chinese and Lascars, who hardly knew the English
Language, and were consequently unable to understand the orders
Given by the captain. Throughout the whole of Friday the weather
Was thick and hazy also, so that no observations could be taken.
Early on Saturday morning the ship was under full sail, for which
The captain was blamed by some of the passengers, who remarked that
The crew could not take in so much sail on an emergency. As the day
Wore on the weather became boisterous, and about ten a.m. land was
In sight. In order to avoid any possible danger the ships course
Was altered about half-past eleven, and she was hauled up two
Points to windward. It was whilst on this course, and in about half
An hour after, that the man in the bows on the lookout cried out,
Breakers on the starboard bow! It was then blowing heavily, and a
High sea running. The helm was put hard to starboard, the sheets of
The headsails let go, and every means taken to bring the ship round
On a course free from the threatened danger. It was then impossible
To see a cable's length from the vessel, and in about twenty
Minutes more she struck with great violence on a reef of rocks
Running out from a creek right to the eastward bluff of Lambay
Island. The shock was tremendous, shaking the vessel from stem to
Stern. She rose on the next wave, and drove in rather broadside on;
And when she struck again still heaving, the sea made a clean
Breach over her amidships, setting everything on deck afloat. After
Two or three more shocks, the ship began to sink by the stern, and
The scene of confusion and dismay that ensued baffles all
Description; the passengers rushing up the hatchway, husbands
Carrying their children, and women lying prostrate on the deck with
Their infants, screaming and imploring help. The ship's quarter
Drifted on towards one side of the creek; and one of the cook's
Assistants (a black man), two Lascars, and three seamen, contrived
To jump across on shore, and thus saved their lives. A rope and a
Spar were afterwards got across, and by this means a number of
Lives were rescued, chiefly through the activity and devoted
Gallantry of two or three young men, passengers, whose exertions in
Saving the lives of their fellow-sufferers deserve the highest
Praise. Those who attempted to escape by the bows of the vessel
All, or nearly, met a miserable fate: the moment they fell into the
Water, the waves caught them, and dashed them violently against the
rocks; and the survivors on shore could perceive the unfortunate
Creatures, with their heads bruised and cut open, struggling amidst
The waves and one by one sinking under them. A first-cabin
Passenger, who managed to get on shore, gives the following account
Of the sad scenes which followed :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;among some of the earliest of the females who attempted to get
On shore were some young Irishwomen. Most of them lost their hold
Of the rope, and fell into the sea. The doctor of the ship, a most
Noble fellow, struggled hard to save his wife and child, he had
Succeeded in getting about half-way to the shore on a rope holding
His child by its clothes in his teeth, but just then the ship
Lurched outwards, by which the rope was dragged from the hands of
Those who held it on the lower rocks, and was held only by those
Above, thus running him high in the air, so that the brave fellow
Could not drop on the rock. Word was now given to lower the rope
Gently; but those who held it above let it go by the run, and the
Poor fellow, with his child, was buried in the waves; but in a
Short time he again appeared above the water, manfully battling
With the waves and the portions of the wreck that now floated about
Him. He at length swam to a ladder hanging by a rope alongside the
Ship, and got upon it. After he had been there a minute or two his
Wife floated close to him; he immediately took bold of her, and
Dragged her on the ladder, tenderly parted the hair from her face,
And appeared to be encouraging her; but in another minute she was
Washed from his hold, and sank almost immediately. He then got up
Again into the ship and tried to get his wife on shore, but they
Both perished. He deserved a better fate. The scene was now most
Truly awful. The most desperate struggles for life were made by the
Wretched passengers, great numbers of women jumped overboard, in
The vain hope of reaching land; and the ropes were crowded by
Hundreds who, in their eagerness, terror, and confusion, frustrated
Each others efforts for self-preservation. Many of the females
Would get half way, and then become unable to proceed further; and,
After clinging to the rope for a short time, would be forced from
Their hold by those who came after them. Three women only, out of
200 were saved. One of those had got part of the way across when
Her legs fell, and she hung for some time by her two hands over the
Foaming waves; her husband then came on the rope, and managed to
Assist her to the shore. Two men came on shore with children tied
To their backs but of the whole who fell into the water not above
Five were saved. I saw one fine girl, who, after falling from the
Rope managed to get hold of another one, which was hanging from the
Side of the ship, and which she held on to for more than a quarter
Of an hour, the sea every moment dashing her against the side of
The ship: but it was impossible for us to lend her any assistance.
Someone got a spar out, by which several got on shore; but it soon
Broke; and now might be seen hundreds hanging on to the bulwarks of
The ship, each struggling to get on shore. I saw one young woman
Hanging on the middle of the rope for some time by her two hands,
But those pushing to get on shore soon sent her to her doom. The
Ships stern now began to sink; the ship made a lurch, and all the
Ropes were snapped asunder. The scene now was most harrowing. Every
Wave washed off scores at a time. We could see them struggle for a
Moment, then, tossing their arms, sink to rise no more. At length
The whole of the ship sunk under water. There was a fearful
Struggle for a moment, and all, except two who were in the rigging,
Were gone. The coastguard, who had been appraised of the wreck, now
Came up; but all they could do was to attempt to save the two who
were in the rigging. They managed to get a line to one of them, by
Fastening two lines, at the end of each of which was a piece of
Wood, to a single line, and guiding it from the rock to the spot
Where the poor fellow was, so that he could reach it. They then
Dragged him ashore. There was one fine young man left on the top,
But they could not reach him, and when he saw them going away his
Cries were heartrending. About two o'clock the next morning the
Coastguard managed to reach him, after he had been in the top
Fourteen hours: you may fancy the poor fellow's joy at his
Deliverance. We found we were on Lambay Island, three miles from
Rush, and about thirteen miles from Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the entire number of persons on board only 282
Individuals were saved, so that 370 lives must have been lost
Altogether. News of the wreck having been taken to Dublin, the
Steam-packet Prince was sent to Lambay Island on Sunday afternoon;
And next morning the whole of the passengers and crew who had been
Rescued were taken to Dublin, where comfortable accommodation was
Provided for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later accounts state that nearly 50 bodies have been found, and
That an inquest is to be held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Liverpool Mercury adds the following statement: We learn
That a letter has been received from Captain Noble, but it conveys
Nothing like an accurate account of the cause of the disaster. It
Appears that he had two sails blown away in the gale of Friday and
Saturday morning. His rudder, a patent one, is complained of as
Difficult to work, and his compasses were wrong. This is the sum of
His statement. It appears that there were a little over 100 females
On board, only three of whom are said to have been saved. The
Vessel still holds together and, as there is a large quantity of
Timber on board, she may continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subscription list has been opened in Liverpool in aid of the
Unfortunate sufferers by this deplorable wreck. It is headed by Mr.
Charles Moore, one of the owners, with £ 150, followed by the names
Of Messrs. Pilkington and Wilson (the Liverpool agents), £ 100; Mr.
James Baines (of the Black Ball line of Australian packets), £ 100,
Mr WS &amp;amp; Co £3o5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Cache&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to claim this cache you will need to do the following
:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Visit 2 locations to get the coordinates for the final
location&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. At the 1st location obtain the information that will give you
the location of the second part of the cache and half of the final
coordinates for the cache itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. At the 2nd location obtain the other half of the coordinates
for the final cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.northbeach.ie/gallery/albums/userpics/10001/windsock-anim-small.gif" /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;The Windsockers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;CLVYXV - Cache location&lt;br /&gt;N/S  __ ° __ . ___ W/E ___ ° __ . ___ &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SLVYXV - Second location&lt;br /&gt;N/S  __ ° __ . ___ W/E ___ ° __ . ___ &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>MISS YE SHIRT</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="103186576">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-08T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Didn't find it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2933361">steokelly</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="True">[Think we were at secound stage but after looking high and low could not find anything.] Reread some other peoples experiance and maybe need to get outside the box. will revisit to check this idea .....</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="97285394">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-02-14T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Didn't find it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1032462">theswerve</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">After finding stage 1 over a year ago...finally worked where stage 2 was...looked today,but found nothing!!!...at least i have half the final location...will be back...</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="82752785">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-08-31T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="289646">snoopyandmickey</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Nice cache to finish the summer.  Tricky cache and it took more than one day.  Thankfully one half of the team is useful with numbers!  TFTC!  </groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="58292148">
          <groundspeak:date>2008-12-05T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Owner Maintenance</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="271623">Windsockers</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Cache checked all in order</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="55904711">
          <groundspeak:date>2008-10-25T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1429023">toczygroszek</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">1st stage found with daraconn and theswerve one month ago. Short brainstorming, some ideas, but no success. One day Dara told he dissloved puzzle with one of ideas what we talking after finding 1st stage. Fortunately theswerwe was remember what the idea was, and after that it took me not too much thinking. After finding with Dara 2nd stage, we went to final location. We spotted dead animal - this time crab - it is always good sign if you looking for difficult Windsockers cache (1st time it was dead cormorant, 2nd dead rabbit). After about 20 min searching we found it - it was more than 20 m off.
Tahnks for this cache, I'm waiting for next puzzle caches!</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
