<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>006771</id>
  <cache-id>GC1VDTJ</cache-id>
  <type>Unknown Cache</type>
  <name>Howth Castle by kazidrat, Unknown Cache (2.5/1.5)</name>
  <size>Small</size>
  <difficulty>2.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>1.5</terrain>
  <last-found>2010-03-09</last-found>
  <placed>2009-07-02</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>kazidrat</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.38625</lat>
  <lon>-6.078567</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFWX</last-logs>
  <owner>kazidrat</owner>
  <description>This is a small cache, which is located on the grounds of the Howth
Castle. The coordinates above are for reference only. For the real
coordinates you will need to answer some questions. Please rehide
it carefully to prevent muggles from discovering its location.</description>
  <long-description><center><img src=
"http://photos-g.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc1/hs195.snc1/6571_1020962221807_1757731697_35798_1153680_n.jpg" /></center>
<p>Howth Castle lies close to the village of Howth, north of the
city of Dublin. It is the ancestral home of the line of the Earl of
Howth, now held by their heirs, the Gaisford St. Lawrence family.
The current building is not the original Howth Castle. It was
restyled by the great English architect Sir Edwin Lutyens. The
grounds are noted for the wild rhododendron gardens. There are
planted about 2 000 varieties of rhododendrons.</p>
<p>The castle itself is not open to the public.</p>
<p>Quiz:</p>
<p>Q 1. In what year did the pirate Grace O'Malley achieved for the
gates to be opened to unexpected visitors, and to set an extra
place at every meal, by abducting the grand son and heir of the 8th
Baron Howth?<br />
Answer = A</p>
<p>Q 2. In the grounds of the Howth Castle is located The National
Transport Museum of Ireland. There is exhibited the restored Hill
of Howth Tram - what number is it?<br />
Answer = B</p>
<p>Q 3. Electric double-decker tramcars ran the five-mile route
from Sutton station via Howth Summit down into Howth railway
station - how many years were the trams in operation?<br />
Answer = C (simply substract)</p>
<p>Q 4. On the grounds of Howth Caste lies a huge megalithic
monument / portal tomb - what is its name? Count the letters<br />
Answer = D</p>
<p>Q 5. What type of single-chamber megalithic tomb is this? Count
the letters<br />
Answer = E</p>
<p>Q 6. Deer Park Hotel Golf & Spa is also situated in the
grounds of Howth Castle and boasts Ireland's largest golf complex,
all created by well-known architect - what is his name? Count all
letters (first and last name)<br />
Answer = F</p>
<p>Q 7. What is the name of the flower which was adopted by the Spa
at Deer Park as its emblem? Number of words<br />
Answer = G</p>
<p>Now that you have all the answers, you can calculate the final
coordinates using the following math exercise.</p>
<p>N 53°(B+F+G). (A-(B+F+D+E+G)) / 2</p>
<p>W 006°04.(CxE)+(FxG)+(E+D)</p></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>FL1VDTJ - Final location<br />N/S  __ ° __ . ___ W/E ___ ° __ . ___ <br /><br />PA1VDTJ - Parking area<br />N 53° 22.874 W 006° 04.669<br /><br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:FL1VDTJ|waypoints:cache-id:PA1VDTJ</links>
  <encoded-hints>Base of tree...</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=313156bc-f0ea-44cf-8526-6ced7d20cd84</url>
  <url-name>Howth Castle</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-05-21T20:24:40Z : Found it by Crannyn <br />Lovely morning caching with hollmanr. They did all the calculations(again) but definately a joint effort finding it.Had a well deserved lunch in Brass Monkey' restaurant in the harbour .IN _ magnet TFTC</li><li>2010-05-21T19:00:00Z : Found it by hollmanr <br />Had the questions and co-ordinates worked out a few months ago but the golf course crossing was putting us off. Went up this morning with crannyn and there weren't too many golfers about. We talked to a man who was working at the DeerPark and he said it was fine to walk along the side of the golf course as long as we let the golfers tee off. So off we went, met no golfers and found the cache with the hint. Took Wooden Geocoin and left large dice and nintendo ds game case.
We came back a different way  - so it is possible to reach the cache location without walking over the golf course which could be awkward at the weekends when its very busy. The path/track starts at the back of the tennis courts. Go initially right and then follow the track and head straight up towards the reservoir. Once you get to the reservoir there is a track leading around it that brings you the cache area. Abundance of wild garlic there today amongst the trees - very pretty.  SL TFTC.</li><li>2010-03-28T19:00:00Z : Found it by Spark_ie <br />Had the co-ords worked out for this one a while ago, but today was my first time in Howth since.  I was a bit wary walking to the cache, as it didn't feel right walking up the pitch and putt course, but when I saw people playing with their dogs etc, I figured I was alright [:)] Got to the cache location no problems, and spotted the cache from a-high.. Snuck around the corner to sign the log as some players were teeing off !! TFTC, Spark_ie</li><li>2010-03-12T20:00:00Z : Write note by Moonshiner Extraordinaire <br />After finding “Chocolate Soup II”, we decided to look for this cache. However, there were NO information boards to get the information required. My sister Anna was dismayed and disappointed at that (I was more like outraged). I went to the nearby transport museum (which was closed) and to the hotel… It seems the questions have to be answered BEFORE you come here! I was caught out like this at a cache in Spain last year, and I wasn’t pleased to ‘find’ another such cache… It could easily have said so on the cache page. Even though the transport museum was closed, outside it I discovered what I thought was a ‘Timoney’ armoured personnel carrier (Irish designed and built for the Irish army, imagine). It must be 30 years since I had my hands on one of them (the good old days). As ‘Arnie’ said “I’ll be back” – some day.

Moonshiner X</li><li>2010-03-09T20:00:00Z : Didn't find it by orangetigerprawn <br />I tried searching for this in vain. I had the final coordinates worked out some time back, just waiting for the right occasion. The GPS was a bit all over the place with plenty hiding places. I'll try again some other day.</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.38625" lon="-6.078567">
    <time>2009-07-02T07:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GC1VDTJ</name>
    <desc>Howth Castle by kazidrat, Unknown Cache (2.5/1.5)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=313156bc-f0ea-44cf-8526-6ced7d20cd84</url>
    <urlname>Howth Castle</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Unknown Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="1300253" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Howth Castle</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>kazidrat</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="1851316">kazidrat</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Unknown Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Small</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>2.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1.5</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Dublin</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">This is a small cache, which is located on the grounds of the Howth
Castle. The coordinates above are for reference only. For the real
coordinates you will need to answer some questions. Please rehide
it carefully to prevent muggles from discovering its location.</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://photos-g.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc1/hs195.snc1/6571_1020962221807_1757731697_35798_1153680_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howth Castle lies close to the village of Howth, north of the
city of Dublin. It is the ancestral home of the line of the Earl of
Howth, now held by their heirs, the Gaisford St. Lawrence family.
The current building is not the original Howth Castle. It was
restyled by the great English architect Sir Edwin Lutyens. The
grounds are noted for the wild rhododendron gardens. There are
planted about 2 000 varieties of rhododendrons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The castle itself is not open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quiz:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q 1. In what year did the pirate Grace O'Malley achieved for the
gates to be opened to unexpected visitors, and to set an extra
place at every meal, by abducting the grand son and heir of the 8th
Baron Howth?&lt;br /&gt;
Answer = A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q 2. In the grounds of the Howth Castle is located The National
Transport Museum of Ireland. There is exhibited the restored Hill
of Howth Tram - what number is it?&lt;br /&gt;
Answer = B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q 3. Electric double-decker tramcars ran the five-mile route
from Sutton station via Howth Summit down into Howth railway
station - how many years were the trams in operation?&lt;br /&gt;
Answer = C (simply substract)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q 4. On the grounds of Howth Caste lies a huge megalithic
monument / portal tomb - what is its name? Count the letters&lt;br /&gt;
Answer = D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q 5. What type of single-chamber megalithic tomb is this? Count
the letters&lt;br /&gt;
Answer = E&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q 6. Deer Park Hotel Golf &amp;amp; Spa is also situated in the
grounds of Howth Castle and boasts Ireland's largest golf complex,
all created by well-known architect - what is his name? Count all
letters (first and last name)&lt;br /&gt;
Answer = F&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q 7. What is the name of the flower which was adopted by the Spa
at Deer Park as its emblem? Number of words&lt;br /&gt;
Answer = G&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have all the answers, you can calculate the final
coordinates using the following math exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N 53°(B+F+G). (A-(B+F+D+E+G)) / 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W 006°04.(CxE)+(FxG)+(E+D)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;FL1VDTJ - Final location&lt;br /&gt;N/S  __ ° __ . ___ W/E ___ ° __ . ___ &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;PA1VDTJ - Parking area&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 22.874 W 006° 04.669&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>Base of tree...</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="109386248">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-21T20:24:40Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2557004">Crannyn</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Lovely morning caching with hollmanr. They did all the calculations(again) but definately a joint effort finding it.Had a well deserved lunch in Brass Monkey' restaurant in the harbour .IN _ magnet TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="109349592">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-21T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2511647">hollmanr</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Had the questions and co-ordinates worked out a few months ago but the golf course crossing was putting us off. Went up this morning with crannyn and there weren't too many golfers about. We talked to a man who was working at the DeerPark and he said it was fine to walk along the side of the golf course as long as we let the golfers tee off. So off we went, met no golfers and found the cache with the hint. Took Wooden Geocoin and left large dice and nintendo ds game case.
We came back a different way  - so it is possible to reach the cache location without walking over the golf course which could be awkward at the weekends when its very busy. The path/track starts at the back of the tennis courts. Go initially right and then follow the track and head straight up towards the reservoir. Once you get to the reservoir there is a track leading around it that brings you the cache area. Abundance of wild garlic there today amongst the trees - very pretty.  SL TFTC.</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="101619884">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-28T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="950104">Spark_ie</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Had the co-ords worked out for this one a while ago, but today was my first time in Howth since.  I was a bit wary walking to the cache, as it didn't feel right walking up the pitch and putt course, but when I saw people playing with their dogs etc, I figured I was alright [:)] Got to the cache location no problems, and spotted the cache from a-high.. Snuck around the corner to sign the log as some players were teeing off !! TFTC, Spark_ie</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="105344304">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-12T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Write note</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="154025">Moonshiner Extraordinaire</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">After finding “Chocolate Soup II”, we decided to look for this cache. However, there were NO information boards to get the information required. My sister Anna was dismayed and disappointed at that (I was more like outraged). I went to the nearby transport museum (which was closed) and to the hotel… It seems the questions have to be answered BEFORE you come here! I was caught out like this at a cache in Spain last year, and I wasn’t pleased to ‘find’ another such cache… It could easily have said so on the cache page. Even though the transport museum was closed, outside it I discovered what I thought was a ‘Timoney’ armoured personnel carrier (Irish designed and built for the Irish army, imagine). It must be 30 years since I had my hands on one of them (the good old days). As ‘Arnie’ said “I’ll be back” – some day.

Moonshiner X</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="99292262">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-09T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Didn't find it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2167131">orangetigerprawn</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">I tried searching for this in vain. I had the final coordinates worked out some time back, just waiting for the right occasion. The GPS was a bit all over the place with plenty hiding places. I'll try again some other day.</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
