<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>007329</id>
  <cache-id>GC20978</cache-id>
  <type>Multi-cache</type>
  <name>11 A Walk in the Garden-Black Hill by Kili or bust, Multi-cache (2/3)</name>
  <size>Regular</size>
  <difficulty>2</difficulty>
  <terrain>3</terrain>
  <last-found>2010-03-07</last-found>
  <placed>2010-03-06</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Kili or bust</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.133583</lat>
  <lon>-6.45515</lon>
  <last-logs>FFF</last-logs>
  <owner>Kili or bust</owner>
  <description>
      </description>
  <long-description><p align="center"><a target="_blank" href=
"http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"><img border="0" src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/2280ab19-c5fc-4d33-8efb-797df9c0ac8c.jpg"
width="150" height="43" align="middle" /></a></p>
<hr size="2" />
<center><font color="green">Visit The Geocaching Ireland discussion
forum <a href="http://www.mccartan.org/forums/" target=
"_blank">HERE</a></font></center>
<hr size="2" />
<b><i>On<br />
Emerald<br />
Glistening hills, naught but<br />
Tinkling streams and soft bog with purple frills, and<br />
Sparkling<br />
Granite, rich<br />
With eons of earth<br />
Life, washed and heaven fed,<br />
Where doe, grouse and silent fox gentle lay their<br />
Cubbing bed, and young men lie dead.</i></b><br />
<br />
This is another in the walking series in the "Garden of Ireland."
There is no puzzle involved and though I used the above quote in
another cache page, I felt that sadly it has slightly more
relevance here.<br />
The circular walk takes about an hour and a half to two hours on a
nice day during which you will be treated to beautiful views over
the Blessington lake. The complete circuit is six and a half
Kilometres with a total ascent of 342 metres which is low level and
easy. A number of "Erratics" (large boulders) left by glaciers
during the last Ice Age feature at various stages of this cache so
keep an eye out for them.<br />
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/e0e73fb1-1bfa-4b1b-aff6-4fb0f6c83c37.jpg" /></center>
<br />
<br />
In order to complete the cache you will need to do the walk as
described so that you can pick up the various pieces of information
needed to calculate the coordinates for the final cache. For this
you may need a pen and a piece of paper.<br />
This can be achieved in many ways but the one I preferred when
placing the cache was to take a circular walking route in an
anticlockwise direction, taking in the final cache near the end of
the hike. The set up of the stages of this cache heavily favours
those prepared to do the short hike. Several parts of this trek
route can almost be reached by car but there is no advantage as you
still would have to walk distances to and from your vehicle that
are similar to the hike itself. and also there would be quite a bit
of driving back and forth. In this regard <b>PLEASE BE AWARE OF
LOCAL OWNERS PRIVATE PROPERTY AND KEEP OFF FARMING LAND.</b><br />
I have provided coordinates here for Ballynultagh Wood (marked with
the large "P" in the map above).<br />
***NOTE: This cache and its neighbour Lugnagun/Sorrel could be done
in one trip on a good hiking day, both from this car park. If you
choose this option be sure to bring plenty of sustenance as it
would be a full day's hiking.<br />
To start the Black Hill circuit, from that car park walk down the
road in the direction of the lake. You will notice, looking
Southward across at Black Hill which is the further hill on your
left, that there is a clear path snaking up the Western (or Lake)
side and another coming back down the Eastern side to the car park
that you just left. You need to be aiming downward (or South) to
get around the privately owned fields and trees in the centre and
reach the start of that Western grass path. You may do so by
dropping down to the left across open moorland anywhere along the
road but do not go any further than N53 08.510 W006 27.314 where
there is an old track leading in the direction you wish to go. It
helps a little but better to head across before that. From the road
you may be able to make out trodden paths across the moorland.
There is a small brook to cross and some rough walking but the rest
of this land is just bumpy and a bit boggy in parts.<br />
You need to be heading for N53 07.863 W006 27.324 which is the
corner of the private land but before that you will need to find
Stage 1 and pick up some information before moving on to the green
path.<br />
Stage 1<br />
At a nice round Erratic at N53 08.015 W006 27.309 you will find a
piece of wood with 3 numbers attached. Call these in ascending
order CDE.<br />
<br />
Stage 2<br />
Continue around the private land in the direction of the grass path
up the mountain. When you reach the start of the path at N53 07.906
W006 27.516 you will reach a reddish brown gate. As you start up
the grassy track toward the mountain, after about 50 metres there
is a trodden path leading Westward (to the right off the track)
toward the lake and roughly in line with the private land boundary.
Follow this till you come to Stage 2 at N53 07.966 W006
28.075<br />
<br />
Here you will find two dates which will give you an age. Call that
age BA.<br />
<br />
Stage 3<br />
You need to go back up to access the grass track to the mountain.
You may do this by retracing your steps or by cutting across
moorland more directly to reach Stage 3<br />
at N53 07.289 W006 27.430<br />
<br />
Here you need to answer how many holes are at the top of the stone
column on the side WITHOUT the inscription, in other words the side
<b>not</b> facing the lake. Call your answer H.<br />
<br />
Continue on the track to the summit of Black Hill.<br />
Stage 4<br />
N53 07.317 W006 26.716<br />
Here you will find 2 numbers. Call these (in ascending order)
FG.<br />
<br />
The final cache coordinates should now take you in the direction of
the road and car park.<br />
Final Cache N53 AB.CDE W006 26.FGH<b><br />
<br />
<br />
From Mountain Views:<br />
Black Hill Mountain Wicklow County<br />
Height: 602 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top<br />
Grid Ref: O04137 09033 Latitude: 53.121964 Longitude: -6.445273
ITM: 704063 709064<br />
Black Hill is the 271st highest summit in Ireland.<br />
<br />
HAMPDEN BOMBER CRASH</b><br />
DUBLIN, IRELAND - On the night of 16th April, 1941, "...hour after
hour of fire-bombs rained down on London." (Belfast had been bombed
the previous night.) Next night a Handley Page Hampden S/N AD730
was detailed to bomb an aiming point at Berlin and was one of seven
from No. 50 squadron which took off from its base at Lindholme in
Yorkshire.<br />
<br />
It was crewed by:<br />
* P/O J. K. Hill, Captain 83253<br />
* Sgt. J. T. Lamb, Navigator 744628<br />
* Sgt. S. Wright, Wireless Operator/Air Gunner 751744<br />
* Sgt. F. H. Erdwin, Air Gunner 553897<br />
<br />
It would appear that this crew did not reach Berlin; the the pilot,
J.K. Hill was not in a position to identify his target, due to haze
over Germany and opted for a secondary one, as he was not in
contact with the other planes. The bad weather encountered over the
North Sea was already crossing over the Continent, with no
improvement over Britain or to the West.<br />
At 02.17 hours, Sgt. S. Wright (Wireless Operator) made contact and
was given a second class fix and bearing from Bircham Common. This
placed the aircraft approximately five miles SW of RAF
Watton.<br />
For some unknown reason the Hampton Bomber continued flying West
--- possibly due to a compass malfunction. The bomber crossed the
Welsh mountains, which would seem to indicate that it was flying at
4000 feet. Its first movements over Ireland were reported by the
look-out posts on the East Coast at 04.05 hours while tracking
inland between Dalkey and Bray. The plane was reported flying west
towards Kildare. It then changed course, which brought it to an
East-Northeast position.<br />
At 04.24 hours, Gardai at Hollywood, County Wicklow, reported an
aircraft in the area to Air Defence. According to the Department of
Defence, local people reported hearing a plane also. (The crew of
the Hampton SD730 who had survived that April night in the German
sky were to die only hours later on a lonelly hillside in Kyleberg
in neutral Ireland.) Investigators reached the conclusion that the
plane crashed ten minutes later, killing the crew instantly.<br />
The instrument panel clocks found in the wreckage recorded the time
of the crash as 04.34 hours. The bodies of the victims lay in
Blackhill (Kyleberg) until Saturday 19th, when they were found by
turf-workers.<br />
It must be remembered that the nearest telephone was in
Blessington, nearly six miles away, so it was late in the evening
when the Security Forces arrived on the scene. A military guard
from the Curragh and an ambulance made their way up the "Hill
Road." L.D.F. and Gardai stood on duty. Comdt. Harrington G (2)
Branch Curragh Command was also present. Air Corps officers under
Comdt. Murphy were standing by.<br />
In his report to the Department of Defence (25/04/41) Comdt. Mackey
was lavish in his praise of the work of Superintendent Quinn, Supt.
Reynolds and Sgt. Bohan, Blessington. On Monday 21st April, 1941,
the Coroner for West Wicklow instructed that no inquest would be
held. His report to Comdt. Mackey stated: "The crew received
frightful injuries and death was instanteous in each case."<br />
The funerals took place on Tuesday 22nd at St. Mary's Church,
Blessington. The coffins, wrapped in the British flag, were carried
to the church by soldiers escorted by a guard of honor and preceded
by the No. 3 Army Band. It was attended by the British
Representative, Sir John Maffey, with Lady Maffey and their
daughter, Mrs. Max Aitken. Also present was Mr. Leywood of the
British Legation, who had arrived in Blessington on Sunday 20th and
visited the scene of the crash.<br />
Irish Army officers attending included Major P. Maher, representing
the Minister of Defence, and Comdt. E. Rooney, representing the
Chief of Staff.<br />
The service was conducted by Rev. W.R. Crooks and the four bodies
were buried in the one grave. The Irish Times of 23rd April, 1941,
said, "During the funeral all shops in Blessington were closed and
blinds drawn on windows."<br />
In his report to the Chief of Staff, Department of Defence,
(25/04/41) Comdt. D.J. Murphy, Air Corps Headquarters, wrote:<br />
"Cause of crash: not known. The aircraft appeared to fly straight
into the side of the hill. Parts were scattered over a wide area.
The area where the Hampton crashed is about 1600 feet above O.D.,
rising sharply from around 620 feet."<br />
Ironically, the motto of the 50th Squadron was "Sic fidem servamus"
(Thus we keep Faith). For those young airmen there was no glory of
D-Day. No honour of being shot down over enemy territory. Kyleberg
was their Armageddon.<br />
For them the war was lost -- and won -- on Blackhill.<br />
<br />
<font color="red"><font size="4"><b>Do not start the trek without
all the proper mountain rain gear, waterproof boots and the
guidance material, compass, map, GPSr with mapping etc. Please note
that all parts of this cache are hiked at your own risk. The cache
owner takes no responsibility of any sort for any reason including
accidents or mishaps.<br /></b></font></font><br />
<br />
<font color="red"><font size="4">Please be aware that cars parked
in areas close to walking trails are vulnerable and they can be
vandalised or stolen. Unfortunately this is an ongoing problem
which is extremely difficult to solve. so there is a risk
involved.<br />
Please observe the country code to the best of your ability. Local
landowners often generously allow access to upland areas across or
through parts of their private property. Please, please be
conscious of this and return the courtesy by keeping all gates
closed, immediately and not on your way back!. Please use the gates
where appropriate but if you have to climb over them then use the
hinged side ONLY.<br />
Please do not cause any damage of any sort to fences or barriers
along the way.</font></font><br />
<br /></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>P120978 - Garden 11 Parking Ballynultagh<br />N 53° 08.294 W 006° 26.459<br /><br />R120978 - Garden 11 Road Track<br />N 53° 08.510 W 006° 27.314<br /><br />R220978 - Garden 11 Corner<br />N 53° 07.863 W 006° 27.324<br /><br />S220978 - Garden 11 Stage 2<br />N 53° 07.966 W 006° 28.075<br /><br />S320978 - Garden 11 Stage 3<br />N 53° 07.289 W 006° 27.430<br /><br />S420978 - Garden 11 Stage 4<br />N 53° 07.317 W 006° 26.716<br /><br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:P120978|waypoints:cache-id:R120978|waypoints:cache-id:R220978|waypoints:cache-id:S220978|waypoints:cache-id:S320978|waypoints:cache-id:S420978</links>
  <encoded-hints>Small boulder</encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=52a46950-1a24-4f90-84c5-c91f75a9727d</url>
  <url-name>11 A Walk in the Garden-Black Hill</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-05-17T19:00:00Z : Found it by theswerve <br />Another great hike with great views over the lakes...found all stages ok...final no problem...TFTC...</li><li>2010-04-10T19:00:00Z : Found it by ljeh <br />My first of the series which I enjoyed very much. Co-ordinates for the stages are spot on. There are stunning views of the Blessington lakes so be sure to bring your camera. Thanks for a terrific cache, really looking forward to doing the rest of the series.</li><li>2010-03-12T20:00:00Z : Found it by Hezekiah <br />FTF!  Beautiful walk with great views, and not a little interest (particularly as a member of the Dublin & District Motorcycle Club - if you do the walk you'll understand!).  Another little cracker in the series - thanks, Sean!</li><li>2010-03-07T11:54:48Z : Publish Listing by Croaghan <br />Published</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.133583" lon="-6.45515">
    <time>2010-03-06T08:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GC20978</name>
    <desc>11 A Walk in the Garden-Black Hill by Kili or bust, Multi-cache (2/3)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=52a46950-1a24-4f90-84c5-c91f75a9727d</url>
    <urlname>11 A Walk in the Garden-Black Hill</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Multi-cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="1444796" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>11 A Walk in the Garden-Black Hill</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Kili or bust</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="281705">Kili or bust</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Multi-cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Regular</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>2</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>3</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Leinster</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">
      </groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href=
"http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/2280ab19-c5fc-4d33-8efb-797df9c0ac8c.jpg"
width="150" height="43" align="middle" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr size="2" /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;font color="green"&gt;Visit The Geocaching Ireland discussion
forum &lt;a href="http://www.mccartan.org/forums/" target=
"_blank"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;hr size="2" /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;On&lt;br /&gt;
Emerald&lt;br /&gt;
Glistening hills, naught but&lt;br /&gt;
Tinkling streams and soft bog with purple frills, and&lt;br /&gt;
Sparkling&lt;br /&gt;
Granite, rich&lt;br /&gt;
With eons of earth&lt;br /&gt;
Life, washed and heaven fed,&lt;br /&gt;
Where doe, grouse and silent fox gentle lay their&lt;br /&gt;
Cubbing bed, and young men lie dead.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is another in the walking series in the "Garden of Ireland."
There is no puzzle involved and though I used the above quote in
another cache page, I felt that sadly it has slightly more
relevance here.&lt;br /&gt;
The circular walk takes about an hour and a half to two hours on a
nice day during which you will be treated to beautiful views over
the Blessington lake. The complete circuit is six and a half
Kilometres with a total ascent of 342 metres which is low level and
easy. A number of "Erratics" (large boulders) left by glaciers
during the last Ice Age feature at various stages of this cache so
keep an eye out for them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/e0e73fb1-1bfa-4b1b-aff6-4fb0f6c83c37.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In order to complete the cache you will need to do the walk as
described so that you can pick up the various pieces of information
needed to calculate the coordinates for the final cache. For this
you may need a pen and a piece of paper.&lt;br /&gt;
This can be achieved in many ways but the one I preferred when
placing the cache was to take a circular walking route in an
anticlockwise direction, taking in the final cache near the end of
the hike. The set up of the stages of this cache heavily favours
those prepared to do the short hike. Several parts of this trek
route can almost be reached by car but there is no advantage as you
still would have to walk distances to and from your vehicle that
are similar to the hike itself. and also there would be quite a bit
of driving back and forth. In this regard &lt;b&gt;PLEASE BE AWARE OF
LOCAL OWNERS PRIVATE PROPERTY AND KEEP OFF FARMING LAND.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have provided coordinates here for Ballynultagh Wood (marked with
the large "P" in the map above).&lt;br /&gt;
***NOTE: This cache and its neighbour Lugnagun/Sorrel could be done
in one trip on a good hiking day, both from this car park. If you
choose this option be sure to bring plenty of sustenance as it
would be a full day's hiking.&lt;br /&gt;
To start the Black Hill circuit, from that car park walk down the
road in the direction of the lake. You will notice, looking
Southward across at Black Hill which is the further hill on your
left, that there is a clear path snaking up the Western (or Lake)
side and another coming back down the Eastern side to the car park
that you just left. You need to be aiming downward (or South) to
get around the privately owned fields and trees in the centre and
reach the start of that Western grass path. You may do so by
dropping down to the left across open moorland anywhere along the
road but do not go any further than N53 08.510 W006 27.314 where
there is an old track leading in the direction you wish to go. It
helps a little but better to head across before that. From the road
you may be able to make out trodden paths across the moorland.
There is a small brook to cross and some rough walking but the rest
of this land is just bumpy and a bit boggy in parts.&lt;br /&gt;
You need to be heading for N53 07.863 W006 27.324 which is the
corner of the private land but before that you will need to find
Stage 1 and pick up some information before moving on to the green
path.&lt;br /&gt;
Stage 1&lt;br /&gt;
At a nice round Erratic at N53 08.015 W006 27.309 you will find a
piece of wood with 3 numbers attached. Call these in ascending
order CDE.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Stage 2&lt;br /&gt;
Continue around the private land in the direction of the grass path
up the mountain. When you reach the start of the path at N53 07.906
W006 27.516 you will reach a reddish brown gate. As you start up
the grassy track toward the mountain, after about 50 metres there
is a trodden path leading Westward (to the right off the track)
toward the lake and roughly in line with the private land boundary.
Follow this till you come to Stage 2 at N53 07.966 W006
28.075&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here you will find two dates which will give you an age. Call that
age BA.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Stage 3&lt;br /&gt;
You need to go back up to access the grass track to the mountain.
You may do this by retracing your steps or by cutting across
moorland more directly to reach Stage 3&lt;br /&gt;
at N53 07.289 W006 27.430&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here you need to answer how many holes are at the top of the stone
column on the side WITHOUT the inscription, in other words the side
&lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt; facing the lake. Call your answer H.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Continue on the track to the summit of Black Hill.&lt;br /&gt;
Stage 4&lt;br /&gt;
N53 07.317 W006 26.716&lt;br /&gt;
Here you will find 2 numbers. Call these (in ascending order)
FG.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The final cache coordinates should now take you in the direction of
the road and car park.&lt;br /&gt;
Final Cache N53 AB.CDE W006 26.FGH&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From Mountain Views:&lt;br /&gt;
Black Hill Mountain Wicklow County&lt;br /&gt;
Height: 602 metres OS 1/50k Mapsheet: 56 for top&lt;br /&gt;
Grid Ref: O04137 09033 Latitude: 53.121964 Longitude: -6.445273
ITM: 704063 709064&lt;br /&gt;
Black Hill is the 271st highest summit in Ireland.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
HAMPDEN BOMBER CRASH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
DUBLIN, IRELAND - On the night of 16th April, 1941, "...hour after
hour of fire-bombs rained down on London." (Belfast had been bombed
the previous night.) Next night a Handley Page Hampden S/N AD730
was detailed to bomb an aiming point at Berlin and was one of seven
from No. 50 squadron which took off from its base at Lindholme in
Yorkshire.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It was crewed by:&lt;br /&gt;
* P/O J. K. Hill, Captain 83253&lt;br /&gt;
* Sgt. J. T. Lamb, Navigator 744628&lt;br /&gt;
* Sgt. S. Wright, Wireless Operator/Air Gunner 751744&lt;br /&gt;
* Sgt. F. H. Erdwin, Air Gunner 553897&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It would appear that this crew did not reach Berlin; the the pilot,
J.K. Hill was not in a position to identify his target, due to haze
over Germany and opted for a secondary one, as he was not in
contact with the other planes. The bad weather encountered over the
North Sea was already crossing over the Continent, with no
improvement over Britain or to the West.&lt;br /&gt;
At 02.17 hours, Sgt. S. Wright (Wireless Operator) made contact and
was given a second class fix and bearing from Bircham Common. This
placed the aircraft approximately five miles SW of RAF
Watton.&lt;br /&gt;
For some unknown reason the Hampton Bomber continued flying West
--- possibly due to a compass malfunction. The bomber crossed the
Welsh mountains, which would seem to indicate that it was flying at
4000 feet. Its first movements over Ireland were reported by the
look-out posts on the East Coast at 04.05 hours while tracking
inland between Dalkey and Bray. The plane was reported flying west
towards Kildare. It then changed course, which brought it to an
East-Northeast position.&lt;br /&gt;
At 04.24 hours, Gardai at Hollywood, County Wicklow, reported an
aircraft in the area to Air Defence. According to the Department of
Defence, local people reported hearing a plane also. (The crew of
the Hampton SD730 who had survived that April night in the German
sky were to die only hours later on a lonelly hillside in Kyleberg
in neutral Ireland.) Investigators reached the conclusion that the
plane crashed ten minutes later, killing the crew instantly.&lt;br /&gt;
The instrument panel clocks found in the wreckage recorded the time
of the crash as 04.34 hours. The bodies of the victims lay in
Blackhill (Kyleberg) until Saturday 19th, when they were found by
turf-workers.&lt;br /&gt;
It must be remembered that the nearest telephone was in
Blessington, nearly six miles away, so it was late in the evening
when the Security Forces arrived on the scene. A military guard
from the Curragh and an ambulance made their way up the "Hill
Road." L.D.F. and Gardai stood on duty. Comdt. Harrington G (2)
Branch Curragh Command was also present. Air Corps officers under
Comdt. Murphy were standing by.&lt;br /&gt;
In his report to the Department of Defence (25/04/41) Comdt. Mackey
was lavish in his praise of the work of Superintendent Quinn, Supt.
Reynolds and Sgt. Bohan, Blessington. On Monday 21st April, 1941,
the Coroner for West Wicklow instructed that no inquest would be
held. His report to Comdt. Mackey stated: "The crew received
frightful injuries and death was instanteous in each case."&lt;br /&gt;
The funerals took place on Tuesday 22nd at St. Mary's Church,
Blessington. The coffins, wrapped in the British flag, were carried
to the church by soldiers escorted by a guard of honor and preceded
by the No. 3 Army Band. It was attended by the British
Representative, Sir John Maffey, with Lady Maffey and their
daughter, Mrs. Max Aitken. Also present was Mr. Leywood of the
British Legation, who had arrived in Blessington on Sunday 20th and
visited the scene of the crash.&lt;br /&gt;
Irish Army officers attending included Major P. Maher, representing
the Minister of Defence, and Comdt. E. Rooney, representing the
Chief of Staff.&lt;br /&gt;
The service was conducted by Rev. W.R. Crooks and the four bodies
were buried in the one grave. The Irish Times of 23rd April, 1941,
said, "During the funeral all shops in Blessington were closed and
blinds drawn on windows."&lt;br /&gt;
In his report to the Chief of Staff, Department of Defence,
(25/04/41) Comdt. D.J. Murphy, Air Corps Headquarters, wrote:&lt;br /&gt;
"Cause of crash: not known. The aircraft appeared to fly straight
into the side of the hill. Parts were scattered over a wide area.
The area where the Hampton crashed is about 1600 feet above O.D.,
rising sharply from around 620 feet."&lt;br /&gt;
Ironically, the motto of the 50th Squadron was "Sic fidem servamus"
(Thus we keep Faith). For those young airmen there was no glory of
D-Day. No honour of being shot down over enemy territory. Kyleberg
was their Armageddon.&lt;br /&gt;
For them the war was lost -- and won -- on Blackhill.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;font color="red"&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do not start the trek without
all the proper mountain rain gear, waterproof boots and the
guidance material, compass, map, GPSr with mapping etc. Please note
that all parts of this cache are hiked at your own risk. The cache
owner takes no responsibility of any sort for any reason including
accidents or mishaps.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;font color="red"&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Please be aware that cars parked
in areas close to walking trails are vulnerable and they can be
vandalised or stolen. Unfortunately this is an ongoing problem
which is extremely difficult to solve. so there is a risk
involved.&lt;br /&gt;
Please observe the country code to the best of your ability. Local
landowners often generously allow access to upland areas across or
through parts of their private property. Please, please be
conscious of this and return the courtesy by keeping all gates
closed, immediately and not on your way back!. Please use the gates
where appropriate but if you have to climb over them then use the
hinged side ONLY.&lt;br /&gt;
Please do not cause any damage of any sort to fences or barriers
along the way.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;P120978 - Garden 11 Parking Ballynultagh&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 08.294 W 006° 26.459&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;R120978 - Garden 11 Road Track&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 08.510 W 006° 27.314&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;R220978 - Garden 11 Corner&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 07.863 W 006° 27.324&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;S220978 - Garden 11 Stage 2&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 07.966 W 006° 28.075&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;S320978 - Garden 11 Stage 3&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 07.289 W 006° 27.430&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;S420978 - Garden 11 Stage 4&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 07.317 W 006° 26.716&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>Small boulder</groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="108959455">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-17T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1032462">theswerve</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Another great hike with great views over the lakes...found all stages ok...final no problem...TFTC...</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="103469861">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-10T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1224919">ljeh</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">My first of the series which I enjoyed very much. Co-ordinates for the stages are spot on. There are stunning views of the Blessington lakes so be sure to bring your camera. Thanks for a terrific cache, really looking forward to doing the rest of the series.</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="99482218">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-12T20:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="274644">Hezekiah</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">FTF!  Beautiful walk with great views, and not a little interest (particularly as a member of the Dublin &amp; District Motorcycle Club - if you do the walk you'll understand!).  Another little cracker in the series - thanks, Sean!</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="98991305">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-03-07T11:54:48Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Publish Listing</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1256091">Croaghan</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Published</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
