<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>007435</id>
  <cache-id>GCZRY9</cache-id>
  <type>Traditional Cache</type>
  <name>Bremore Castle by Windsockers, Traditional Cache (2/1)</name>
  <size>Not chosen</size>
  <difficulty>2</difficulty>
  <terrain>1</terrain>
  <last-found>2009-03-30</last-found>
  <placed>2006-12-16</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Windsockers</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.617617</lat>
  <lon>-6.190217</lon>
  <last-logs>FXXXF</last-logs>
  <owner>Windsockers</owner>
  <description><center>
<img src="http://img.geocaching.com/cache/d1464d52-52e0-4fb8-a198-9b188e09af7e.jpg" />
</center></description>
  <long-description><p>A short distance north of Balbriggan at Bremore, (High Hill),
lies the alleged site of a. seventh century church founded by a
native son of County Cork, namely Molaga, alternatively called
Lachinus. The legendary life of Molaga is recounted in several
manuscript and printed documents and while certain chronological
examples occur, his exploits are worth relating. Molaga was born in
the territory known as Feramugia, in North Cork and of the Darine
race. Deceased local historian, Paddy Daly, in an article published
on February, 9th, 1929 recounts the story of Molaga's miraculous
birth in the following way: "In the early years of the faith in
Ireland, it happened that St. Cummin the Tall and St. Cuman Mac de
Chearda were passing by a place called Aghacross, midway between
Mitchelstown and Kildorrey and in a field by the highway, they saw
an old couple sowing flax. St. Cumin wondered at an old couple
doing the work unaided and he asked them what brought about that
state of things. The man said "We are married more than thirty
years and it was the will of god not to give us any children. As
soon as we understood in our own minds that this was the will of
God we thought also that it was his will that we should spend our
lives in perfect chastity. We did so and with the help of God we
will finish our time in this world in the same way." Dubhlaigh and
Mionchulla were the names respectively of this man and woman. The
Saint spoke: "It is true that you will have spent your lives
according to the will of God and that which lie did not bestow on
you hitherto, he will do so now. God will give you a son and he
will have great and holy virtues, and he shall give good example to
all...." Paddy Daly continues: "Soon after their interview with the
saints, a wonderful change came over the old people. The
decrepitude of old age left them and the beauty and bloom of youth
returned ... In due time, Mionchulla gave birth to a son and that
child was Molaga."</p>
<p>Various sources relate that King Cuanna of Fermoy had the
parents and child brought to his palace and that multitudes came
from all parts to see the miraculous child. Molaga received a good
education and as a young man embarked on a missionary journey of
Scotland and Wales.</p>
<p>He supposedly spent twelve years studying in St. David's
monastery at Menevia, in southwest Wales. This monastery was
located in an isolated valley, which the Welsh called Glyn Rhosyn -
the Valley of the rose - in modern Pembrokeshire. Before returning
to Ireland, Molaga received a bell, called Boban Molaga, as a
present from St. David. Rev. John O'Hanlon, author of Lives of the
Irish Saints, published in 1875, casts some doubt as to whether
these two remarkable men actually met as die death of St. David is
generally placed at 592 AD!</p>
<p>The story continues with the return of Molaga to Ireland where
legend recalls that he healed a chieftain of the Canasta sept of an
ailment variously described as "a wasting illness" and as "leprosy
of the face. As a reward die grateful chieftain granted Molaga an
annual tribute and a tract of land allegedly near Bfemore in Fingal
36 where the saint built a church. According to Rev. OTlanlon,
Professor Brian O'Looney in his mss, Life of St. Molaga, states dm
this tribute amounted to a pingin (penny) from everyone in Dun
Dubhline, and was to be paid to Molaga every third year. At this
point, the story of Molaga becomes interwoven with that of St.
Modomnoc of Ossory.</p>
<p>Writer Margaret Mayo, author of a delightful little book
entitled Saints, Birds and Beasts, chronicles die story of Domnocs
long sojourn as gardener and beekeeper to St. David in Glyn Rhosyn.
In old age, a sorrowful Modomnoc was instructed to return to his
native Ireland by St. David. While setting out on his voyage a
swarm of his beloved bees thrice alighted on die mast of his little
vessel. Legend has it that St. David perceiving this occurrence to
be a good omen allowed Modomnoc to bring the bees to Ireland. It is
not clear how they found their way to Bremore. Perhaps Modomnoc
visited his friend Molaga ON his way home to Kilkenny. James K.
Watson, author of Bee-Keeping in Ireland: a history quotes an
article written by May Nevin, which appeared in The Imeldist,
March, 1952, in which she stated that Modomnoc returned to Wexford.
Where the Irish Abbot gave his new monk leave to build a hermitage,
around which the bees could live in peace and as time passed the
swarms increased and were sent to other places in Ireland.</p>
<p>What we do know is that Molaga's thriving bee culture at Bremore
gave rise to one of the most interesting place names in Irish
topography- The Church at Bremore was called Llan-Beach-Aire
(Church of the Beekeeper), an unusual amalgam of the Welsh and
Gaelic language.</p>
<p>Molaga later journeyed to Clonmacnois where he may have been a
teacher. While there, he was invited back to his native district
where he is reputed to have founded churches at Tulach Min
(Knockaneeun/ and at Teampall Molaga, near Kildorrery. A third
foundation, in the same district, called Leabba Malaga is said to
be his final resting place. His last and perhaps greatest
foundation was situated in Timoleague or Teach Molaga. Fr. James
Coombes, present Parish Priest of Timoleague, relates this
foundation in his booklet A History Of Timoleague and Barryroe,
published in 1969, in the following way: "Every school child in the
district knows the lovely legend of how he (St. Malaga), founded
his monastery in Timoleague. Molaga and his companions chose
several other places, but what they built by day fell by night. He
then took a lighted candle from the altar, placed it on a sheaf of
corn, and set it afloat on the waters of the Arigideen river or of
the bay and prayed that God would direct it to where he wished him
to build his church, they then followed the sheaf and candle; Tigh
Molaige, the house of Molaga, was built where the sheaf floated
ashore, on or near the site of the friary."</p>
<p>As to Bremore, we know that the Papal Bull of Pope Alexander III
dated April 20th, 1179, addressed to Archbishop Laurence OToole,
granted to the See of Dublin, Lusk and all that belonged to it,
including Bremore. In 1220, the first dismemberment of the mother
church of Lusk occurred with the appropriation of Baldungan,
Bremore and Balrothery churches to a leper hospital, dedicated to
St. Mary in 1192, situated at Kilbixey, near Tristernagh, in County
Westmeath. The powerful Anglo-Norman Barn wall family built a
castle sometime in the 14th century at Bremore on a site adjoining
the presumed site of Molaga's once famous foundation. John Dalton,
in his standard work, The History of the County Dublin (1838),
affords a brief description: "Here is a very handsome cottage of
Mr. Gilbert, opposite which in a farmyard, the wreck of the ancient
castle may be traced, on a site commanding a most extensive and
sublime prospect. Near it are the remains of the old church, within
which may be seen a stone, that seems to have formed the arching of
the castle doorway and bears the date 1689. On the ground in front
of the farmhouse is another stone of the same edifice, charged with
the armorial bearings of the families of Buriford, Howth and
Barnewall."</p>
<p>The Barnewalls at least prolonged the spirit of St. Molaga
during Penal Times by offering a safe house for hearing Mass and
Bishop Donnelly, author of Short Histories of Dublin Parishes tells
us that Rev. John Corcoran, PR between 1700 and 1725,was a life
long friend of the Barnewalls in whose castle at Bremore he usually
resided and there said Mass. Shortly after this period the lands of
Bremore passed to Viscount Landsdowne. The Butler and King families
farmed the lands of Bremore, and in the early 1980s Dublin County
Council purchased the lands from the Bell family. The Council
commissioned a conservation/restoration survey of the castle and
church graveyard site in 1991 following representations from
Balbriggan Historical and Cultural Society who were concerned with
the rapid deterioration of this most historic site. Accordingly, a
total reconstruction project started in 1994 and is now in full
swing involving F.A.S., Fingal County Council and Balbriggan and
District Historical Society. It is planned to restore the Castle,
discover the ancient monastic garden, feature and protect the
remaining artifacts located in the church/graveyard site, and
perhaps provide a small museum for exhibitions and displays of
local materials. In this way, perhaps the work and pastor ship of
Molaga and his successors may best be remembered.</p>
<p><b>The Cache</b></p>
<p>The cache is a small container with a log book and pen<br />
Please take care when retrieving and rehiding the cache to prevent
Muggles from discovering its existence</p>
<center>
<img src="http://www.northbeach.ie/gallery/albums/userpics/10001/windsock-anim-small.gif" />
<br />
<b>The Windsockers</b></center></long-description>
  <encoded-hints>
      </encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=70236de6-3f81-4e30-b6c9-8b562ee4edf7</url>
  <url-name>Bremore Castle</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-06-17T19:00:00Z : Found it by Petr Skacha <br />Found it with hint from owner within 3 minutes.
Log is bit soaked so we take the log home to dry and put in new log.
TFTC</li><li>2010-05-28T19:00:00Z : Didn't find it by Tranicka <br />Very good hide cache, we didn't find it :-(</li><li>2009-09-24T19:00:00Z : Didn't find it by Flidais <br />The cache was too well hidden, so we couldn't found it.

[V]</li><li>2009-09-24T19:00:00Z : Didn't find it by die eichhoernchen <br />No luck on this cache ...</li><li>2009-03-30T19:00:00Z : Found it by Moonshiner Extraordinaire <br />Having failed to find “Harry’s Cache”, I was in bad humour – as well as having sore & bleeding arms, hands & head. I visited the cemetery up the road and then, because I had ages to wait before the next bus city-wards, decided I might as well have a look-in at the “Bremore Castle” cache – which I had failed to find on numerous (very) occasions during 2007 & 2008. My Colorado went to ‘0’ in exactly the same place (thankfully) as my 12XL had on previous visits. This, however, was 7 metres from where I almost instantly found the cache today (at 14:22). God knows how many times I must have touched it during my previous attempts! It was very nicely hidden – and I was careful to leave it as I had found it. Go raibh maith agat faoi’n taisce.

Moonshiner X (cache #830)
</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.617617" lon="-6.190217">
    <time>2006-12-16T08:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GCZRY9</name>
    <desc>Bremore Castle by Windsockers, Traditional Cache (2/1)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=70236de6-3f81-4e30-b6c9-8b562ee4edf7</url>
    <urlname>Bremore Castle</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Traditional Cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="506582" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Bremore Castle</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Windsockers</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="271623">Windsockers</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Traditional Cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Not chosen</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>2</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Leinster</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src="http://img.geocaching.com/cache/d1464d52-52e0-4fb8-a198-9b188e09af7e.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;p&gt;A short distance north of Balbriggan at Bremore, (High Hill),
lies the alleged site of a. seventh century church founded by a
native son of County Cork, namely Molaga, alternatively called
Lachinus. The legendary life of Molaga is recounted in several
manuscript and printed documents and while certain chronological
examples occur, his exploits are worth relating. Molaga was born in
the territory known as Feramugia, in North Cork and of the Darine
race. Deceased local historian, Paddy Daly, in an article published
on February, 9th, 1929 recounts the story of Molaga's miraculous
birth in the following way: "In the early years of the faith in
Ireland, it happened that St. Cummin the Tall and St. Cuman Mac de
Chearda were passing by a place called Aghacross, midway between
Mitchelstown and Kildorrey and in a field by the highway, they saw
an old couple sowing flax. St. Cumin wondered at an old couple
doing the work unaided and he asked them what brought about that
state of things. The man said "We are married more than thirty
years and it was the will of god not to give us any children. As
soon as we understood in our own minds that this was the will of
God we thought also that it was his will that we should spend our
lives in perfect chastity. We did so and with the help of God we
will finish our time in this world in the same way." Dubhlaigh and
Mionchulla were the names respectively of this man and woman. The
Saint spoke: "It is true that you will have spent your lives
according to the will of God and that which lie did not bestow on
you hitherto, he will do so now. God will give you a son and he
will have great and holy virtues, and he shall give good example to
all...." Paddy Daly continues: "Soon after their interview with the
saints, a wonderful change came over the old people. The
decrepitude of old age left them and the beauty and bloom of youth
returned ... In due time, Mionchulla gave birth to a son and that
child was Molaga."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various sources relate that King Cuanna of Fermoy had the
parents and child brought to his palace and that multitudes came
from all parts to see the miraculous child. Molaga received a good
education and as a young man embarked on a missionary journey of
Scotland and Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He supposedly spent twelve years studying in St. David's
monastery at Menevia, in southwest Wales. This monastery was
located in an isolated valley, which the Welsh called Glyn Rhosyn -
the Valley of the rose - in modern Pembrokeshire. Before returning
to Ireland, Molaga received a bell, called Boban Molaga, as a
present from St. David. Rev. John O'Hanlon, author of Lives of the
Irish Saints, published in 1875, casts some doubt as to whether
these two remarkable men actually met as die death of St. David is
generally placed at 592 AD!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story continues with the return of Molaga to Ireland where
legend recalls that he healed a chieftain of the Canasta sept of an
ailment variously described as "a wasting illness" and as "leprosy
of the face. As a reward die grateful chieftain granted Molaga an
annual tribute and a tract of land allegedly near Bfemore in Fingal
36 where the saint built a church. According to Rev. OTlanlon,
Professor Brian O'Looney in his mss, Life of St. Molaga, states dm
this tribute amounted to a pingin (penny) from everyone in Dun
Dubhline, and was to be paid to Molaga every third year. At this
point, the story of Molaga becomes interwoven with that of St.
Modomnoc of Ossory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writer Margaret Mayo, author of a delightful little book
entitled Saints, Birds and Beasts, chronicles die story of Domnocs
long sojourn as gardener and beekeeper to St. David in Glyn Rhosyn.
In old age, a sorrowful Modomnoc was instructed to return to his
native Ireland by St. David. While setting out on his voyage a
swarm of his beloved bees thrice alighted on die mast of his little
vessel. Legend has it that St. David perceiving this occurrence to
be a good omen allowed Modomnoc to bring the bees to Ireland. It is
not clear how they found their way to Bremore. Perhaps Modomnoc
visited his friend Molaga ON his way home to Kilkenny. James K.
Watson, author of Bee-Keeping in Ireland: a history quotes an
article written by May Nevin, which appeared in The Imeldist,
March, 1952, in which she stated that Modomnoc returned to Wexford.
Where the Irish Abbot gave his new monk leave to build a hermitage,
around which the bees could live in peace and as time passed the
swarms increased and were sent to other places in Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we do know is that Molaga's thriving bee culture at Bremore
gave rise to one of the most interesting place names in Irish
topography- The Church at Bremore was called Llan-Beach-Aire
(Church of the Beekeeper), an unusual amalgam of the Welsh and
Gaelic language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molaga later journeyed to Clonmacnois where he may have been a
teacher. While there, he was invited back to his native district
where he is reputed to have founded churches at Tulach Min
(Knockaneeun/ and at Teampall Molaga, near Kildorrery. A third
foundation, in the same district, called Leabba Malaga is said to
be his final resting place. His last and perhaps greatest
foundation was situated in Timoleague or Teach Molaga. Fr. James
Coombes, present Parish Priest of Timoleague, relates this
foundation in his booklet A History Of Timoleague and Barryroe,
published in 1969, in the following way: "Every school child in the
district knows the lovely legend of how he (St. Malaga), founded
his monastery in Timoleague. Molaga and his companions chose
several other places, but what they built by day fell by night. He
then took a lighted candle from the altar, placed it on a sheaf of
corn, and set it afloat on the waters of the Arigideen river or of
the bay and prayed that God would direct it to where he wished him
to build his church, they then followed the sheaf and candle; Tigh
Molaige, the house of Molaga, was built where the sheaf floated
ashore, on or near the site of the friary."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to Bremore, we know that the Papal Bull of Pope Alexander III
dated April 20th, 1179, addressed to Archbishop Laurence OToole,
granted to the See of Dublin, Lusk and all that belonged to it,
including Bremore. In 1220, the first dismemberment of the mother
church of Lusk occurred with the appropriation of Baldungan,
Bremore and Balrothery churches to a leper hospital, dedicated to
St. Mary in 1192, situated at Kilbixey, near Tristernagh, in County
Westmeath. The powerful Anglo-Norman Barn wall family built a
castle sometime in the 14th century at Bremore on a site adjoining
the presumed site of Molaga's once famous foundation. John Dalton,
in his standard work, The History of the County Dublin (1838),
affords a brief description: "Here is a very handsome cottage of
Mr. Gilbert, opposite which in a farmyard, the wreck of the ancient
castle may be traced, on a site commanding a most extensive and
sublime prospect. Near it are the remains of the old church, within
which may be seen a stone, that seems to have formed the arching of
the castle doorway and bears the date 1689. On the ground in front
of the farmhouse is another stone of the same edifice, charged with
the armorial bearings of the families of Buriford, Howth and
Barnewall."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Barnewalls at least prolonged the spirit of St. Molaga
during Penal Times by offering a safe house for hearing Mass and
Bishop Donnelly, author of Short Histories of Dublin Parishes tells
us that Rev. John Corcoran, PR between 1700 and 1725,was a life
long friend of the Barnewalls in whose castle at Bremore he usually
resided and there said Mass. Shortly after this period the lands of
Bremore passed to Viscount Landsdowne. The Butler and King families
farmed the lands of Bremore, and in the early 1980s Dublin County
Council purchased the lands from the Bell family. The Council
commissioned a conservation/restoration survey of the castle and
church graveyard site in 1991 following representations from
Balbriggan Historical and Cultural Society who were concerned with
the rapid deterioration of this most historic site. Accordingly, a
total reconstruction project started in 1994 and is now in full
swing involving F.A.S., Fingal County Council and Balbriggan and
District Historical Society. It is planned to restore the Castle,
discover the ancient monastic garden, feature and protect the
remaining artifacts located in the church/graveyard site, and
perhaps provide a small museum for exhibitions and displays of
local materials. In this way, perhaps the work and pastor ship of
Molaga and his successors may best be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Cache&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cache is a small container with a log book and pen&lt;br /&gt;
Please take care when retrieving and rehiding the cache to prevent
Muggles from discovering its existence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.northbeach.ie/gallery/albums/userpics/10001/windsock-anim-small.gif" /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;The Windsockers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      </groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="113186150">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-17T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="821695">Petr Skacha</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found it with hint from owner within 3 minutes.
Log is bit soaked so we take the log home to dry and put in new log.
TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="113221016">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-28T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Didn't find it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2731117">Tranicka</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Very good hide cache, we didn't find it :-(</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="85625528">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-09-24T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Didn't find it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="801632">Flidais</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">The cache was too well hidden, so we couldn't found it.

[V]</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="85624264">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-09-24T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Didn't find it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="756748">die eichhoernchen</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">No luck on this cache ...</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="73252509">
          <groundspeak:date>2009-03-30T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="154025">Moonshiner Extraordinaire</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Having failed to find “Harry’s Cache”, I was in bad humour – as well as having sore &amp; bleeding arms, hands &amp; head. I visited the cemetery up the road and then, because I had ages to wait before the next bus city-wards, decided I might as well have a look-in at the “Bremore Castle” cache – which I had failed to find on numerous (very) occasions during 2007 &amp; 2008. My Colorado went to ‘0’ in exactly the same place (thankfully) as my 12XL had on previous visits. This, however, was 7 metres from where I almost instantly found the cache today (at 14:22). God knows how many times I must have touched it during my previous attempts! It was very nicely hidden – and I was careful to leave it as I had found it. Go raibh maith agat faoi’n taisce.

Moonshiner X (cache #830)
</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
