<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>008239</id>
  <cache-id>GC23CWD</cache-id>
  <type>Multi-cache</type>
  <name>Jailhouse Rock by Blue Jay 59, Multi-cache (2.5/1)</name>
  <size>Other</size>
  <difficulty>2.5</difficulty>
  <terrain>1</terrain>
  <last-found>2010-05-09</last-found>
  <placed>2010-01-27</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>Blue Jay 59</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.3421</lat>
  <lon>-6.309583</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFFW</last-logs>
  <owner>Blue Jay 59</owner>
  <description><p align="center"><a target="_blank" href=
"http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"><img border="0" src=
"http://geocachingireland.com/logo4.jpg" width="328" height="53"
align="middle" /></a></p>
<hr size="2" />
<br />
<center><font color="blue">Visit the Geocaching Ireland discussion
forum <a href=
"http://forums.geocachingireland.com/index.php?sid=d6c5add6c283f15152a98bb69176c028"
target="_blank">HERE</a></font></center></description>
  <long-description><br />
<br />
This is a short Multi cache &ndash; all stages are within walking
distance around Kilmainham.
<p>Disc parking is available in the area : 07.00 &ndash; 19.00
&ndash; Mon &ndash; Sat.</p>
<p><b>Kilmainham</b> (<b><i>Cill Mhaighneann</i></b> in Irish,
meaning "St Maighneann's church") is a suburb of Dublin - An area
of great historical interest, it is bounded by the river Liffey and
the Grand Canal and also has the little Camac flowing through it.
Kilmainham lies about three miles west of the city centre, in the
Dublin 8 postal district. The Celts settled in Kilmainham about
2,000 years ago to take advantage of a ford across the Camac, the
local river. The Vikings also established a community and their
largest graveyard outside Scandinavia was found in Kilmainham.</p>
<p>Of interest in this area are Kilmainham Gaol, Kilmainham
Courthouse, The Royal Hospital, The Richmond Gate, and The War
Memorial Gardens, to name but a few. The stages of the cache will
bring you to some of these sites.</p>
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c22a69e0-4c2f-4237-9f27-cf4767a48e8c.jpg" /></center>
<p><b>Kilmainham Gaol</b> (Irish: <b><i>Pr&iacute;os&uacute;n Chill
Mhaighneann</i></b>) operated as a prison for over 130 years. It
played an important part in Irish history, as many leaders of Irish
rebellions were imprisoned here - many famous Nationalists and
Republicans, members of the Society of United Irishmen (1798),
Young Irelanders (c1840s), Fenians and Land agitators, Parnell,
Davitt and of course the leaders of the 1916 Rising. There were
many executions in the jail by the British and latterly in 1923 by
the Irish Free State.</p>
<p>When it was first built in 1787, Kilmainham Gaol was called the
'New Gaol' to distinguish it from the old jail it was intended to
replace - a noisome dungeon, just a few hundred yards from the
present site. It was officially called the County of Dublin Gaol,
and was originally run by the Grand Jury for County Dublin.</p>
<p>Before you even enter the building you get a hint of its macabre
past.Public hangings took place at the front of the Gaol. The
balcony over the front door entrance was used as a gibbet for the
hangings. Children were sometimes arrested for petty theft, the
youngest said to be a seven year-old boy, while many of the adult
prisoners were deported to Australia. There was no segregation of
prisoners; men, women and children were incarcerated up to 5 in
each cell, with only a single candle for light and heat, most of
their time was spent in the cold and the dark.</p>
<p>Over the years, its cells held many of the most famous people
involved in the campaign for Irish independence. The British
imprisoned and executed the leaders of the 1916 Easter Rising
here.The most famous, or infamous, executions of all in Kilmainham
were those of fourteen of the leaders of the failed 1916 Easter
Rising. These took place in May 1916, in the early hours of the
morning in the Stonebreaker&rsquo;s Yard. Among them was leader of
the Rising Padraig Pearse and his brother William, James Connolly,
Eamon Ceannt and Sean McDermott. Stark black crosses now mark the
places where these deaths occurred.</p>
<p>While the Easter Rising ended in failure, the execution of those
involved was a disaster for the British as it rallied even those
who had opposed the Rising to the cause of Irish Freedom and
eventually led to the formation of the Irish Free State in 1921.
During the Civil war executions of anti-treaty Republican prisoners
took place. Kilmainham Gaol was abandoned as a gaol in 1924, by the
government of the new Irish Free State. It wasn&rsquo;t until the
1960s that efforts began to preserve it and open it again to the
public. It opened in time for the 50th anniversary of the 1916
Rising and is now one of the most popular tourist destinations in
Dublin. It now houses a museum on the history of Irish nationalism
and offers guided tours of the building. An art gallery on the top
floor exhibits paintings, sculptures and jewellery of prisoners
incarcerated in jails all over Ireland.</p>
<p>The following films have been filmed at Kilmainham Gaol: The
Quare Fellow, The Face of Fu Manchu, The Italian Job, The
MacKintosh Man, The Whistle Blower, In the Name of the Father,
Michael Collins,The 24 Movie, The Escapist, and others. A music
video for the U2 song A Celebration was filmed in Kilmainham jail
in 1982.I highly recommend a visit to this site.</p>
<p><b>Proclamation &ndash; Rowan Gillespie</b></p>
<br />
<img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/3c13fcc2-4ba0-476b-a717-ab3972e61cc1.jpg"
align="right" />
<p style="text-align:left">Fourteen figures stand in a megalithic
circle, blindfolded, as they would be for execution. The figures
are limbless, but far from lifeless. At the centre is a plaque
containing a copy of the Proclamation of Independence, engraved in
bronze. Each figure has at its base a small plaque, engraved with
the British military tribunal&rsquo;s verdict and sentence of
death. The figures are perforated with bullet holes. Since the
original commission was for the seven signatories of the
Proclamation, Gillespie has donated the other seven martyrs to the
site himself.</p>
<p>Proclamation is a monument to those who gave their lives to
change the course of Irish history and release the dreams of the
Irish people: and it is a reminder, of those whose light burns so
strongly, it awakens the imagination of us all.</p>
<p><i>No man has a right to fix the boundary of the march of a
nation; no man has a right to say to his country, Thus far shalt
thou go and no further&hellip;</i> Charles Stewart
Parnell&hellip;</p>
<p><b>Kilmainham Courthouse</b></p>
<br />
<img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/4a8624e2-2dd6-4119-a494-c8b6fae8728b.jpg"
align="left" />
<p style="text-align:right">Built in 1820 to replace an older
structure, the courthouse is sited next to the former gaol. The
building is finished with austere stonework and the Royal
coat-of-arms in the pediment. Closed in July 2008, it is planned to
become a legal museum. Now the Celtric Tiger has stopped roaring,
one wonders if projects like this will ever be completed.</p>
<p><b>Richmond Tower / Gate:</b></p>
<br />
<img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/1e927ee8-d915-4a98-8fcf-6fe895ad5e3a.jpg"
align="right" />
<p style="text-align:left">When you reach the gateway look through
at the rather dramatic avenue to the Royal Hospital / IMMA. The
gateway, known as the Richmond Tower, has an intriguing history.
This tower was not built for the Royal Hospital at all but once
stood much nearer to the city centre at the junction of Watling
Street and Victoria Quay, as a symbolic western gateway to the city
of Dublin. When the railway terminal at nearby Kingsbridge Station
(now Heuston) opened in 1846, the resultant increase in traffic
caused congestion daily at the gatehouse junction. Traffic
problems, even in 1846! It was taken down in 1847 and relocated a
short distance away to it's present position.</p>
<p>Designed by Francis Johnston, it was built of Dublin granite. He
had placed his personal coat of arms above the arch, concealed by a
piece of wood painted to match the stone, his idea being that his
arms would be revealed to future generations after the wood became
rotten. However, his little trick was uncovered when the gateway
was taken down for removal. The coat of arms at present on the
gateway is that of the Royal Hospital.</p>
<br />
<p><b>Bully's Acre & The Royal Hospital</b> Through the gateway
are the grounds of The Royal Hospital &ndash; now IMMA, The Irish
Museum of Modern Art, it&rsquo;s gardens, several graveyards
(graves of the soldiers the hospital was built for) and Bully's
Acre. Bully&rsquo;s Acre (actually 3.7 acres) is one of Dublin's
oldest cemeteries, dating back to the 6th/7th century. A 10th
century standing stone still stands here. Robert Emmet, the leader
of the 1803 rebellion was buried overnight here, after his
execution, but his final resting place is unknown. The cemetery was
very busy during the great Cholera Epidemic of 1832 and until it
was closed, it remained popular with the poor, as it was common
ground, and there was no charge for burials.</p>
<br />
<p><b>The Cache</b></p>
<p>Stage 1:<br />
How many windows are blocked on the 2nd level? Answer = A<br />
Patrick banished them, George slayed one, but how many altogether
are here in chains? Answer = B</p>
<p>Stage 2:<br />
How many were sentenced to 'Death by being shot'? Answer = C<br />
How many have 5? Answer = D</p>
<p>Stage 3:<br />
Both are fierce but how many letters in the name of the
mythological one? Answer = E<br />
Around the side, how many steps to go in? Answer = F</p>
<p>Stage 4:<br />
How many bars? Answer = G<br />
What number on the Patriots Bar? Answer = H</p>
<p>The cache can be found at:<br />
<br />
N C*E+A &nbsp;&nbsp;A*D. H*2+E+G<br />
<br />
W 0F G*3. (B^4) - [(D^2)*A]<br />
<br />
Please watch out for muggles</p></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>S223CWD - GC23CWD - Stage 2<br />N 53° 20.535 W 006° 18.572<br /><br />S323CWD - GC23CWD - Stage 3<br />N 53° 20.517 W 006° 18.509<br /><br />S423CWD - GC23CWD - Stage 4<br />N 53° 20.517 W 006° 18.458<br /><br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:S223CWD|waypoints:cache-id:S323CWD|waypoints:cache-id:S423CWD</links>
  <encoded-hints>
      </encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=c8ad172f-cbaa-4f51-bf36-3957106978d5</url>
  <url-name>Jailhouse Rock</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-06-13T19:00:00Z : Found it by daraconn <br />Having gone into town to find the final of Geometricache, and some shopping, we decided to do this one on the way home. My wife was pleased that all the stages are quite close together, so it didn't involve a lot of walking. Most of the stages and questions were straightforward enough. However when we did the calculations it seemed we had the wrong number for "E". The result was obviously wrong and we made the correction.

Our calculated final co-ordinates were about 30-40 metres from where I found the cache. It could well be that we went wrong somewhere along the way, but it may be worth the cache owner paying a visit to recheck the numbers and the final co-ordinates. The high stone walls can play havoc with GPS signals.

Thank you for a cache of great historical interest, Dara.</li><li>2010-06-02T19:00:00Z : Found it by eve1987 <br />[:D][8D][}:)] 

Most of the answers we had to guess when we started calculating ... But when you nearly know where to go - it works!

Nice box, but the logbook is wet!

TFTC, eve</li><li>2010-06-02T19:00:00Z : Found it by GudrunXY <br />Found with eve1987 on our caching tour through Ireland.
While we had no idea what we were looking for or should count more or less the whole time, we are excellent at guessing and arguing over the right amounts. [;)] The final cords we guessed lead us directly to the well hidden cache. [^]
Thanks for showing us this part of the history.

TFTC GudrunXY</li><li>2010-05-14T19:00:00Z : Found it by lamm4 <br />The walk to the jailhous was very nice. The stages beside stage 3 (we should had pay more attention during school [;)]), were possible to do, and for the west co-ords one shouldn't argue very long [;)]. TFTC # 132</li><li>2010-05-09T19:00:00Z : Write note by AbbeyAckbar <br />I was trying to find my way to the war memorial park nearby when I missed the turn off and found myself closer to this cache [:)] so I pulled over to have a look at the description and like Moonshiner's log I discovered that my Colorado 300 had only recorded the description to a certain point and there was no info. about the stages or the cache location. I didn't know it did that [:o)] Another time so...</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.3421" lon="-6.309583">
    <time>2010-01-27T08:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GC23CWD</name>
    <desc>Jailhouse Rock by Blue Jay 59, Multi-cache (2.5/1)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=c8ad172f-cbaa-4f51-bf36-3957106978d5</url>
    <urlname>Jailhouse Rock</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Multi-cache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="1537677" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>Jailhouse Rock</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>Blue Jay 59</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="2709154">Blue Jay 59</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Multi-cache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Other</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>2.5</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>1</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Dublin</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href=
"http://www.geocachingireland.com/index.html"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src=
"http://geocachingireland.com/logo4.jpg" width="328" height="53"
align="middle" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr size="2" /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;font color="blue"&gt;Visit the Geocaching Ireland discussion
forum &lt;a href=
"http://forums.geocachingireland.com/index.php?sid=d6c5add6c283f15152a98bb69176c028"
target="_blank"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is a short Multi cache &amp;ndash; all stages are within walking
distance around Kilmainham.
&lt;p&gt;Disc parking is available in the area : 07.00 &amp;ndash; 19.00
&amp;ndash; Mon &amp;ndash; Sat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kilmainham&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cill Mhaighneann&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; in Irish,
meaning "St Maighneann's church") is a suburb of Dublin - An area
of great historical interest, it is bounded by the river Liffey and
the Grand Canal and also has the little Camac flowing through it.
Kilmainham lies about three miles west of the city centre, in the
Dublin 8 postal district. The Celts settled in Kilmainham about
2,000 years ago to take advantage of a ford across the Camac, the
local river. The Vikings also established a community and their
largest graveyard outside Scandinavia was found in Kilmainham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of interest in this area are Kilmainham Gaol, Kilmainham
Courthouse, The Royal Hospital, The Richmond Gate, and The War
Memorial Gardens, to name but a few. The stages of the cache will
bring you to some of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c22a69e0-4c2f-4237-9f27-cf4767a48e8c.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kilmainham Gaol&lt;/b&gt; (Irish: &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pr&amp;iacute;os&amp;uacute;n Chill
Mhaighneann&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;) operated as a prison for over 130 years. It
played an important part in Irish history, as many leaders of Irish
rebellions were imprisoned here - many famous Nationalists and
Republicans, members of the Society of United Irishmen (1798),
Young Irelanders (c1840s), Fenians and Land agitators, Parnell,
Davitt and of course the leaders of the 1916 Rising. There were
many executions in the jail by the British and latterly in 1923 by
the Irish Free State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was first built in 1787, Kilmainham Gaol was called the
'New Gaol' to distinguish it from the old jail it was intended to
replace - a noisome dungeon, just a few hundred yards from the
present site. It was officially called the County of Dublin Gaol,
and was originally run by the Grand Jury for County Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you even enter the building you get a hint of its macabre
past.Public hangings took place at the front of the Gaol. The
balcony over the front door entrance was used as a gibbet for the
hangings. Children were sometimes arrested for petty theft, the
youngest said to be a seven year-old boy, while many of the adult
prisoners were deported to Australia. There was no segregation of
prisoners; men, women and children were incarcerated up to 5 in
each cell, with only a single candle for light and heat, most of
their time was spent in the cold and the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, its cells held many of the most famous people
involved in the campaign for Irish independence. The British
imprisoned and executed the leaders of the 1916 Easter Rising
here.The most famous, or infamous, executions of all in Kilmainham
were those of fourteen of the leaders of the failed 1916 Easter
Rising. These took place in May 1916, in the early hours of the
morning in the Stonebreaker&amp;rsquo;s Yard. Among them was leader of
the Rising Padraig Pearse and his brother William, James Connolly,
Eamon Ceannt and Sean McDermott. Stark black crosses now mark the
places where these deaths occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Easter Rising ended in failure, the execution of those
involved was a disaster for the British as it rallied even those
who had opposed the Rising to the cause of Irish Freedom and
eventually led to the formation of the Irish Free State in 1921.
During the Civil war executions of anti-treaty Republican prisoners
took place. Kilmainham Gaol was abandoned as a gaol in 1924, by the
government of the new Irish Free State. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the
1960s that efforts began to preserve it and open it again to the
public. It opened in time for the 50th anniversary of the 1916
Rising and is now one of the most popular tourist destinations in
Dublin. It now houses a museum on the history of Irish nationalism
and offers guided tours of the building. An art gallery on the top
floor exhibits paintings, sculptures and jewellery of prisoners
incarcerated in jails all over Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following films have been filmed at Kilmainham Gaol: The
Quare Fellow, The Face of Fu Manchu, The Italian Job, The
MacKintosh Man, The Whistle Blower, In the Name of the Father,
Michael Collins,The 24 Movie, The Escapist, and others. A music
video for the U2 song A Celebration was filmed in Kilmainham jail
in 1982.I highly recommend a visit to this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Proclamation &amp;ndash; Rowan Gillespie&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/3c13fcc2-4ba0-476b-a717-ab3972e61cc1.jpg"
align="right" /&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;Fourteen figures stand in a megalithic
circle, blindfolded, as they would be for execution. The figures
are limbless, but far from lifeless. At the centre is a plaque
containing a copy of the Proclamation of Independence, engraved in
bronze. Each figure has at its base a small plaque, engraved with
the British military tribunal&amp;rsquo;s verdict and sentence of
death. The figures are perforated with bullet holes. Since the
original commission was for the seven signatories of the
Proclamation, Gillespie has donated the other seven martyrs to the
site himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proclamation is a monument to those who gave their lives to
change the course of Irish history and release the dreams of the
Irish people: and it is a reminder, of those whose light burns so
strongly, it awakens the imagination of us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;No man has a right to fix the boundary of the march of a
nation; no man has a right to say to his country, Thus far shalt
thou go and no further&amp;hellip;&lt;/i&gt; Charles Stewart
Parnell&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kilmainham Courthouse&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/4a8624e2-2dd6-4119-a494-c8b6fae8728b.jpg"
align="left" /&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right"&gt;Built in 1820 to replace an older
structure, the courthouse is sited next to the former gaol. The
building is finished with austere stonework and the Royal
coat-of-arms in the pediment. Closed in July 2008, it is planned to
become a legal museum. Now the Celtric Tiger has stopped roaring,
one wonders if projects like this will ever be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Richmond Tower / Gate:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/1e927ee8-d915-4a98-8fcf-6fe895ad5e3a.jpg"
align="right" /&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;When you reach the gateway look through
at the rather dramatic avenue to the Royal Hospital / IMMA. The
gateway, known as the Richmond Tower, has an intriguing history.
This tower was not built for the Royal Hospital at all but once
stood much nearer to the city centre at the junction of Watling
Street and Victoria Quay, as a symbolic western gateway to the city
of Dublin. When the railway terminal at nearby Kingsbridge Station
(now Heuston) opened in 1846, the resultant increase in traffic
caused congestion daily at the gatehouse junction. Traffic
problems, even in 1846! It was taken down in 1847 and relocated a
short distance away to it's present position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designed by Francis Johnston, it was built of Dublin granite. He
had placed his personal coat of arms above the arch, concealed by a
piece of wood painted to match the stone, his idea being that his
arms would be revealed to future generations after the wood became
rotten. However, his little trick was uncovered when the gateway
was taken down for removal. The coat of arms at present on the
gateway is that of the Royal Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bully's Acre &amp;amp; The Royal Hospital&lt;/b&gt; Through the gateway
are the grounds of The Royal Hospital &amp;ndash; now IMMA, The Irish
Museum of Modern Art, it&amp;rsquo;s gardens, several graveyards
(graves of the soldiers the hospital was built for) and Bully's
Acre. Bully&amp;rsquo;s Acre (actually 3.7 acres) is one of Dublin's
oldest cemeteries, dating back to the 6th/7th century. A 10th
century standing stone still stands here. Robert Emmet, the leader
of the 1803 rebellion was buried overnight here, after his
execution, but his final resting place is unknown. The cemetery was
very busy during the great Cholera Epidemic of 1832 and until it
was closed, it remained popular with the poor, as it was common
ground, and there was no charge for burials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Cache&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stage 1:&lt;br /&gt;
How many windows are blocked on the 2nd level? Answer = A&lt;br /&gt;
Patrick banished them, George slayed one, but how many altogether
are here in chains? Answer = B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stage 2:&lt;br /&gt;
How many were sentenced to 'Death by being shot'? Answer = C&lt;br /&gt;
How many have 5? Answer = D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stage 3:&lt;br /&gt;
Both are fierce but how many letters in the name of the
mythological one? Answer = E&lt;br /&gt;
Around the side, how many steps to go in? Answer = F&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stage 4:&lt;br /&gt;
How many bars? Answer = G&lt;br /&gt;
What number on the Patriots Bar? Answer = H&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cache can be found at:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
N C*E+A &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;A*D. H*2+E+G&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
W 0F G*3. (B^4) - [(D^2)*A]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Please watch out for muggles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;S223CWD - GC23CWD - Stage 2&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.535 W 006° 18.572&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;S323CWD - GC23CWD - Stage 3&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.517 W 006° 18.509&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;S423CWD - GC23CWD - Stage 4&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 20.517 W 006° 18.458&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      </groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="112675928">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-13T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="591662">daraconn</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Having gone into town to find the final of Geometricache, and some shopping, we decided to do this one on the way home. My wife was pleased that all the stages are quite close together, so it didn't involve a lot of walking. Most of the stages and questions were straightforward enough. However when we did the calculations it seemed we had the wrong number for "E". The result was obviously wrong and we made the correction.

Our calculated final co-ordinates were about 30-40 metres from where I found the cache. It could well be that we went wrong somewhere along the way, but it may be worth the cache owner paying a visit to recheck the numbers and the final co-ordinates. The high stone walls can play havoc with GPS signals.

Thank you for a cache of great historical interest, Dara.</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="111881918">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-02T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1617792">eve1987</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">[:D][8D][}:)] 

Most of the answers we had to guess when we started calculating ... But when you nearly know where to go - it works!

Nice box, but the logbook is wet!

TFTC, eve</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="111277177">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-06-02T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2694097">GudrunXY</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Found with eve1987 on our caching tour through Ireland.
While we had no idea what we were looking for or should count more or less the whole time, we are excellent at guessing and arguing over the right amounts. [;)] The final cords we guessed lead us directly to the well hidden cache. [^]
Thanks for showing us this part of the history.

TFTC GudrunXY</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="108399226">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-14T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1932037">lamm4</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">The walk to the jailhous was very nice. The stages beside stage 3 (we should had pay more attention during school [;)]), were possible to do, and for the west co-ords one shouldn't argue very long [;)]. TFTC # 132</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="107834577">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-09T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Write note</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1265839">AbbeyAckbar</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">I was trying to find my way to the war memorial park nearby when I missed the turn off and found myself closer to this cache [:)] so I pulled over to have a look at the description and like Moonshiner's log I discovered that my Colorado 300 had only recorded the description to a certain point and there was no info. about the stages or the cache location. I didn't know it did that [:o)] Another time so...</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
