<?xml version="1.0"?>
<celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
<element>
  <id>009807</id>
  <cache-id>GC23ETC</cache-id>
  <type>Earthcache</type>
  <name>White Rock, Killiney Bay by AbbeyAckbar, Earthcache (2/2.5)</name>
  <size>Not chosen</size>
  <difficulty>2</difficulty>
  <terrain>2.5</terrain>
  <last-found>2010-04-03</last-found>
  <placed>2010-02-02</placed>
  <gpx-date>2010-06-21</gpx-date>
  <placedby>AbbeyAckbar</placedby>
  <found>Geocache</found>
  <lat>53.266</lat>
  <lon>-6.106667</lon>
  <last-logs>FFFFF</last-logs>
  <owner>AbbeyAckbar</owner>
  <description><p><b>Killiney</b></p>
<p>The coastal areas of Killiney are often compared to the Bay of
Naples in Italy. This comparison is reflected in the names of
surrounding roads, like Vico, Sorrento, Monte Alverno, San Elmo,
and Capri. This EarthCache brings you to Vico Road where there is
magnificent views over Killiney Bay, Bray Head and the Great Sugar
Loaf mountain.</p></description>
  <long-description><p>Parking is available halfway along the Vico Road (waypoint
provided). There are several paths from here that all lead down
over the railway line and down the steep steps onto Whiterock
beach. I have provided waypoints for these paths near the parking
area. Here you will see close up, the dramatic contact between two
contrasting rock types at Whiterock, but first, a little
information about rocks.</p>
<p><b>Rocks</b></p>
<p>The scientific study of rocks is called petrology.<br />
Rocks are named according to the way in which they were formed.
There are 3 types:</p>
<p><b>- Igneous<br />
- Sedimentary<br />
- Metamorphic</b></p>
<p><b>Igneous</b> (from the Latin "ignis" - fire)<br />
Igneous rocks originates from molten matter deep inside the earth.
Hot magma (liquid rock) comes up through cracks in the
earth&rsquo;s surface and fills other cracks or forms a layer on
the surface. It then cools forming a very hard igneous rock.</p>
<p><b>Sedimentary</b> (from the latin word meaning to settle)<br />
Sedimentary rock is formed from broken bits and pieces of different
rocks. The three most common forms of sedimentary rock are
limestone, sandstone and shale. Sedimentary rocks are very
important as three quarters of the mass of the continents are
covered with a thin layer of them, and concentrated within them are
important resources such as coal, oil, groundwater and iron
ore.</p>
<p><b>Metamorphic</b> (from two greek words meaning change and
form)<br />
Metamorphic rocks formed from igneous or sedimentary rocks that
have been changed into a new rock. They form as a result of high
pressures or temperatures. Sandstone gets changed into quartzite
and limestone gets changed into marble. These new rocks are not as
hard as igneous rock but can be very heavy. Slate, schist, gneiss
and quartzite are other examples.</p>
<p>The three rock types are transformed into one another by
processes of weathering and erosion, melting and exposure to heat
and pressure.</p>
<p><b>Rocks at Whiterock</b></p>
<p>Killiney Hill is composed of an igneous rock called granite,
which cooled from a molten magma forced up into the surrounding
shales during the Devonian geological period (around 400 million
years ago). Where the granite heated the adjacent shales, a new
type of (metamorphic) rock called schist was formed. Both granite
and schist have proved quite resistant to erosional forces over
time.</p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/643d19cd-f26d-47ec-a9aa-7e00d86b4220.jpg" /></center>
<p>At Whiterock you can see close-up, an outcrop of rocks which
shows the contact between the granite of Killiney Hill & the
adjacent Ordovician mica-schists. The Ordovician period of
geological time is about 475 million years ago. Here you are seeing
the original relationship between the rocks from the time of the
granite intrusion. The rocks against which the granite abuts are
called mica-schists, characterised by thin, parallel bedding planes
along which the rock tends to split. Extreme heat from the granite
intrusion metamorphosed what were originally compacted sandstones
& mudstones from the Iapetus sea floor, into schists. (Iapetus
was a deep ancient ocean of the Ordovician period.) Shiny
plate-like crystals of mica are orientated along the bedding planes
as a result of pressure from the granite. New minerals such as
garnet and andalusite also formed in the zone of metamorphism (the
area where the two rocks contact each other). The andalusite can be
picked out as a dark criss-cross pattern of crystals covering the
bedding planes of the mica-schists.</p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c83b94f8-e349-4d31-9026-c5212c124a8c.jpg" /></center>
<center>
<p><b>Andalusite crystals on a mica-schist bedding plane</b></p>
</center>
<p>When viewed closely, the granite can be seen to be composed of
three main minerals which occur as grains a few millimetres across;
glassy grey quartz, white feldspar and shiny plate-like micas,
which impart the glint to the rock. The granite was worked from a
quarry on the Dalkey side of the hill for the construction of the
Dun Laoghaire harbour piers between 1817 and 1859. Six million
tonnes of granite were transported along a straight narrow-gauge
tramway, the line of which still exists in places as the 'Metals'
pathway.</p>
<p><b>Pebbles on the beach</b></p>
<p>Most of the pebbles have come from the glacial cliffs behind
killiney beach, having been plucked as fragments from various rock
formations near and far, and carried by ice age glaciers as they
scoured the landscape. The fragments have been rounded and smoothed
from the wave action of the sea. They represent a stage in the
ongoing tectonic rock cycle of igneous intrusion, mountain
building, erosion, sedimentation of the detritus, compaction,
deformation and metamorphism.</p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/d8a0d675-e51c-48c7-819b-f0927901c75d.jpg" /></center>
<p>Looking at these pebbles is a good way of seeing a variety of
rocks, minerals and fossils that make up the three rock groups
known as sedimentary, igneous and metamorphic. Take a look for
yourself and see what you can find.There is an abundance of
beautiful coloured pebbles to find on the beach. We took these
photos of the pebbles that we found during one of our trips
there.</p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/b78f034c-252f-4875-a777-9d2816500a8a.jpg" /></center>
<br />
<p><b>The Abandoned Mine</b></p>
<p>The contact between intruded granites and their surrounding
'country' rocks is significant in that this is also the site of
economically important mineralisation. A short distance northwards
from the granite-schist contact, there is an old mine entrance in
the cliff (it is unsafe to enter),that can be seen when the tide is
out, where lead and copper was worked sporadically during the
1750's and 1820's.</p>
<br />
<center><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/4583f0aa-dacf-44ca-a20b-ec49568a7f12.jpg" /></center>
<p><b>Note :</b> Close inspection of the rocky part of the beach is
tidal dependent. You can check the tides <a href=
"http://www.irishtimes.com/weather/tides.html">HERE</a> It isn't
necessary to time your visit for the exact time of low tide, just
be aware of when the tide is coming in and going out. Remember
safety first! : )</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>To log your visit</b></p>
<p style="color:darkgreen">Please email the following to
geocaching@thyme-it.ie :</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>1.</b>Describe and compare the
colour, texture and appearance between the schists and the
granite.</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>2.</b>Look for and measure the
andalusite. Please take a photograph of your find.</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><b>3.</b> With your back to the sea, how
many man made stone arches do you see?</p>
<p style="color:darkgreen">The following is optional and <b>NOT</b>
a requirement to log your visit - Feel free to upload any photos
you take during your visit to the earthcache site providing they
don't give away the answers to the logging requirements.</p>
<center>
<p style="color:darkgreen"><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/9ad353ba-760c-4a56-8a5a-9facf75f224b.jpg" /><font size="4"><b>HAPPY
EARTHCACHING!</b></font><img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/9ad353ba-760c-4a56-8a5a-9facf75f224b.jpg" /></p>
</center>
<br />
<br />
<center>
<table>
<tr>
<td align='center'>I am a proud</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align='center'><a href='http://www.earthcache.org'><img src=
'http://img.geocaching.com/user/e01b4330-2470-4531-a05d-2662bb4def80.jpg'
border='0' /></a></td>
</tr>
</table>
<br />
<a href="http://s06.flagcounter.com/more/Dv5"><img src=
"http://s06.flagcounter.com/count/Dv5/bg=CFCFCF/txt=1D6B18/border=1D6B18/columns=6/maxflags=60/viewers=3/labels=0/"
alt="free counters" border="0" /></a></center></long-description>
  <additional-waypoints>W123ETC - Path to White Rock<br />N 53° 16.087 W 006° 06.228<br />Access point to path that leads to White Rock<br />W223ETC - Path to White Rock<br />N 53° 16.059 W 006° 06.303<br />Access point to path that leads to White Rock<br />W323ETC - Path to White Rock<br />N 53° 16.034 W 006° 06.384<br />Access point to path that leads to White Rock<br />W423ETC - Parking for White Rock<br />N 53° 16.040 W 006° 06.357<br />Parking area along Vico Road<br /></additional-waypoints>
  <links>waypoints:cache-id:W123ETC|waypoints:cache-id:W223ETC|waypoints:cache-id:W323ETC|waypoints:cache-id:W423ETC</links>
  <encoded-hints>
      </encoded-hints>
  <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=97c948f7-0503-4b91-a75c-b530de801951</url>
  <url-name>White Rock, Killiney Bay</url-name>
  <logs><ul><li>2010-05-28T19:00:00Z : Found it by daraconn <br />I think this is my first earth-cache! I ran down all the steps to the beach with the dog. I found it very interesting to see the boundary between the granite and schist, and also the way the schist layers (originally laid down as horizontal layers on the sea floor) had been folded into a vertical orientation.

My father was a geography teacher before he retired, and when I was a boy he would always point out these features, and explain the different kinds of rock. But I had never before heard of andalusite, and it was fun to look closer and discover it. It was also interesting to see the veins of quartz.

Thanks for a very interesting and educational cache!</li><li>2010-04-09T19:00:00Z : Found it by didi2206 <br />Me and the dogs took advantage of low tide at a nice time of day for walking the beach... not sure if i saw the actual rocks required but did my best. had to wait a bit for some of the swimmers to get dressed- they seem to like to " air dry" in the very alcoves where the rocks we need are located!! </li><li>2010-04-04T19:00:00Z : Found it by Balla & Silly <br />After we knew when the tide would be low we visited this nice Earthcache in the late morning, arriving from Dublin with the DART. It was a nice ride with the train along the coast and the walk to the White Rock was also very enjoyable. When we got off the train and down to the beach we started walking and weren't sure if we could go all the way along the beach or if some cliffs would stop us before reaching the final destination. So we decided to go upstairs again and followed the road until waypoint 3 where we went down to the beach again. There we saw that this extra way wasn't necessary but we didn't regret it. We had some nice views on our way and later we went back to the DART station along the beach. 
At the White Rock we had a long and good look around, only disturbed by...well, the owners know. [:I]
Great to see all these different kind of rocks and stones, we could have spent much more time there! It must be packed in summer but that day there were only a few more visitors there and we loved to stroll around in bright sunshine.
Thanks a real lot for another great Earthcache and the log permission,
many regards,
Balla & Silly</li><li>2010-04-03T19:00:00Z : Found it by Hellynka <br />I found it with Lenik1 who send all required answers and photo. TFTC:)</li><li>2010-04-03T19:00:00Z : Found it by lenik1 <br />A lovely day for a walk today [:)] Answers were sent. We really enjoyed that cache as i was on this beach just once before. TFTC</li></ul></logs>
  <original-xml>  <wpt  lat="53.266" lon="-6.106667">
    <time>2010-02-02T08:00:00Z</time>
    <name>GC23ETC</name>
    <desc>White Rock, Killiney Bay by AbbeyAckbar, Earthcache (2/2.5)</desc>
    <url>http://www.geocaching.com/seek/cache_details.aspx?guid=97c948f7-0503-4b91-a75c-b530de801951</url>
    <urlname>White Rock, Killiney Bay</urlname>
    <sym>Geocache</sym>
    <type>Geocache|Earthcache</type>
    <groundspeak:cache id="1539536" available="True" archived="False" xmlns:groundspeak="http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0">
      <groundspeak:name>White Rock, Killiney Bay</groundspeak:name>
      <groundspeak:placed_by>AbbeyAckbar</groundspeak:placed_by>
      <groundspeak:owner id="1265839">AbbeyAckbar</groundspeak:owner>
      <groundspeak:type>Earthcache</groundspeak:type>
      <groundspeak:container>Not chosen</groundspeak:container>
      <groundspeak:difficulty>2</groundspeak:difficulty>
      <groundspeak:terrain>2.5</groundspeak:terrain>
      <groundspeak:country>Ireland</groundspeak:country>
      <groundspeak:state>Leinster</groundspeak:state>
      <groundspeak:short_description html="True">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Killiney&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coastal areas of Killiney are often compared to the Bay of
Naples in Italy. This comparison is reflected in the names of
surrounding roads, like Vico, Sorrento, Monte Alverno, San Elmo,
and Capri. This EarthCache brings you to Vico Road where there is
magnificent views over Killiney Bay, Bray Head and the Great Sugar
Loaf mountain.&lt;/p&gt;</groundspeak:short_description>
      <groundspeak:long_description html="True">&lt;p&gt;Parking is available halfway along the Vico Road (waypoint
provided). There are several paths from here that all lead down
over the railway line and down the steep steps onto Whiterock
beach. I have provided waypoints for these paths near the parking
area. Here you will see close up, the dramatic contact between two
contrasting rock types at Whiterock, but first, a little
information about rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rocks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific study of rocks is called petrology.&lt;br /&gt;
Rocks are named according to the way in which they were formed.
There are 3 types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;- Igneous&lt;br /&gt;
- Sedimentary&lt;br /&gt;
- Metamorphic&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Igneous&lt;/b&gt; (from the Latin "ignis" - fire)&lt;br /&gt;
Igneous rocks originates from molten matter deep inside the earth.
Hot magma (liquid rock) comes up through cracks in the
earth&amp;rsquo;s surface and fills other cracks or forms a layer on
the surface. It then cools forming a very hard igneous rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sedimentary&lt;/b&gt; (from the latin word meaning to settle)&lt;br /&gt;
Sedimentary rock is formed from broken bits and pieces of different
rocks. The three most common forms of sedimentary rock are
limestone, sandstone and shale. Sedimentary rocks are very
important as three quarters of the mass of the continents are
covered with a thin layer of them, and concentrated within them are
important resources such as coal, oil, groundwater and iron
ore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Metamorphic&lt;/b&gt; (from two greek words meaning change and
form)&lt;br /&gt;
Metamorphic rocks formed from igneous or sedimentary rocks that
have been changed into a new rock. They form as a result of high
pressures or temperatures. Sandstone gets changed into quartzite
and limestone gets changed into marble. These new rocks are not as
hard as igneous rock but can be very heavy. Slate, schist, gneiss
and quartzite are other examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three rock types are transformed into one another by
processes of weathering and erosion, melting and exposure to heat
and pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rocks at Whiterock&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Killiney Hill is composed of an igneous rock called granite,
which cooled from a molten magma forced up into the surrounding
shales during the Devonian geological period (around 400 million
years ago). Where the granite heated the adjacent shales, a new
type of (metamorphic) rock called schist was formed. Both granite
and schist have proved quite resistant to erosional forces over
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/643d19cd-f26d-47ec-a9aa-7e00d86b4220.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Whiterock you can see close-up, an outcrop of rocks which
shows the contact between the granite of Killiney Hill &amp;amp; the
adjacent Ordovician mica-schists. The Ordovician period of
geological time is about 475 million years ago. Here you are seeing
the original relationship between the rocks from the time of the
granite intrusion. The rocks against which the granite abuts are
called mica-schists, characterised by thin, parallel bedding planes
along which the rock tends to split. Extreme heat from the granite
intrusion metamorphosed what were originally compacted sandstones
&amp;amp; mudstones from the Iapetus sea floor, into schists. (Iapetus
was a deep ancient ocean of the Ordovician period.) Shiny
plate-like crystals of mica are orientated along the bedding planes
as a result of pressure from the granite. New minerals such as
garnet and andalusite also formed in the zone of metamorphism (the
area where the two rocks contact each other). The andalusite can be
picked out as a dark criss-cross pattern of crystals covering the
bedding planes of the mica-schists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/c83b94f8-e349-4d31-9026-c5212c124a8c.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Andalusite crystals on a mica-schist bedding plane&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When viewed closely, the granite can be seen to be composed of
three main minerals which occur as grains a few millimetres across;
glassy grey quartz, white feldspar and shiny plate-like micas,
which impart the glint to the rock. The granite was worked from a
quarry on the Dalkey side of the hill for the construction of the
Dun Laoghaire harbour piers between 1817 and 1859. Six million
tonnes of granite were transported along a straight narrow-gauge
tramway, the line of which still exists in places as the 'Metals'
pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pebbles on the beach&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the pebbles have come from the glacial cliffs behind
killiney beach, having been plucked as fragments from various rock
formations near and far, and carried by ice age glaciers as they
scoured the landscape. The fragments have been rounded and smoothed
from the wave action of the sea. They represent a stage in the
ongoing tectonic rock cycle of igneous intrusion, mountain
building, erosion, sedimentation of the detritus, compaction,
deformation and metamorphism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/d8a0d675-e51c-48c7-819b-f0927901c75d.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at these pebbles is a good way of seeing a variety of
rocks, minerals and fossils that make up the three rock groups
known as sedimentary, igneous and metamorphic. Take a look for
yourself and see what you can find.There is an abundance of
beautiful coloured pebbles to find on the beach. We took these
photos of the pebbles that we found during one of our trips
there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/b78f034c-252f-4875-a777-9d2816500a8a.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Abandoned Mine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contact between intruded granites and their surrounding
'country' rocks is significant in that this is also the site of
economically important mineralisation. A short distance northwards
from the granite-schist contact, there is an old mine entrance in
the cliff (it is unsafe to enter),that can be seen when the tide is
out, where lead and copper was worked sporadically during the
1750's and 1820's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/4583f0aa-dacf-44ca-a20b-ec49568a7f12.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note :&lt;/b&gt; Close inspection of the rocky part of the beach is
tidal dependent. You can check the tides &lt;a href=
"http://www.irishtimes.com/weather/tides.html"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt; It isn't
necessary to time your visit for the exact time of low tide, just
be aware of when the tide is coming in and going out. Remember
safety first! : )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;To log your visit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;Please email the following to
geocaching@thyme-it.ie :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.&lt;/b&gt;Describe and compare the
colour, texture and appearance between the schists and the
granite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;2.&lt;/b&gt;Look for and measure the
andalusite. Please take a photograph of your find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;b&gt;3.&lt;/b&gt; With your back to the sea, how
many man made stone arches do you see?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;The following is optional and &lt;b&gt;NOT&lt;/b&gt;
a requirement to log your visit - Feel free to upload any photos
you take during your visit to the earthcache site providing they
don't give away the answers to the logging requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p style="color:darkgreen"&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/9ad353ba-760c-4a56-8a5a-9facf75f224b.jpg" /&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;HAPPY
EARTHCACHING!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://img.geocaching.com/cache/9ad353ba-760c-4a56-8a5a-9facf75f224b.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;I am a proud&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.earthcache.org'&gt;&lt;img src=
'http://img.geocaching.com/user/e01b4330-2470-4531-a05d-2662bb4def80.jpg'
border='0' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://s06.flagcounter.com/more/Dv5"&gt;&lt;img src=
"http://s06.flagcounter.com/count/Dv5/bg=CFCFCF/txt=1D6B18/border=1D6B18/columns=6/maxflags=60/viewers=3/labels=0/"
alt="free counters" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional Waypoints&lt;/p&gt;W123ETC - Path to White Rock&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 16.087 W 006° 06.228&lt;br /&gt;Access point to path that leads to White Rock&lt;br /&gt;W223ETC - Path to White Rock&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 16.059 W 006° 06.303&lt;br /&gt;Access point to path that leads to White Rock&lt;br /&gt;W323ETC - Path to White Rock&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 16.034 W 006° 06.384&lt;br /&gt;Access point to path that leads to White Rock&lt;br /&gt;W423ETC - Parking for White Rock&lt;br /&gt;N 53° 16.040 W 006° 06.357&lt;br /&gt;Parking area along Vico Road&lt;br /&gt;</groundspeak:long_description>
      <groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      </groundspeak:encoded_hints>
      <groundspeak:logs>
        <groundspeak:log id="110460454">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-05-28T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="591662">daraconn</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">I think this is my first earth-cache! I ran down all the steps to the beach with the dog. I found it very interesting to see the boundary between the granite and schist, and also the way the schist layers (originally laid down as horizontal layers on the sea floor) had been folded into a vertical orientation.

My father was a geography teacher before he retired, and when I was a boy he would always point out these features, and explain the different kinds of rock. But I had never before heard of andalusite, and it was fun to look closer and discover it. It was also interesting to see the veins of quartz.

Thanks for a very interesting and educational cache!</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="103289682">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-09T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2623045">didi2206</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">Me and the dogs took advantage of low tide at a nice time of day for walking the beach... not sure if i saw the actual rocks required but did my best. had to wait a bit for some of the swimmers to get dressed- they seem to like to " air dry" in the very alcoves where the rocks we need are located!! </groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="103266720">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-04T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="133281">Balla &amp; Silly</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">After we knew when the tide would be low we visited this nice Earthcache in the late morning, arriving from Dublin with the DART. It was a nice ride with the train along the coast and the walk to the White Rock was also very enjoyable. When we got off the train and down to the beach we started walking and weren't sure if we could go all the way along the beach or if some cliffs would stop us before reaching the final destination. So we decided to go upstairs again and followed the road until waypoint 3 where we went down to the beach again. There we saw that this extra way wasn't necessary but we didn't regret it. We had some nice views on our way and later we went back to the DART station along the beach. 
At the White Rock we had a long and good look around, only disturbed by...well, the owners know. [:I]
Great to see all these different kind of rocks and stones, we could have spent much more time there! It must be packed in summer but that day there were only a few more visitors there and we loved to stroll around in bright sunshine.
Thanks a real lot for another great Earthcache and the log permission,
many regards,
Balla &amp; Silly</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="104512767">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-03T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="2734402">Hellynka</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">I found it with Lenik1 who send all required answers and photo. TFTC:)</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
        <groundspeak:log id="102287470">
          <groundspeak:date>2010-04-03T19:00:00Z</groundspeak:date>
          <groundspeak:type>Found it</groundspeak:type>
          <groundspeak:finder id="1925842">lenik1</groundspeak:finder>
          <groundspeak:text encoded="False">A lovely day for a walk today [:)] Answers were sent. We really enjoyed that cache as i was on this beach just once before. TFTC</groundspeak:text>
        </groundspeak:log>
      </groundspeak:logs>
      <groundspeak:travelbugs />
    </groundspeak:cache>
  </wpt>
  </original-xml>
</element>
</celsiusv2.1.addinfofile>
